Chapter 31: Harry and the Centaurs Argue Philosophy

Salor Sprig, The Forbidden Forest, Scotland

September 10th, 1995

Four years before the present

When a centaur is young, he immerses himself in knowledge and study. The centaurs have an ancient culture, unified between the world's seven great herds and stretching back in an unbroken chain into the distant past. It has survived to this day only because it is a combination of one rigid precept and a yielding openness to new ideas. There is no debate over the Unforked Path - but that is the only thing not open to discussion. Everything else - life and death and everything in between - is open to dispute and change.

The Unforked Path includes a strong education in all the gathered wisdom of centaurs from the ages, gleaned from the stars and the wizards and the Muggles, but each centaur eventually tends to find a framework that suits them best. For practical purposes, in fact, each herd is often said to be divided into different naʼniłkaadí. This Muggle word, which has been appropriated and exported to centaurs all over the world, actually means "herd" as well, confusingly enough. The centaurs use it to describe particular schools of thought.

The Kachina herd, now gone, popularized the term when they first struggled to articulate what they considered wholesale errors in the fundamental worldview of their Muggle enemies, the Navajo. But that is a sad tale for another time.

The young Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, only a few years into his power and stinging from the fresh defeat of the International Statute for Health and Life on the floor of the Confederation, has come to visit the Salor Sprig in the Forbidden Forest. He has an important request.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

"I need help," said Harry. The teenager had shaggy hair that he kept pushed to the side, and green eyes that were attentive and thoughtful, lingering on details. Their contemplative care reflected the rapid workings of the mind behind them.

"You are unfair," said Roonwit. "You speak within a context which is extremely vast, old, firmly established, rooted in a network of conventions - a clear statement that places demands on us by virtue of that context. To speak of 'need' and 'help' - we cannot separate such things from their primal origin, and it is unfair to rely on that privileging - on that binary. It makes demands on us separate from the merits of your arguments, by using language with deep implications from the usual context for those spoken words."

Roonwit was a young centaur, and accounted small among his kind, yet he towered over Harry and every emphatic thump of his hoof reminded the wizard of the pure physical power of the creature. It was an uncomfortable reminder of a past tragedy - a tragedy he'd remedied, to be sure, but one with a lingering sting.

"Language has context like everything has context," Harry replied, after taking a moment to parse the complicated accusation. "I think trying to avoid a direct request would be a mistake, and only further rely on that unavoidable 'primal' context." He thought for a moment longer. "It's an appropriate context, anyway - we are talking about life and death."

I recognize some of this language… this is Muggle philosophy. Harry glanced at the bark shacks that were set up in the clearing - the only things here, in fact, beyond the sacred sapling in the center. Where do they get Muggle books? Do they have some sort of magic or artifacts that enable them to disguise themselves, or do they have intermediaries? This must be known to someone in Magical Creatures, but Harry hadn't known to ask. He'd have to find out. He wished he could spend the time to learn those things for himself, but just this single meeting had been difficult. To make it happen, he'd needed to rely on some of the contacts Dumbledore had left him, as well as an outstanding blood debt. He was fascinated: they seemed like an entire civilization of philosophers. On the other hand, this conversation was proving that some strands of thought were a trifle too dense for pleasurable discourse.

"Roonwit holds you to an account that is perhaps overstated in terms of intention, but your intentions are irrelevant. State your needs and ply your arguments, and let us make our choices," rumbled Aosta. The dark bay's skin color was almost the same as her coat, which made her unusually unified in a crowd of centaurs (who were usually two-toned). It suited the elder's temperament, which was singularly calm.

Glenstorm, standing next to Aosta, nodded his agreement. He had his worry beads in one hand, and had been idly rubbing them with a broad thumb since the beginning of the conversation.

"My needs…" Harry rubbed his forehead in frustration, then remembered himself. He cleared his throat. "I need your assistance in locating some items of power that are hidden from all scrying or location, but not - I think - from divination and the implications of prophecy. It's the only way to keep the Dark Lord Voldemort imprisoned, and the world safe."

"When something has an origin, its destruction is ordained at that moment, wizardling," said Glenstorm. "Even if the stars did not promise a coming recompense when the debt of creation is fulfilled, this would be true. In the primal chaos, infinite worlds have been created and destroyed. So it will continue to be. But you should know better than to come before us in such a way: you are here only on the sufferance of Firenze and in acknowledgement of his own debt... to you. Otherwise, we could not ignore that you are the one who will bring this about. The stars scream at the future, and no centaur can ignore it." The centaur's voice was mild, but there were brittle depths beneath it.

"Yes," said Roonwit, glancing over at the two elders, and then back at Harry, nodding. "We cannot deny you a hearing, not after learning of that shame or of your own nobility. But destruction is not an exterior force. The ending of a system predicated on inexactness, as with our world where idea and reality are eternally at odds, necessitates that destruction lies in an eccentric center of all things, in a corner whose eccentricity assures the solid concentration of the system, participating in the construction of what it, at the same time, threatens to deconstruct." The centaur's tail flicked back and forth, thoughtfully. He added, almost as an afterthought, "One might then be inclined to reach this conclusion: deconstruction is not an operation that supervenes afterwards, from the outside, one fine day. It is always already at work in a thing."

"Muggles have discovered a similar sort of idea… a rule that nature seems to follow, called the Second Law of Thermodynamics," said Harry. "It states that any closed system tends towards chaos, eventually. But," and here he held up a finger, "outside influence can sustain it. Consider yourselves that outside influence, and sustain the world."

Harry felt a moment's unsettledness for abusing a scientific principle so badly as to twist it into metaphor. It made him feel like he needed a bath. But this isn't real discussion of reality… this is argument by analogy and rhetoric, and we're all secretly agreed on that. Otherwise we'd be discussing facts, not… whatever you'd call this. Framing, I suppose. I think I can engage on these terms. He took a moment to consider if that was a Voldemort thought, but decided it wasn't. They set the terms of debate, after all, so it was no evil to abide by them.

Aosta shook her head. Her hair was in a beautiful, long ponytail tied back with jute twine, strikingly similar (certainly intentionally so?) to her tail. Harry kept his eyes on it and on her face, which was difficult - considering her height and the fact that centaurs go unclothed. "We are not blind to the world, and it is plain enough that there is suffering everywhere. We could not act to bring about that final chaos, especially not if it would yield a void for a time. The lack of pain is preferable."

Utilitarianism, sort of? Some sort of consequentialism, anyway. Harry felt like he had been dropped unprepared into a pit of rabid Philosophy 101 undergrads. Okay, so how do I prove that there is more pleasure than pain in the world, making saving it a net good and ethical imperative? Will they accept statistics?

"It would not even be the worst of fates," agreed Roonwit. "The worst violence occurs when the other," he said, leaning on the word, "to which one is related is completely appropriated to or completely in oneself. It is this complete exclusion that makes this violence the worst violence - there is no limit to it, since it makes reality and idea entirely subsumed in the other in sovereign unity."

"You can't mean that the world would be better destroyed. If you did, and also thought helping me might hurry up that end, well… then you'd be obligated to help me for that reason, instead," Harry said, adapting as best he could to the different strains of argument. No, it was more than that… the outright different strains of language. Different worldviews. They didn't agree with each other on fundamental principles - virtue ethics or consequentialism - so how could he convince them of anything?

"No, I don't mean that," said Roonwit. "To take a direct hand in assisting you… we could not do that. But the shape of civil society, the shape of the law, is always rooted in violence. To help you would be to participate in that violence, or worse, be a motivating force behind it. It is bad enough that we inhabit the decision and its context. Neither do we oppose you, or endorse Firenze's error. We are obligated to assist or oppose you, but it is…"

"Undecidable?" Harry offered, hoping he was guessing wrong.

"Yes," said Roonwit, smiling. He clopped a hoof down, nodding.

Okay, time to try the other two. It's really more like trying to guess a code than making an argument.

Really, this was a good reminder of why policy debates in Parliament tended towards appeals to emotion, attacks on the messenger, and other fallacies.

"Would you agree, then," he said to Glenstorm, "that the world is better off destroyed? And that a virtuous being is the sort who would let that happen?"

"There is no real destruction," replied the blue roan. His worry beads clicked in one hand as he lowered them to his side. "There are undoubtedly an infinite number of worlds, and we have a union with all of them. But I will not hide in the Athenian solution. No, it would not be a good thing, and the virtuous would oppose it. But we return to the same issue, of which you have argued both sides like a confused coiner: assisting you would hasten stardeath and world-end, not prevent it. Your kind has access to visions of the future, in your crude way - do not your own people tell you this?"

No prophecies, not anymore. Harry had entered the Hall of Prophecy, three years ago, only to find it ruined - a chaos of shattered crystal, splintered shelves, and a thick haze of magically-suspended dust. Dumbledore had been true to his word, and at some unknown point he had eradicated the facility... and had worked to hide that fact, ever since. One of the greatest works of magic in the world had been undone, and the prophecies of Britain could no longer be hoarded and studied. It had been one of the powers that made Britain dominant in the magical world for centuries, for no other nation had its like. Its loss was a national tragedy. Only the old works survived, locked in their special vault of obdurate slade from the Urist Quarry in Hungary: the hundred-odd prophecies that had been individually preserved by independent means. Most of them were shockingly ancient, said to date back before Merlin's era, but there were also some dozens of more modern imported prophecies, and a few British ones that had been doubly preserved, for whatever reason. Scorpion and archer, locked beyond return...

"In a way. But that makes it all the more important that the magical items I need be found, so that the 'world-end' can be of a qualitatively different sort," said Harry. "The world might end in many ways… one of them is by growing into something bigger and better."

"There is something of everything in everything else, and so there is never any motion, and never any change," said Glenstorm, shaking his head. "Withall, a good creature must prevent suffering… but it is wisdom to remember that failure is no one's fault. Indeed, in the event that failure is certain - and the stars speak only of what will happen, and give no conditions - a good creature must vouchsafe his own virtue. Firenze has rightly said that we cannot interfere with the philosopher-kings of wizardkind or else it will sully our own hooves." The centaur paused, shaking his head, and added, "Although he is late-come to this advice, as you know."

I don't even know whether or not that's ingratitude. "He's a Platonic-style dictator I failed to murder and who brought me back to life with a fantastic cover story and who plans to defeat war, pain, and death, so maybe let's not get in his way… but definitely don't help him or anything."

Harry glanced at Aosta and Roonwit, to see if they agreed. If they had a common position in this outcome of their independent strains of reasoning - that non-interference was ethically necessary to keep their hands clean from an inevitable evil - then he could stop talking in circles and tackle that single idea.

"I agree with Elder Glenstorm," said Roonwit. "But I think that we should not fool ourselves, Elder, into thinking that the decision not to interfere is not itself a form of interference. It will send signals, and it will cause consequences. We make the decision within the structures of society - world society, not wizarding - that we are forced to inhabit. We must do so, or else any decision is not possible or effective, nor can they take accurate aim, except by inhabiting those structures. Inhabiting them in a certain way, an aware way. We strive for goodness by stepping back, but the very act of deciding makes us involved… there is an eternal gap that follows us. The important thing is to know. One always inhabits, and all the more when one does not suspect it."

Aosta began to look mildly impatient by the end of this diatribe, but she was certainly used to it, and neither elder centaur looked inclined to interrupt their younger kinsman. Debate is sacred. Once he finished, though, she gave her own perspective with more practiced concision, restraining her kind's natural garrulousness.

"The end of this world is certain, as Glenstorm says," she said. "We have good evidence for this. I am unconvinced whether or not this is a good thing, or whether there can be a qualitative difference in that end, as you say, wizardling. I do not know about 'undecidable,' but I know that there is no compelling reason to dedicate effort to the cause if it would reduce our appreciation of the time we have left."

Harry felt like his brain was growing physically warm with exertion as he tried to track three independently-derived philosophical traditions and answer all of their objections simultaneously. If he had still been articulating interior voices, this would be the moment when he promised his brain a cookie.

"So, if I understand correctly, then," he finally said, rubbing his forehead again. "You, sir," he indicated Glenstorm with a gesture, "think that assisting me is wrong because the action wouldn't be the sort of thing a good person does. But may I suggest that this is simply displacing the real moment of assessment - restating it? The virtuous person is someone who does virtuous things. Choosing not to do something that will improve the world - make people happier, healthier, wealthier - is not the act of a virtuous person."

Glenstorm shook his head. "Except to the extent that the stars speak, we can't know the future. That means that virtue must come from within, not from what occurs. If I were to rescue a child from the tar, and then that child went on to commit murder later that day, I have still found virtue."

"So then the pivotal question is whether or not your own knowledge would lead you to believe that it is a virtuous action?" The centaur nodded, looking amused.

"Hold that thought," said Harry. He turned to Roonwit. "And you, sir. You believe that we can evaluate the world and decide on the ethical course of action, but that every action incorporates and stains us with the guilt of participating in systemic injustice. You think it's undecidable - but you do make ethical decisions on some things, and the way you do that is by determining the most ethical course, yes? If you agree that we're always inhabiting the inherent injustice of the world, even if we do nothing, then you want to either help or not, depending on whether it's the course that will improve the world? Do you agree?"

Roonwit said, "Yes, that is so, although I would challenge your use of this broad binary of 'agree.' It's a corruption of thought by language, since it commits one to the entire endorsement of an idea and eliminates all shade of question or doubt or uncertainty."

"But there's no way around the inherent injustice of language, including its privileged binaries, so at least we're aware of it," said Harry, hurriedly. "Okay, so in both cases we're at the question of fact."

He turned to Aosta. "You, madame. You-"

"The question of fact is the important thing," she said, interrupting him with a smile. "Does the action improve the world... that is the question."

May you live to be queen and rule them all, Harry thought, gratefully. He smiled back at her. Well, not queen… whatever the equivalent would be. As he recalled, they'd adopted the Russian model of regional representatives with a figurehead military leader. Hopefully Aosta's

naʼniłkaadí would gain disproportionate influence... that would be for the best. He wondered if there was any way he could help that happen. He made a mental note for later.

"Then we all agree," Harry said, stepping back a pace so that he didn't have to crane his neck so far, "that we're at the question of whether or not helping me locate these items of power is the most important thing. If it will improve the world, then you and yours should do it. Otherwise, you should not." He had to resist the urge to be rigorous and suggest they define "improve" and "important" and the other vague words they were using. That couldn't conceivably help him make his case.

The three centaurs glanced at each other, and then all three nodded in agreement.

"Okay," said Harry. He smiled. "Then I will explain. There are three things I need to locate. The Cup of Midnight, which can bind anyone who does not give the Cup their name, and which according to legend may actually already be broken. I need to confirm that or not. And the Cup of Dawn, also known as the Goblet of Fire, which can bind anyone whose name is cast within it. And the Resurrection Stone, one of the Deathly Hollows of the three Peverell brothers, which can transcend any barrier. The Goblet and the Stone were both in the possession of Lord Voldemort, and we haven't been able to locate them. They are very powerful, and too important to be left to chance."

"We know of all three devices," said Aosta. She glanced at Roonwit for confirmation, and the centaur nodded.

"I will tell you my intentions, and we will settle the question of fact, if you are willing?" Harry said. He marshalled his knowledge and his arguments and his wits. A lot is riding on this. If I fail, I'll have to approach someone like Aosta more privately. And if that fails… well, I'll just have to try something else. The thought of compulsion occurred to him, but he quashed it. That was a dark road to go down, and he wouldn't begin planning last resorts until he'd run out of every other idea.

Glenstorm's worry beads clicked. Aosta folded her arms in front of her chest, stern but receptive. And Roonwit listened eagerly.

"Well, then," Harry said. He cleared his throat, and checked the abacus in his pocket. Seventeen of the beads had moved, one per minute of this conversation. The hidden aurors ensuring the secrecy and privacy of this conversation were still on task and unmolested. "Here is my plan - or as much as I can tell you about it, anyway."

Chapter 37: Levels

At some point in the past few minutes, all of Hermione's confusion and anxiety and sadness had been swept away, leaving only the cold and clear consideration of tactics.

I need to stop Bellatrix, protect Harry and Draco and a roomful of dignitaries to preserve this new peace, and get the Resurrection Stone. And to save any aurors that I can still rescue.

I can directly command the aurors and my Returned, and probably also get the Boston Brahmins and the Siberian Rakshasa, if necessary.

Bellatrix is, without question, here for Voldemort. Harry said that she didn't seem capable of caring about anything else - she might have plans and secondary goals on his behalf, but her purpose is clear. She'll want Harry, since she'll rightly assume he knows where Voldemort is kept. She is one of the most fearsome witches of her generation and has access to spells and power we don't have, but she also spent years in Azkaban and has been forced to resort to a single desperate attack with a massed army of psychotic, enslaved werewolves.

No, that doesn't make any sense. She wouldn't risk herself in an attack like this without some sort of trump card - some way to defeat all the massed forces she knows are present here. Some way to defeat me. That would mean risking Voldemort's last chance at freedom, and if she were unhinged enough to do that, then she wouldn't have waited this long and prepared this much. She has some additional force or power at her command… even beyond Fiendfyre.

Plans danced in her mind, considered in their permutations and in their costs. No time for optimal planning or more than one level of preparation - they needed direct response, and they needed it before Bellatrix managed to pass through the trapped south corridor.

Massed attack with Returned… no, narrow constraints make us all vulnerable to any unknown threat or renewed werewolf attack. Lure into open room and trap… no, would sacrifice too much ground and put her too close to assets.

Direct attack, flank her and cut off any reinforcements, set up a second layer of defense and trust to Harry for a third layer. She'll go for him - assume he knows where Voldemort is kept.

There, yes, that was it. No time to second-guess. She committed.

"Here's the plan," said Hermione, throwing the Cloak of Invisibility to Hyori. "Take this and go around the back, to the rear of the clinic. Have them let you through - you know the sequences? - so you can flank Bellatrix. Stop at the Establishment on the way and tell Simon and Esther to come here to guard 'Harry.' The Americans and Siberians should stay with the real Harry and prepare to swarm Bellatrix if she makes it that far… he should make a false Voldemort, just in case." Her last words were as much for the benefit of Harry's bubbler in the corner as Hyori.

Hyori caught the Cloak and sprinted from the room without another word, her lips pursed.

Tonks, who was lifting the meeting room table onto its side for a barricade, glanced over at Hermione. He had already fashioned himself into a perfect simulacrum of Harry, and had torn the collar of his robes to make them look more masculine. "And you're going to go try to duel my dear Auntie Black, are you?"

"Yes, in order to protect your dear cousin Draco and everyone else," said Hermione, working her fingers in her gauntlet and heading to the other door.

"I'm Harry's distant cousin, too, actually, along with half that room of muckity-mucks," said Tonks, cheerily. "All our families have been snogging each other for a thousand years."

"A proud legacy," said Hermione, smiling. She drew her wand.

"Don't die, mudblood!" called Tonks, after her.

"You either, blood traitor," replied Hermione, and then she was through the door and heading to the south corridor, breaking into a run.

She could already see the auror as she rounded into the corridor. He was standing at the corner with the south corridor, putting up runes. Probably runes of balance, out of the hopes that it would damage Bellatrix's Fiendfyre chimera. He didn't run.

A brave man, she thought, and pushed into a flat-out run, arms pumping. Balance probably won't be enough to save his own life, but it's most likely to slow her down. He's willing to die to buy us a few more minutes.

She raised her wand, holding it level as she ran, and then flicked it twice to the left - "Lagann!" - and then with a sharp rising jerk towards herself - "Impedimenta!" The auror's location wards broke under her first spell, and he was jerked off his feet with the second, sliding towards her, legs flailing. She leapt as she reached him, one powerful stride carrying her ten meters forward and over him. Hermione had the briefest of glimpses of a look of absolute awe on the man's face - Auror Salamander, she recognized him - and then he was past her. She lowered her body into a lunge and turned herself, and her feet skidded over the stone. She came to a neat stop at the corner at the end of the south corridor, over the body of the fallen auror. Everything was red and scarlet. There was Fiendfyre.

And there was Bellatrix Black.

It was hard to see her past the chimera, which was lazily pushing at the stone of the floor, kneading it with lion's paws as it vitrified and bubbled. But she was there. A tall woman with a strong jawline, she was dressed in black leather leggings and a ragged gray tunic, belted at the waist. One of her arms was black and misshapen: an enchanted prosthetic. Bellatrix had a wide smile on her face.

"Ten green bottles, standing on the wall," she sang, loudly. Her voice was high-pitched - too young for her age. She tilted her head, and stared at Hermione down the length of the corridor. Dozens of carbon nanotubes blocked her path… but they wouldn't withstand an instant of Fiendfyre.

"Bellatrix Black!" shouted Hermione. "My name is Hermione Granger! I know you're here for your Dark Lord… let us give you what you want!" She glanced down at the body of the auror, and leaned over to grasp it with one hand and give it a powerful shove away from her. The fallen auror tumbled end-over-end towards the meeting room.

"Ten green bottles, standing on the wall," repeated the other witch, and bubbled with a moment of insane laughter.

"Can you hear me? Can you understand me?" shouted Hermione. She tensed her fingers on her wand, and flexed her other hand within her gauntlet.

"And if one green bottle should happen to fall..." said Bellatrix, and raised her free hand. She gestured, and her Fiendfyre chimera jerked upright and lurched forward. The scabrous black lines channeling through the thick flames pulsed, and the broken-necked goat's head riding atop the nightmare's back lolled to one side.

"Bellatrix!"

"There'll be nine green bottles, standing on the wall!" shrieked Bellatrix and waved her hand again. The chimera leapt into the air and blazed forward, flaring bright with hellish flame. It surged towards Hermione, and it was so hot that it was destroying the nanotubes before it even touched them - she could hear the rapid staccato clicks as they broke. The chimera flared and crackled and melted the surface of the corridor into glass as it surged towards Hermione, and nothing stood in its way.

And she had a moment, then, to remember.

Pain. Heat. A sweet stink in her nostrils. Her hair crackling as it burned. No knowledge of her body, which had gone far away - only pain and panic. Somehow she'd lost track of herself, even though she knew on some level that she was thrashing and screaming and there was no Granville oh god Granville was gone. But no, that level of knowledge was going away. The world was going away. She was fading burning dying. There was one level, and it was blackness.

Hermione remembered, and as time separated into a series of instants, she felt her stomach clench with fear. She felt herself ready to scream. She felt the blackness, waiting.

But in the next instant all of that was gone, and she was brandishing her wand and shouting her defiance, stamping her heels into the stone beneath her until it cracked.

And in the next instant Hermione could feel the smile on her face as the chimera flared even brighter - red and crimson, everything was dyed red and crimson - and she heard the loud crack of seals coming loose.

Then the chimera was jerked violently to the right and down, spinning helplessly. Thousands of pounds of air pulled it along, sucking with hurricane force at its fire-formed body. Its snake-tail whipped around and hissed angrily, only to be caught up by a different force and wrenched in another direction. Hermione's shout was lost in the roar of wind, and she felt herself lifting off of her feet. She buried her gauntlet into the wall with an extravagant punch, pushed down on her embedded heels, and held her ground.

Buried in the walls were forty extended spaces, linked into a system. They were as large as possible, and they were filled with nothing… not even air.

The chimera had time enough to buck twice in the air, its lion's body flexing, and then it splashed into the wall of the corridor with a wash of mad-red flame. Three of the vacuum chambers, exposed by the Fiendfyre flames that had melted into the walls, sucked air by the gallons. They exerted over a ton of force on the corridor, expressed in a hurricane of sucking wind. The chimera shockingly managed to hold itself away from them for a moment, straining to pull away with whatever magical force that gave it motion. Hermione could see the lion of black and red flame roar without sound... and then the chimera was torn apart, rent into scraps of scarlet and ribbons of red, spread out and scattered and dissipated.

According to legend, Fiendfyre could not be stopped or killed or contained. The ritual was the incarnation of a creature of flame and hatred, and nothing could stem its destruction.

That hypothesis, however, hadn't held up under testing.

The wind died in a few moments, as ball valves were sucked into place. Hermione pulled her gauntlet free from the wall with a rattle of stones, and glanced to her right. Auror Salamander had been pulled back towards her, but was already back on his feet, running towards the meeting room.

Bellatrix was also standing up. Behind her, four long gouges in the stone showed where she'd held on - she must have dug her own new hand into the wall. Something of which to take note: that device probably had other powers, as well, if she'd gotten it from some hidden hoard.

"Stupefy," cast Hermione, and threw herself low and to the side. Bellatrix's own silent curse came in reply a moment later, a rippling wave of purple crystal that swept over Hermione's head. Hermione kicked herself back to her feet with a nimble motion, whipping her wand around and raising a rapid and disposable Roger's Shield. The multicoloured disc of light unfolded from a single bright line just in time to intercept a second wave of crystal shards. Translucent pieces of the shattered projectiles scattered everywhere, and Hermione could feel them patter into her hair.

Classically trained duelist, but acts without the rhythm of convention. Voldemort's work. She'll have something up her sleeve that I can't counter - some wardbreaker or elemental conjuration. And even beyond that… she's just better than me. I need to get in close and press my own advantages.

A thick wash of fog rolled forward from Bellatrix, but Hermione interrupted with a rapid-fire burst of minor hexes, fired from around the edge of her shield. That fog's slow and flashy, that's a trap. Without time for another thought, Hermione cooled her mind into a receptive calm and extended her will, thrusting forth the thought of blue November and the smell of burning leaves. A ward of prisms burst into existence, blocking the corridor from top to bottom, and Bellatrix's hidden curse, the Slow Blade of Unusually Specific Destruction, which had been cruising sedately but invisibly forward, burst like a soap bubble.

I need to-

But the thought was interrupted as both the prisms and Roger's Shield exploded towards her, shattered by a blazing beam of white-hot light. Hermione felt a hot wave of pain as the energy clipped her right shoulder, and then she was tumbling backwards from the impact. So fast, she thought, but there was no time and she rolled to one side and thrust out her hand, pushing herself upright with a powerful motion just in time to avoid a sticky gobbet of grey liquid, which landed in a pulsing sphere on the stone and exploded into a fine mist.

Hermione recognized the spell and held her breath, but there was just no time to prepare a counter-attack. She could already see a white glow building in intensity at the other end of the corridor, and could only swirl her wand and raise it to Vom Tag, pulling an eruption of grey stone up from the floor. The beam of light broke against the stone with a sound like shattering glass - the pattern, I see it - and Hermione threw herself to the side again, smashing into the side of the corridor, as a Killing Curse passed through the space in which she'd just been standing.

Then Hermione seized her advantage while she could. She smashed her clenched and gauntleted hand into her shield of stone, bursting through it with a golden blow, and barked, "AquaCem!"

Sticky foam rushed out of the gauntlet, seething and swelling as it flooded down the hallway towards Bellatrix. Hermione couldn't see it, thanks to the stone that protected her from any backflow, but she could hear the sizzle of spells, muffled by a corridor crammed with foam.

She had a moment. Bellatrix would be delayed for at least a short time. Time enough for Hermione to prepare, and time enough for Hyori to get in position. She didn't dare hope that she'd just ended the fight; even if she'd managed to surprise the other witch and actually catch her in the foam, there were any number of ways Bellatrix could escape.

"Ventus," she cast, clearing away the mist. She took a deep breath, and considered her options.

I should have kept the Cloak, and had Hyori take Simon and Esther with her, she thought. She'd been wary of sending anyone without perfect concealment around to the north corridor, since more werewolves might have been on the way. But I made my decision, and it's done. Hindsight bias be damned.

So how do I get in close? She took a quick inventory, trying to think of some way to get to the end of the corridor before Bellatrix could react. Her broom was too slow and vulnerable. Explosives? No, that was silly and impractical, even if it was theoretically possible. She couldn't bubble and have the Anti-Disapparation wards taken down (even if that was something they could easily so), for obvious reasons.

The foam hissed, and some of its stiff grey bubbles poured through the hole she'd left in the stone shield in front of her. Hermione could hear a crackling sound, growing louder by the second. She had another foam charger, should she…

Oh. Wait, no, that's crazy.

But she couldn't think of why it wouldn't work, and she didn't have anything better, and this needed to end before more people got hurt. So there it was.

Hermione turned and smashed her gauntleted fist into the stone behind her. She twisted her hand violently, and a small shower of broken rock came loose. Pulling the gauntlet free from her hand, she pushed hard on the underside of one knuckle. The spent foam charger came loose, and she pocketed it. She replaced it with a spare wind charger from her pouch, locking it into place next to an identical one. Then she shoved the gauntlet into the hole she'd made, backwards. It faced the opposite end of the south corridor, where Bellatrix was still dealing with the foam.

The sound of crackling had very nearly reached Hermione, and the air was almost unbreathable with an acrid smell. There was some sort of chemical reaction - had Bellatrix set the foam on fire, somehow?

The answer came in seconds, as Hermione's shield of stone began to sizzle. The top melted at the same time that holes appeared along the surface, and Hermione could see the thick yellow mist that was eating away at the rock. She'd changed the foam into some sort of airborne acid.

How oddly helpful.

"Bullesco," cast Hermione, and the Bubblehead Charm swelled up and around her head. Here goes… well, something. She put her back to the gauntlet, facing the end of the corridor and Bellatrix squarely. Then she raised her wand."Ventus! Ventus! Kavo!"

Two gusts of wind swept the airborne acid back at Bellatrix. It was the obvious counter-attack, meaning it was an obvious trap - the dull yellow glow of two Bertram Bolts whipped from out of the swirling acid, which had obscured their passage.

But Hermione had also triggered the two wind chargers in her gauntlet. Twin gales of compressed air, released in a moment from their extended space, swept her up and down the corridor, over the curses, bouncing painfully against the ceiling and turning in an awkward tumble. She lost sight of Bellatrix as she spun, but saw the yellow fog of acid vanish in a glimmer of light - the Obliteration Charm.

Hermione hit Bellatrix's shields with one tense leg. Her ankle twisted to the side violently with the impact and she crashed to the ground, arms akimbo and head cracking into the stone sharply. Bellatrix's eyes were wide with shock and anger and crazed delight. Her false arm held her wand delicately between three fingers, still pointed forward. She brought it down to point at Hermione. "Avada-"

Hermione lashed out with her uninjured foot, sharply striking Bellatrix's wooden arm. The blow would have broken any human arm, but the smooth-grained wooden arm - oddly delicate in appearance, all shifting layers, an intricate mesh of components - was only knocked away.

"Silly stupid scum," hissed Bellatrix, hopping backwards and out of reach.

Hermione could see the other witch's eyes clearly, in this instant as she scrambled to her feet. They had a burning intensity to them: the fever brightness of madness. But she saw more than that, and her heart ached as she recognized that there was a hollowness behind her gaze. A hungry distance that lay somewhere in those crazed dark eyes.

You never Returned, even when you left Azkaban. You carry your Azkaban with you.

It was a moment of recognition. A moment of hesitation.

Bellatrix's wand danced in a complicated swivel and bob, and she tapped it on her chest. "Amandher Penkue!"

The air shuddered with a pulse of magical power. Hermione felt it in her bones. One of Bellatrix's eyes popped wetly, exploding from the socket into a small burst of black dust.

A sacrifice. An old spell.

"Here I am," said Bellatrix Black.

"Here I am here I am," said a second Bellatrix Black.

"Here I am here I am here I am," said a third Bellatrix Black.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Pip could barely stand. He was very near toverislot, and he could feel his will ache with overexertion. He would pass out soon - should have passed out a while ago, actually.

Despite knowing this, somewhere in the back of his mind, he didn't stop. He couldn't stop. Pip crushed the crowded hall with attack after attack. His back against the clinic door, he fought screaming madmen. He broke their bodies and rent their flesh, casting spell after spell, chaining together one effect after another. He fought without stopping, without resting, without thinking.

Pip fought until there was no one left to fight.

The hallway was a ruin of gore and wrecked humanity. Broken or abandoned wands were strewn in and around the smoking remains of their owners. Someone was wetly wheezing, trying to curse or scream even as they drowned in their own blood. Pip leaned on the wall, his vision swimming - but wand at the ready.

The door to the clinic clanked loudly, and swung open behind him. Pip turned, wearily, to see that witch from the Returned - the angry-looking Korean one. Her wand was out, but she appeared to be missing her other arm. No, an invisibility cloak. Bugger, I am tired. She stared at him for a moment, narrowing her eyes with scrutiny.

"Hullo," he said.

"Come," she replied, handing him a phial. The label read, "PEPPER-UP POTION." Then she pushed past him, breaking into a run, throwing the cloak over her shoulders.

I shouldn't drink this, Pip thought, as he swallowed the potion. He felt it burn down into his stomach, boiling in his guts. Thick heat spread throughout his limbs, and his ears burned.

I'm too tired… I'll just sit down here and take a rest. Forget the lockdown protocol, let the clinic aurors go fight, Pip thought, as he raced down the corridor after the vanishing Returned, slipping on blood.

Mum would want me to let someone else take their turn… bollocks to this, I'm going to go have a nap, Pip thought, as he began to raise his wards for what felt like the thousandth time. New strength was rising in him, but it felt artificial and thin - the false energy of a strong cup of tea in the wee hours of a long watch.

He could hear Bellatrix's voice as they neared the junction of the north and south corridors. She was chanting something, but there was some strange effect - it sounded like a chorus. Like there were-

Three of the bloody crazy bints. All fighting Hermione Granger.

It was impossible. Everything about it was impossible. It was impossible that Bellatrix had duplicated herself somehow - it wasn't even an illusion, they were all doing different things! - since there had never been any magic like that, not that he'd ever heard. It was impossible that anyone could cast so many curses - so many Killing Curses! - with such speed and viciousness. He'd heard stories, but to see it…

And it was impossible that the Goddess was still alive.

But she was. She ducked and threw up shields and cast curses and lashed out with her fists and feet. Killing Curses streamed past her, but she slipped gracefully among them, pausing only to rip away wards from her foes or attack them. She moved faster than anyone could move. She was dancing between the raindrops.

"Lagann! Stupefy!" Pip shouted, and immediately wished he'd kept quiet. His spell smashed through the shields of one of the Bellatrixen, but his stunner hit her wooden right arm and had no effect.

"Oh hell," Pip said, as that Bellatrix (Bellatrix #1? Bellatrix A? Bellatrix holyhellrunaway?) rounded on him, leaving her doubles to fight the Goddess. Like the other two, she was missing her right eye. A bloody socket wept crimson down her cheek.

"Silly dolly," hissed Bellatrix A. "It's time to-"

But her words were cut off suddenly, turning into a wet gurgle as a red slash appeared across her throat. Blood began to spurt from the wound, and Bellatrix A staggered backwards into the wall, clutching it with one hand as she tried to clamp her fingers over her throat with the other. Her wand dropped to the floor.

In unison, the two other Bellatrixes whirled. They spoke in one voice.

"Avada Kedavra."

Both curses flashed through the air and vanished into nothingness. There was the sound of someone collapsing to the ground.

"Stupefy!" cast Pip again. The stunner missed, but it did force the two standing Bellatrixen to adapt and raise new shields, distracting them for a further precious instant. It gave the Goddess a moment to snatch a knife from a pouch at her waist. She renewed her attack, casting three Bertram Bolts in as many seconds and lunging at the nearest Bellatrix.

Her target whirled to bring up her artificial arm and wand. The Bellatrix deflected the Bolts with an instantaneous Roger's Shield, and continued the motion to intercept the knife with the enchanted wood of her forearm. It was a marvel of combat.

Something didn't go as the Bellatrix expected, though, since the knife punched right through the prosthetic. It was a small knife, and its silver tip only just breached the other side of the relic-arm, but it was something.

"Lagann! Lagann! Lagann! Reducto! Reducto!" Pip began casting, trying to capitalize on the momentum. He kept his distance and only tried to support the Goddess, because he could feel a vast lethargy welling up from his guts. The potion was wearing off. He didn't give up. He wouldn't give up.

"Thank you for saving the Goddess and the whole Tower," breathed Cedric. He shook Pip's hand, and then held on. He didn't let go as he looked into Pip's eyes. "I… I don't know how to say this, but… I'd noticed you, before. When you were on duty. I noticed you in your auror's robes. Your eyes."

Pip dodged to the side with a desperate effort, contorting his body to avoid three precise blasts of Hippo's Fire. "Lagann!" he cast. "Depulso! Reducto! Glacius!" He was slowing down, dimming, fading. Everything began to get darker, and it felt like he was fighting in knee-deep water. Water that was rapidly rising, and making him sluggish and dull. He pushed himself. He pushed himself beyond where he ever thought he could go.

It felt odd to be sitting at the head table, next to Headmistress McGonagall. But they'd insisted. It was only proper for the new Head of Slytherin to take the place of honour. "I want you to know," said the Headmistress, with a softness in her Scottish voice that he'd never heard, "that Hogwarts owes you a debt it can never repay. The name of Slytherin has new meaning, thanks to you. Let them all be Silver Slytherins in your mold. Let them strive to live up to the name of Pirrip."

Everything was slow. Too slow. A bolt of fire hit Pip in the leg. He felt the pain as though at a great distance. He couldn't bring up any more shields, couldn't manage any difficult curses. He cast stunners and disarms, and even that took so much effort that it felt like his soul was being scraped raw. "Stupefy! Stupefy! Expelliarmus!" Anything to make the Bellatrix react and fight him - to distract her - needed to distract her - needed to save the Goddess…

"I'm so proud of you, Philip. Your dad would be so proud of you."

Then he felt a curse hit him in the stomach. Too slow. Couldn't avoid it. Didn't feel like anything, though. The world tilted and rocked as he fell, crumpling to the ground. Couldn't feel his legs. Couldn't feel bloody anything. Everything sideways. Everything dim.

Pip could see the Bellatrix he'd been fighting turn around. She touched her wand to the one with the slashed throat. After a moment, the hand of the fallen Bellatrix twitched and clenched itself. It scrabbled around, looking for a missing wand.

The Goddess was putting up layered shields, trying to outpace the other Bellatrix, whose prosthetic hand seemed to be moving more slowly. They were getting smaller - the whole fight was getting smaller. Everything was shrinking, as though he were being drawn back into a tunnel. A dark tunnel.

Bellatrixen A and B joined their sister. Dull shapes, moving far away. A thick fog. The Goddess was fighting. But it wasn't… wasn't working… she couldn't…

Dimly, Pip watched as Bellatrix Black and her two duplicates cast the Killing Curse. They cast it in quick succession, and they cast it flawlessly. This time, Hermione Granger was too slow.

One of the Killing Curses hit her. Colors were dim, and Pip's mind was fading, but still he saw the green bolt strike her in the chest.

He saw the Goddess die.

Two of the Bellatrixen sprang forward, down the corridor and out of his sight. Pip watched them go with the distant thought that this was important… that this mattered… but he couldn't quite…

Almost as an afterthought, the last Bellatrix turned to him. He watched, dully. He tried to keep his eyes open. He felt for his wand with numb fingers. He needed… he had to…

"Avada Kedevra."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Harry had done everything he could. He entered the Extension Establishment with his most commanding air and had informed everyone that there had been a security breach. The defence had been easy to organize. Draco was there to publicly and cordially avow that the Honourable and Independents had no hand in the attack, and that the same honour which compelled their defiance of tyranny would compel them to defend innocent lives. Harry suspected that, even if Draco hadn't been there, he would have met little opposition. This was his place of power and his fortress, and those in attendance respected such things.

Politics were still a necessity, though, and having Draco with him helped. The Slytherin was able to make awkward requests with such beautiful elegance that they seemed like compliments. Per Aavik-Söderlundh-Ellingsen and the other incompetents were ushered off to the far corners, where they wouldn't be in the way. The process was considerably eased when Harry sent the Brahmins - a grizzled, enormous pack of battle-hardened witches and wizards - next door, to fetch some of the Mobile Marys and other extended spaces. Fully half of the gathered crowd was dispersed among them. Everyone who would be a liability, or who declined to risk themselves, was put out of the way in that manner, and there was room to maneuver and plan.

But then that was arranged, and he'd worked with Draco and Cedric to deploy the British aurors and the Brahmins and their Siberian counterparts and some of the Returned (Urg, Charlevoix, and Susie) in strategic positions, and everyone was weaving wards and shields that were (frankly) far better left to them. Harry stood where he was politely asked to stand by Buckeye Dave of the Brahmins.

And he had to watch the bubbler and wait.

Tonks-as-Harry made her own preparations with Simon and Esther in the meeting room. They laid magical traps and wards and shields. They made plans. Harry watched and listened to them.

He waited.

Draco stood nearby, talking quietly with his mother (who kept giving Harry hateful glares) and Gregory Goyle. Harry wished they could keep talking, openly, like before - even just about the situation, much less everything else that had happened over these past few years.

Harry thought about everything that could be lost today. He thought about Dumbledore's wise words about war and loss, seven years ago, in a room filled with monuments to the fallen.

"I see that you still do not understand. I think you will not understand until the day that you - oh, Harry. So very long ago, when I was not much older than you are now, I learned the true face of violence, and its cost. To fill the air with deadly curses - for any reason - for any reason, Harry - it is an ill thing, and its nature is corrupted, as terrible as the darkest rituals. Violence, once begun, becomes like a Lethifold that strikes at any life near it. I... would spare you that lesson the way I learned it, Harry."

Would Harry learn that lesson today? Would he learn that there were never enough levels to a plan - never enough layers of deception or preparation that could save everyone?

He'd rejected that principle, then and every other time he thought about it. Dumbledore had shown him the costs of war, and had challenged him: did Harry really think he was smart enough - that anyone could be smart enough or prepared enough or powerful enough - to fight a war without loss?

Dumbledore had tried to point out that violence was often unpredictable, and seldom neat. They spoke of history - Gandhi and Churchill and Grindelwald - and they spoke of slippery slopes. And still, all around them, had been the evidence of loss. Dumbledore had done everything he could to avoid war, and when it came, he had led the forces of goodness. He had been the most powerful wizard known to the world, and he had somehow discovered the Word of the First Enchanter and had listened to every prophecy held in Britain, and still he had suffered grievous losses in the wars against Grindelwald and Dumbledore.

"I do not accept your answer, Headmaster," Harry had said at the time. It had been a childish refusal to engage in an argument on its merits, really. "You are willing to accept balances of power where the bad guys end up winning. I am not," he'd said.

"Refusing to accept something does not change it. I wonder now if you are simply too young to understand this matter, Harry, despite your outward airs; only in children's fantasies can all battles be won, and not a single evil tolerated."

Harry had hated the bullying at Hogwarts. He'd been willing to disrupt the school to stop it. If that had upset Lord Jugson, he'd been willing to arrange for Lord Jugson to be exiled. If that had upset Lord Malfoy and his whole Wizengamot contingent, he'd been willing to break Malfoy and every single one of them - or all of them at once, if need be.

For the sake of ending bullying, Harry had been willing to conquer the world.

Was that right?

Harry drew his wand.

It wasn't the Elder Wand. The Elder Wand was hidden in the Tower, guarded by a thousand traps. It would have been foolish to carry it: Harry was clever and creative, but no duelist. Any unguarded moment and he could be "defeated"... no, better to keep it safe and hidden until he had need of it.

This was Harry's wand. Eleven inches long. Holly. Phoenix core.

What would Fawkes say to him now?

Noise from the bubbler. Harry's attention snapped over to it. Charlevoix, standing to his left, stepped closer to watch.

They could see three versions of Bellatrix Black entering the meeting room. There was fighting - hard to make out from the bubbler's limited vantage point. Esther was casting curses, and so was "Harry." Simon was already down. He was just visible at the bottom of the bubbler's view. He wasn't moving.

Flashes of light. Some sort of trap triggered, and the picture on the bubbler was whited-out. When the view returned, Esther and one of the Bellatrixen were both out of sight. Either they were out of range of the bubbler's vision, or… something else. He could hear a sharp intake of breath from Charlevoix.

But now it was Tonks against two Bellatrix Blacks, and no one could have won that battle. Harry cringed as the two attacking witches disarmed "Harry."

One of the Bellatrixen moved, and her back blocked Harry's view of Tonks. The other one was pulling something from within her belt. They struggled with Tonks, who wouldn't cooperate, finally settling on Incarcerous to bind him. They forced him to open his mouth, poured something in. A potion. Veritaserum. A lot of Veritaserum, more than anyone could ever use on someone they wanted to keep alive and sane. Enough to wrest the truth from Mad-Eye Moody himself.

"I'm Nymphadora Tonks, I'm not Harry Potter! He's oh Merlin no no no he's back through that door, in the Extension Establishment with everyone else no no no Merlin I'm so sorry Harry I'm so sorry Hermi-"

"Avada Kedavra," said one of the two remaining Bellatrix Blacks. Harry closed his eyes, and felt bile rise in his throat.

He'd taunted Dumbledore. Hurt him on purpose. "And that's why I can destroy Dementors and you can't. Because I believe that the darkness can be broken."

The two witches laughed - insane and hideous laughter - and vanished from his view.

Harry heard laboured breathing, and turned to see Charlevoix's shoulders heaving. Her cheeks were wet with tears.

"Fucking bitches," said Susie.

Buckeye Dave gave orders to the Brahmins. Марат gave whispered commands to the Rakshasa. Cedric gave direction to the aurors.

Harry waited.

He remembered what Dumbledore had written to him - the last word in that conversation, delivered after the good man's sacrifice.

There can only be one piece whose value is beyond price.

That piece is not the world, it is the world's peoples, wizard and Muggle alike, goblins and house-elves and all.

Harry lurched into motion. First a step forward, and then another. Then he knew what he was doing and knew it was what Fawkes would tell him to do.

He broke for the door.

Angry and dismayed shouts broke out from those important enough to object, but what could they do? Stun him? Who would dare stun Harry Potter-Evans-Verres and ruin his clever plan? Draco called out something in alarm, but Harry couldn't understand him. Wouldn't understand him.

He was out the door and into the hall.

Bellatrix Black was there. So was a second Bellatrix Black. They stood side-by-side, ten meters away. They stank of death and madness.

Harry skidded to a halt, almost falling forward, awkwardly. He kept his wand at his side, deliberately, but raised his other hand.

He snapped his fingers.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Note: I'm sorry.

The next chapter will be posted in two weeks. It will be titled "Walpurgisnacht."

Chapter 40: Science

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

October 3rd, 1998

"Mr. Abercrombie, Ms. Ryan. How can I help you?" asked the dean, glancing at his wristwatch. "It must be important if you've come to see me during my office hours this week."

Visiting the dean was relatively simple, but annoyingly tedious: you simply pinned a note to the front of your robes about office hours, then snapped a Safety Stick. Few students ever bothered, especially considering how intimidating the former prodigy and current magical titan could be. His inaugural speech to the Science Program students hadn't been especially impressive - a great deal of fuss about a "pale blue dot" - but some of the new students in the Program had felt faint just from being in the Tower and in such proximity to the great man. Craig Abercrombie and Siobhan Ryan thought this visit was necessary, however.

As usual, every team in their year of the Science Program had been given their project on Sunday. In this instance, each trio of students was handed a small brown box containing the broken shards of a vase and a small card of information. Craig, Siobhan, and Perry Paderau got a box full of white-glazed pieces decorated with delicate designs in blue and green. The card had informed them that this was formerly an Art Nouveau vase created by Leon Solon, and told them that they were required to "repair the vase" without magic. You may use magic in any way you please during the process, as long as no spell directly touches or affects the pieces of the vase. Points will be awarded based on the completeness of the restoration, overall aesthetic effect, and creativity.

"Well, sir, it's just got to be Muggle glue, right?" said Craig. "Nothing else you can do. Not much of a challenge. We were wondering if you might talk to Professor Syracuse about it, and get him to change it a bit."

"I suggested this assignment, actually," said Dean of the Science Program Harry Potter-Evans-Verres. He leaned back in his chair behind the huge wooden table, adjusting his glasses, and gestured at a pile of books at one end of the table. Craig recognized some of the textbooks from the science program and several books on pottery styles and history, along with a handful of note-filled parchments.

There was a brief pause as the two students absorbed this information, then Siobhan spoke up. "Sir, I'm not sure it fits with some of the other projects we've done. They all needed… well, you had to think about them. This will just be… tedious. Gluing things together."

"Don't underestimate the value of patience, Ms. Ryan," said the dean. "Having the fortitude to do something annoying and fiddly is a key aspect of good science." He pushed himself back from the big table, and stood up, gesturing vaguely. "A few rooms away is a project I've been working on for years, trying minor variations on the same thing over and over again to try to find the exact shielding that will work for my purposes. And I'll probably keep working at it tomorrow, and next week, and so on. If you've decided on a way to complete your project, don't quit just because it seems tedious. Most worthwhile things are tedious at some point, so you should get used to tedium… as long as it's for a good purpose, and not just busywork."

"This is just different than Professor Syracuse's previous assignments, that's all," said Siobhan.

Craig nodded in agreement, and then his face lit up. "There was something about this sort of thing in one of our books…"

He walked over to the pile of books and notes that the dean had indicated. He leafed through them until he found what he was looking for: a copy of Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman! Craig opened it and began flipping through it, rapidly.

Some of the previous weekly projects from the Professor of Engineering had been:

-Construct a way to view a basilisk with sufficient clarity that it could be effectively fought. Any means allowed, Muggle or magical. Entries included glasses with mirrors built into them, blindfolds enchanted with vitalis revelio, a purchased pair of Muggle night-vision goggles, and a simple piece of parchment inscribed with the words, "Use the Killing Curse and then view it as much as you want."

-Build upon last week's work studying Muggle agriculture, and suggest a new way to improve it in a well-structured essay. No minimum number of inches. Answers were almost universally centered around either the use of magical creatures (interbreeding, pest control, etc.) or the production of fresh water (wide-scale weather management, enchanted salt-water filters, etc.) The most successful team pointed out that simply using Vanishing Rooms would result in the biggest improvement to Muggle agriculture, eliminating all the problems of preservation and transportation.

-Go to the northeast corridor, take the second stairwell, go left down the hall, and enter the eighteenth room on the left. Once the door locks behind you, your team will have one hour to escape. You may not use your wands. You may bring anything else with you that you wish. Students brought lockpicks enchanted with flawless function, battering rams transfigured to a small size, bottles of magical fire or Bundimun acid, and other things. Most plans had needed to be altered somewhat after the door vanished.

-This is a Muggle device known as a "mousetrap," used in place of the Vermexous Charm. It is missing the spring which would normally power it with mechanical energy. Make it work. Points will be awarded based on the effectiveness of the trap on a living mouse and creativity. Most teams succeeded to get the trap to work, replacing the spring with twisted rope or other solutions. The two winning teams, however, found more innovative approaches. One team had put a lump of poisoned bait on the trap and ignored the device's original purpose. The other had tied the broken mousetrap to the back of a hungry kneazle.

-Write an essay in three parts: (1) Where is an example of the Pareto Principle at work within Hogwarts? (2) Where can you find an example of the normal distribution in Hogwarts? (3) Identify a place where you would normally expect to find an example of either concept, even though it is not present. No minimum number of inches.

-Golden Snitches have been immobilized and hidden throughout the fifth floor. Find any Snitch, but remember that most sensory spells will not be effective. Do not go past the mungbeans or you will certainly become lost. Only two teams had won. The first had gone and purchased a new Golden Snitch in Hogsmeade, pointing out that the rules didn't state which Snitch they needed to find. The other had researched the history of Quidditch's most famous cheaters and found a little-known fifteenth-century charm to divine the location of a Snitch. It used a distinctive wand motion. The following month, the Seeker for the Slough Sizzlers was fined a hundred Galleons and barred from competition.

After a moment of searching through the book, Craig had found the part he wanted.

"Sir, remember when Mr. Feynman goes to Brasilia and talks to them about what they do with their science education?" Dean Potter nodded; it was one of the more famous parts of the book. "Well, sir, Mr. Feynman says they have to choose a way because of 'a good reason, a sensible reason; not just because other countries do.' " The student tapped the spot in the book.

"Yes, Mr. Abercrombie. But I assure you, we're not doing this project just because other engineering classes do it this way." The dean smiled indulgently, and the expression paradoxically made him look very young. He was only a few years older than them, after all.

"Yes, sir, but maybe you're assigning this project because you're doing the sort of thing you think that Mr. Feynman would do?" said Craig, questioningly. He closed the book and set it back down with the rest.

Siobhan frowned, shaking her head. "Well, I don't know if that's it, Craig. I just thought..."

"It's a good point," said the dean, looking thoughtful. "When I was younger, I spent quite a bit of time feeling frustrated with my teachers, and wishing I had a truly talented and creative tutor. I wasn't quite prepared when I got my wish." He fell quiet for a moment, and the students waited, a bit impatient despite their awe. The dean was either referring to Albus Dumbledore or David Monroe, and it was a dramatic reminder of how close they were to history… but they still wanted to leave as soon as possible.

"I'll think about it," said the dean. "And before I give any more suggestions to Professor Syracuse, I'll write out some clear lesson objectives. Cleverness isn't a substitute for pedagogy, I suppose."

"Thank you, sir," said Craig and Siobhan, just slightly out of unison. They seemed discomfited by the end of the conversation; Craig was tugging at his robes nervously and Siobhan was visibly sweating. They left without another word.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

The ensuing week was relatively normal - or what passed for normal in Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry's Science Program, which was not known for its normality. The lower-form students (in their first two years of the Program) scurried in small packs from one class to another, learning the rudiments of seven core subjects and one elective. The upper-form students spent their time with fewer professors, studying the rudiments of a few branches of science and doing labs. It was a ruthlessly intense program, and more than half of the students quit during their first year.

Professor Syracuse's afternoon class on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, and Saturdays was a group of fourth-years. They had a swagger about them: they'd survived three years of a course of study that was already legendary for its difficulty, surpassing even the Salem Witches' Institute's "Trial by Fire" graduate school of languages. In another year, they'd be choosing independent courses of study in magical science in the School of Doubt, working with Tower or Unspeakable researchers - or even just beginning careers, if they wanted. They would be the third graduating class of the Science Program, and they were on top of the world.

Truth be told, the swagger in these fourth-years might explain why Professor Santo Syracuse agreed so readily to the vase project when it was suggested by Dean Potter-Evans-Verres. Such an assignment had good prospects for teaching some arrogant teenagers a little humility.

"Sit down, sit down," snapped Professor Syracuse. "Paderau! You heard me! Sit down and be quiet! We have no time for your nonsense - the ladies aren't impressed. If you want to impress them, learn your equations."

The boy in question stood up from where he'd been crouched between two witches and walked around their station back towards his own in the back, wearing an expression of aggrieved innocence. He sat down between Siobhan and Craig, making as much noise as possible as he settled his elbows on the high table and his rear on the stool. His partners exchanged a look of annoyance behind his back.

Professor Syracuse watched him intently for a moment to be sure that the admonishment had been effective, then brightened as he turned to the class as a whole. He was a thin man of average height, and gloriously bald, with a shiny pink scalp and a mouth that twitched from side to side when he was excited. He was often excited.

"Today we'll spend the first hour on project presentation, and then after the break we'll be doing more work on friction," the professor said, rubbing his hands together in anticipation and illustration. "We'll try to hammer at least a few basic principles into you, so that you're only woefully ignorant, and not completely ignorant. It will be a rich, full day." He waggled his eyebrows in anticipation. "Okay! Get out your projects - whatever you have, get it out, even if it's just your notes! You can put your binders away for now. Do not spill your flobberworm mucus or murtlap essence, or you will be cleaning everyone's station at the end of the afternoon."

There was some shuffling and murmuring as people got themselves sorted, taking out whatever their team had managed to complete that week. All six of the teams appeared to have put together something in order to repair the vase, but as everyone looked around, they saw a variety of solutions.

"What did we get done, guys?" Perry Paderau asked the other two, in a hushed voice.

" 'We' didn't get anything done… Craig and I did finish something, though," answered Siobhan, annoyed. She was arranging a closed box in front of herself, carefully.

"Don't be that way, Ryan… it's been crazy this past week," said Perry, frowning. "My dad wants me to come work for him when we get done this year, and so I've been trying to get some extra help from Professor Sprout in the evenings." Perry's father grew Sopophorous beans for export.

"You didn't do anything, you just let Siobhan and I do it, and now you're going to take credit," said Craig, irritably.

Perry turned to him, and spoke in a harsh whisper, "Hey, you're not the one who's expected to spend the rest of his life with baskets of Mooncalf dung and a pair of silver scissors, okay? Do you know how often you need to sharpen silver scissors?" He scowled. "I did all the work to get us out of that room last month, when the door vanished, so have some mercy, will you?"

"This is the only time," said Siobhan.

"Fine!" said Perry, a bit too loudly.

"Quiet over there!" said Professor Syracuse, darting his gaze at their team. He frowned. "Again, Paderau? One point from Ravenclaw!" Perry groaned and slumped forward on the table. "Okay, first team… Jess, Raphael, Sally… what do you have?"

Two boys and a girl rose from their stools and walked awkwardly to the front table. They set a vase down, carefully, as well as two small bowls. The vase was small, brown, and extremely plain.

"Our solution was simple. We had a broken vase, and we needed to make a working vase - to 'repair' it. So it seemed to us like the best thing would be to just make a new vase, rather than trying to remake the old one." She gestured at the table, and one of her teammates dipped his fingers into one of the small bowls, lifting out a palmful of brown powder. "We took the pieces of the original vase and ground them down into dust. Then we took that dust," she gestured again, and another teammate displayed a handful of dark clay, "and we added water, turning it back into clay. We didn't use any magic on the pieces, before or after we ground them down. We didn't even use Aguamenti to create the water - we just used the tap." She sounded very proud.

"Then," she said, gesturing at the brown pot, "we made a pot, and asked a house elf to put it in the kilns for us the next time they fired something. We got it back this morning, and here is the pot: clean and new, and in one piece."

The professor approached the front table, frowning. "Full marks for creativity, and I supposed this is a 'complete restoration.' " He picked up their pot, and examined it. "I am actually surprised that this worked. I wouldn't have thought that you'd be able to grind the it down and then just re-fire it. The glassification… hmm…"

Professor Syracuse drew his wand and tapped the side of the pot twice, saying, "Aparecium." The pot and the bowl of clay changed color - very slightly, tinting itself just a bit pink. The bowl of powder, on the other hand, turned red. The professor turned to regard the trio of students, eyebrow raised. "Oddly, very little of the invisible dye seems to have found its way into your new pot… almost as though you just mixed a little in with new clay, after discovering that your plan wouldn't work."

They muttered some excuses, but the professor was already waving them back to their seats. "If you want to remedy your low score today, then I'd suggest you each write me thirteen inches on why you think your plan didn't work, and what you should have done instead. I'd also suggest availing yourself of the library, this time around. If you'd done even a bit of research - or if you'd been paying attention when we discussed ceramics - you'd have known about why this wouldn't work."

Professor Syracuse turned back to the class. "Next."

The next two teams had simply glued the vase back together. One of the teams had done much better than the other, and had clearly taken the time to choose a specific kind of glue and practice, while the other team's vase had small chips missing and beaded lines of overflow dried along the seams. It even leaned a bit to the side.

Professor Syracuse commented on patience and conscientiousness as each team presented their work. The team that would go last watched in dismay, since it was obvious to everyone in the room that they had done the worst job - their glue didn't even look dry. One of them muttered a charm under their breath, and tried to subtly position their box so that it hid her efforts to use the warming spell on her work.

"Next."

The fourth team had tried hard for the "creative" and "aesthetics" points as a strategy, and had used the pieces of their broken vase as a mosaic on the outside of a different vase, breaking them into even smaller fragments and arranging them in an attractive pattern. They held up drawings they'd copied from a book with a Quarto Quickening Quill from Queevel's, showing different examples of mosaics in art around the world, as well as a large diagram indicating the best way to fit the pieces and stick them in place. They were a very thorough group, and the class was just lucky that they hadn't had time to make a diorama of a Pompeiian antechamber. They looked to be leading the class this week, easily.

"Next," said the professor, gesturing at Craig, Siobhan, and Perry.

The three of them got up. Siobhan carried the box with their project in it. She set it down, stood in front of it, and took out the vase. The white vase stood tall, and patterns of blue meshed with patterns of green on its surface. All of the pieces had been placed neatly where they belonged, but despite this care, the seams were clearly visible. Indeed, they gleamed with gold. Thick lines of the metal traced the joints between each piece. It was ostentatious, calling attention to the damage rather than trying to hide it.

Perry looked horrified. "This looks like we went mad," he hissed to Siobhan.

"Shut up," she whispered back, fiercely.

"We wanted to do a technique from Japan called 'kintsugi.' It's a traditional Japanese craft, and part of an approach that doesn't try to hide the history of a piece of broken ceramic, but instead make that history part of the visible story of the piece," Craig said, sounding a bit wooden and rehearsed. "We couldn't find a shop that sold the sort of lacquer that would work, which comes from a special tree, so we experimented with different things - potions and some goop from a Doxy nest and that sort of thing that we thought might work."

"This is Skele-Grow, reduced by half," said Siobhan, and she carefully lifted the pot and held it up. "We added a tiny bit of bone to activate it, and dusted it with some powdered gold. Not a lot, and it turns out to be cheaper than you'd think -"

"Because it's very ductile, so it can be made extremely thin," interrupted Perry, smiling as he was won over.

"...and so our receipts still only total up to about five Sickles," finished Siobhan, after an annoyed glance at Perry.

"Wonderful!" exclaimed Professor Syracuse, looking positively delighted. "It looks beautiful - and it shows not just creativity, but real scholarship. This is actually - my goodness - this is actually something specifically mentioned to me by the dean when we discussed this project! He is quite a Japanophile, in fact, and we discussed the wabi-sabi aesthetic in particular!" The professor shook his head, marveling. "I know we don't have any books on the topic… how exactly did you learn about this technique?"

"Ah, well," said Craig, thinking about the notes on the table in the Tower that he'd read while looking for the Feynman book. "We remembered what you said about 'social engineering'... it's easier if you start with half the solution."

The top sheet had read:

Santo, one final thought on my suggested assignment for next week:

I don't want to step on your toes, or make you feel like you have to give this. We promised you broad discretion when Minerva first came to you about your position in Killarney, and that hasn't changed. This is just an idea I thought would be fun. The idea here isn't just to make it difficult or tedious, since students will encounter enough of that without our help. But we're giving them only the rudiments of a scientific education here… I want to challenge them as much as possible. I mentioned kintsugi to you as one possible solution to the project, but it's also a metaphor for the wizarding world. You're a Muggleborn, and you were ostracized for relying on Muggle science for your research on mermaids and evolution, so you know what we're up against as we try to change society. These students are golden, but we have to make them strong... so they can hold together a broken world.

-H

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

I think it goes back to my high school days. In computer class, the first assignment was to write a program to print the first 100 Fibonacci numbers. Instead, I wrote a program that would steal passwords of students. My teacher gave me an A.

-Kevin Mitnick

Chapter 41: Mascon

300 miles above the Earth

May 16th, 1999

Now

"Pocket is away," Basil Horton said into the radio. He folded the controls to the waldo back into the wall, and the sturdy little arm, moved by the Protean Charm to mimic the movement of the controls, collapsed against the outside of the ship, out of sight beneath the viewport. He watched the satellite, freed of the waldo's grip, float away. "Floating free of the ship - I don't see any problems."

He waited for a response, squinting at the Muggle device, irritably. There was none. Scowling, Basil got to his knees in the small space between the pilot's seat and the wall, pushed down by the ship's inverted floating charm, and tapped the bulky black radio box. Probably waited until now to give up the ghost. Would be typical. Everything works fine until the very moment it becomes important.

He tapped the microphone on the headset again, and repeated the message. There was still no response… just the quiet crackles or hissing. At least it had electricity, and the speaker still seemed to be working. Basil cursed the very name of Marconi and got back to his feet, stooping significantly. He was a big man with an athletic build, even if he'd gotten a bit soft around the middle in recent years, and he couldn't stand comfortably in the ship without rapping his head against the smooth goblin-silver ceiling.

The entire ship was ridiculous, really… just a big silver ball. When that Ronnie Weasley boy had taken the first trip up, everyone had been all agog about "making history" and claptrap like that. The ginger idiot had the biggest, stupidest grin that Basil had ever seen when he got into the ship, and called out some Russian word before they closed the hatch - sounded like "Poor you kal" or some nonsense.

Should he get out the spare, or the repair kit? He could fix the damn thing, he knew… it was one of seventeen Muggle devices that they'd trained him to repair (sitting in a desk in some miserable little Muggle classroom like a wandless nitwit). Maybe something was wrong on the RCP's end, instead.

Basil tugged gently at the lead coming out of the back of the radio, to see if it had come loose on either end. The gobbos had needed to bore a small hole through the surface of the sphere, so that the Tower could slap an antenna along the outside, after discovering that the ship became more and more radio-impenetrable by the day. Had that lead gotten loose outside, or had one of the seals fouled it up somehow? Could the seals strangle off the flow of the signal, somehow? Basil considered. He didn't think so.

Annoyed, he turned and peered out the viewport. The brown satchel of the pocket world was visible, securely fixed to a Mitsubishi platform and surrounded by the white plastic Leaf spheres that protected the electronic sensors, thrusters, and other Muggle components. It seemed to be unharmed, but it also wasn't adjusting its attitude or showing any other signs that the staff at the RCP had taken control. They didn't seem to have heard him; they were still waiting to hear that the pocket was clear.

Maybe the radio had died - killed by a nearby enchantment or his own spells? There should have been enough Leaf inside the casing to protect it, absorbing ambient magic and preventing the accompanying electromagnetic interference, but the ship had been put into orbit with the Vanishing Cabinet on the Monroe, their first satellite… that could have been too much magic for the radio to endure.

Basil thought about the Tower's words when they'd been talking about possible equipment failures and the necessary redundancies. "My father always says that firm percussive maintenance is part of any good troubleshooting toolkit," the young man had said - speaking in that way he had, both patronizing and making an annoying show of being considerate. Hard to believe that everyone in the Ministry fell all over themselves to try to please the kid… in Basil's opinion, Potter had just been lucky in his friends. He was riding back-broom after the Goddess, holding onto her coat-tails. Someday soon, she'd take over, and Potter would be put in his place.

"Basil? Are you clear of the pocket? We have its camera, now, but we don't see you," buzzed the radio, and not even the crackle of static could hide the sweetness of Dolores Umbridge's voice. Basil smiled, then leaned over and gave the radio a single good thump with the palm of his hand. It squealed and fell completely silent. Bugger.

He took another glance out at the pocket world, which was floating further and further away, and then sighed heavily. Merlin's nose, there's nothing for it but to get to it… Muggle junk. Basil opened the supply kit and found the pouch labeled "A6," and began the process of getting out the backup radio (bulkier with even more Lovegood Leaf to shield its components) and connecting it to the antenna lead. He should have enough time to try broadcasting. If it didn't work, he'd use the Vanishing Cabinet and a Quotes Quill, however clunky that solution might be. He wished the bubblers had enough range that they could just use them, or that they'd hurry up in the Vision Verge and get some other magical solution.

After almost fifteen minutes of laborious fiddling, Basil shoved the broken radio into the pouch and grabbed the headset of the new one, turning the frequency knob until the display showed the correct number. "Hullo… Dolores, am I transmitting?"

"Basil!" said Umbridge. "We were worried," she cooed. "Everything all right?" He could picture her as she spoke, that curvy beauty. Basil grinned.

"Fine, fine. Pocket is away and I'm well clear. Bit of trouble with this Muggle junk, but I've sorted it out," he said into the radio.

"Well done, Basil," Umbridge said, sounding a bit tinny over the radio - but still sweet. "We're getting a good connection with the pocket. Keep an eye on it, wouldn't you?"

Basil shifted around the pilot's seat and sat down in it, radio still in hand. He rested his free palm on one of his guidance sticks. "Of course, madame." He willed the stick to move - as though he were flying a broomstick, funny enough - and the ship shifted slightly so that he had a clear view of the satellite.

He watched as one and then another of the thrusters fired in short bursts, and the satchel-carrying satellite, with its completely mental marriage of Muggle and magical materiel, moved gradually… presumably, finding a stable orbit.

The radio crackled. "Everything looks good on our end. How is it up there? Are you receiving still?"

"Five by five," Basil replied with a touch of irony, and smiled as Umbridge tittered. "Yes, everything looks good." He watched as the satellite slowly spun in place, and settled back a little into his seat.

The whole thing was truly remarkable, he had to admit. He never would have dreamed of this sort of thing when he was a younger man - it was more than impossible, it was inconceivable - beyond what he could have imagined. But these days… well, everything was speeding up and there were new ideas and new devices every week, it seemed. Anything seemed possible in a world where Muggles could fly beyond the end of the air. Basil and most everyone else might poke fun at the antics of the Muggles and their crude, fragile world… but they'd lain down there in the mud and looked up at the stars, and reached for them. It was inspiring, really.

After the satellite was safely in orbit, floating precisely where it should be, according to its onboard sensors and the tracking data they were collecting in the increasingly well-staffed RCP, Basil stayed in position for some time. He stared out at the steady dots of light that were scattered in the black like glittering alchemist's sand.

Basil knew the plans - what they wanted to do. What the Tower wanted. He wanted to send wizards out there… out among those stars.

It had started small - sending up the Monroe with its onboard Vanishing Cabinet, and sending the goblin-silver ship through that Cabinet, carrying a Weasley, for a test run of twelve minutes. Half of the onboard equipment had failed and one of the seams on the viewscreen had leaked, but Weasley had come through it unharmed. He'd made another trip three days later with new equipment shielded against ambient magic. Basil went out the next week, and by now between the two of them they had nearly twenty hours of flight-time.

And now they had the pocket world - the "slicebox world," as some called it - in orbit as well. After testing its stability, they'd be bringing out the airlock chamber in pieces from the Monroe and locking it on outside of that brown satchel. They'd pump the vast chamber full of air and put some of the more useful Transfiguration wards in place as a safeguard. Then they'd slap a high-powered, long-term, upside-down Floating Charm on the whole giant cavern to float everything towards the "ground," just like the ship Basil was in. It would be its own little world.

There would be a lot of testing, of course. Basil was friendly with one of the gobbos - good bloke, even if he was a Puddlemere supporter - who had told him that the Tower already had some of the people in Material Methods working on a way to transport huge amounts of soil and water. There were even some specific sites in mind, such as some wetlands in the American South. Of course, even after they filled the big thing with dirt and water and whatever, it would still be experimental. Basil supposed they'd leave rats and flies in the pocket world for a good month before even beginning human testing, and the first planned permanent residents would be acromantulas.

But the trajectory was clear. Wizards in pocket worlds, out in space.

Basil sat there for a long time, and watched the stars.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 16th, 1999

"Trade?" asked Harry, leaning forward on the stool. He reached over and moved the microphone away from the shiny black box. The box flickered with a pulse of reddish light as he did so.

Voldemort fell silent, the bland male voice going quiet for a few beats. Any pause was a message - surely Voldemort had already considered whether he'd be willing to trade more information, and what questions he might ask in return. A pause this long was very nearly a shout - a strong reminder that the voice in the box had leverage. Harry smiled.

"Yes," came the answer, eventually.

"You discovered the Chamber of Secrets of Salazar Slytherin. I'd like to hear about that… whatever you could share." I'll cast a wide net, first.

"Very well. In exchange, I would like to know more about your Tower," replied Voldemort.

"Vetoed," Harry said immediately. He didn't need to think about it: he'd set some hard rules about what information he was willing to trade, and some things fell entirely out of the range of acceptable discussion. And this was spectacularly dangerous information.

Harry remembered.

"Tell me what you can do." No answer.

"Tell me what you are." No answer.

"Help." No answer.

"Root." No answer. In fairness, that one had been rather a longshot.

"Noitlilov." And with that - at that word, which really should have been obvious, since why have any backwards-meaning runes on the device at all, honestly it didn't provide any security and just looked silly, you just needed to spent thirty seconds with a microcasette recorder to figure it out - the Mirror changed. The image of Harry and the Hogwarts room behind him vanished. In its place, the Mirror displayed question.

Not the word "question," or a symbol like a question mark, or really any other visual communication. Instead, the very idea of questioning was reflected in the Mirror. This was obviously sheer semantic nonsense since an amorphous concept had no physical reality that could be represented with light, and Harry thought it was ridiculously silly. Obnoxiously, it continued to be true.

Harry considered what he would ask of the Mirror.

"Show me the world where the phoenixes came from." He could try to verify some of the information he already had about the Mirror, and maybe discover more about how it worked.

Nothing happened. Still only: question.

"Show me my extrapolated volition." Nothing.

"Show me my coherent extrapolated volition." Nothing.

"Noitilov detalo partxe tnere hoc." Nothing.

Different attempts at pronunciation also had no result.

There was only the question, staring back at him. What question? What was it asking? Voldemort had said that the Mirror was supposed to possess morality - didn't that imply intelligence? Or that it consulted some external intelligent to make moral assessments of a person or situation or request? Could every possibility have been programmed into it ahead of time? Or did it borrow intelligence or morality from the viewer somehow?

What was it asking?

Did it want to know what he wanted?

Harry closed his eyes for a moment, then opened them again. He stared intently at the Mirror and said, his voice fervent with desire, and spoke his will.

"Sorry," Harry said again, returning to the present. "Can't do it."

Within the Tower, the Killing Curse had no power to take life. Here, the human spirit clung to the flesh more tenaciously than anywhere else. It was a plane of life and possibility, accidentally discovered - or accidentally created - during those hesitant experiments with the Mirror, years ago. That secret was beyond price.

It didn't matter that Voldemort was stuck in the box. There was not even the slightest reason to risk it, and the rules of their trading game stated that Harry had absolute veto power.

"More about this box, at least -"

"Vetoed," Harry said again, interrupting.

This was easier. Harry simply didn't know much about the box. Neither did the Unspeakables. It was clearly an item of significant power, and bore every mark of being goblin-made, but the only information that the Department of Mystery had on record was that it was intended to be an unbreachable prison. Tentative investigation, carefully done to avoid piquing anyone's notice, had turned up more than a few possibilities for the box… but no definitive answer.

Those would both obviously be off-limits, Harry thought. Next will come a slightly more subtle question, which I will feel more obliged to answer. But that didn't serve. No, it would be another level further.

"All right, then," said Voldemort. There was a tone of resignation in the voice - he had been getting more and more adept with using the magically-generated speech to convey emotion or emphasis. "Tell me about Ms. Granger, then. What have the effects of the Gattai Ritual been on her?"

Harry could see no reason to avoid this question. It seemed harmless, and was certainly something that Voldemort would be genuinely curious about.

"Vetoed," he said. Just because he couldn't spot the plot at work, or understand what Voldemort might gain, didn't mean he had to agree to the first mysterious step.

"Tell me about some new person, someone interesting," replied Voldemort, almost immediately. There was an odd warble to his last word. Harry supposed it was the artificial voice's version of "irritation."

"All right," said Harry. He felt confident he could make a harmless selection.

"You have already seen the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets - the hidden door had a mural of Salazar fighting a jötnar. We took a different passage, one of many that Salazar wove through Hogwarts and required the castle to maintain, but had we continued down the first path, we would have come to the Chamber proper. It is a large stone vault in a plain style, rather like the Tower of Mendoza, lit by a green light. I assume we would also have found the bones of a basilisk, fallen and defanged where I left it, but at the time that I first discovered the Chamber, the basilisk was very much alive and dwelling within a ludicrous statue of Salazar Slytherin himself. It ignored me, and did not look upon me, and would not speak to me despite my commands in Parseltongue." Voldemort paused. "I was a young man, then, and not as rich in lore, but I had wits enough to recognize the telltale shape of the statue's joints, and magic enough to know the minor enchantment which gave mobility to the design. All of the statues in Hogwarts have the same purpose. I could see the expected next step.

"When animated, the statue attempted to engage me in an old game of gestures which had been popular for many centuries in Salazar's time. It is a game of symbols with a vocabulary of hand-signs, combining them in sequences of three, and one attempts to back one's opponent into a position where they can take no action. It is forgotten today by all except the most learned.

"I was poor and unpracticed at the game, knowing about it only from hoary scrolls, and I swiftly lost. The basilisk ignored me when I commanded it to assist me, replying that it had ears only for victory. I played the game again with the statue, which moved its stone limbs with flawless strategy.

"Some hours later, I was finally able to win by playing the Pestle, the Dragon, and the Worm. The statue of Salazar bowed to me and returned to its former posture - arms crossed, intending to be imposing. Only then would the basilisk speak to me, asking me to produce something called the 'writ of the blood,' in preparation for the second trial." There was another pause from the box, accompanied by a buzz. Harry had heard this imitation of a sigh before. "I admit that I lost my temper, then, and acted out of turn. I cast the Killing Curse thrice in succession, deliberately missing the basilisk each time, and I made some sort of speech - the bold words of an ignorant boy, threatening and demanding in Parseltongue.

"This, too, was within the expectations of Salazar Slytherin, it would seem, for the basilisk hissed its laughter and asked me what I would know of it."

"You destroyed the basilisk, so you must have been satisfied that you'd learned everything it could teach you," Harry said. "How did that work?"

"It was a matter of some months, Mr. Potter. An intellectual game between the basilisk and myself. It was compelled to cooperate with me, but was also driven to continually assess my motives, worthiness, and will… this meant that it did not merely spill its secrets. It required things of me… further trials, and it would accept no bluffs. It was a… harrowing time. And I think that is all I will speak of it, for now."

Harry didn't press the issue, yet, by asking about specific spells or rituals. That treasure trove still existed, and had incredible value, but there was no reason to press the issue. And as far as Harry could verify, the story was true. He'd been to the Chamber of Secrets, and found only a statue and a skeleton.

"Tell me of an interesting person, then, Mr. Potter," said Voldemort.

Harry considered who would qualify as interesting while still being harmless. "All right. There is a young man named Lawrence Bradwian whom I met a few months ago. He has a prophecy about him, supposedly… he is said to be fated to 'bring down a great house.' You'd think this would result in him being shunned by everyone else with noble blood, but instead he seems to be quite popular. He's a Slytherin, but almost seems a Gryffindor… rescuing a half-giant from persecution, breaking up a Euphoric ring, and accidentally helping me recover an artifact." One of your oldest Horcruxes, which we then destroyed, along with dozens of others we've found by tracing the paths of the invisible links between them with the most sensitive magic detector ever created, Harry thought, remembering the device Luna's team had created. "He even badly assaulted a classmate and framed him for an attack on the Tower, with the goal of becoming… I don't know, my protege or favorite? He's a Silver Slytherin, so I think he was more misguided than anything."

"And I expect you did not expel him or arrange for his removal, ensuring no large disruptions in the political scene? Instead, did you take him aside for a gentle scolding?" asked Voldemort.

"Well," said Harry, "rather more than that. But yes, I arranged for him to learn what real intrigue and danger and fear are like. I never put him in any real danger, but I think the experience might have been enough to actually change his mind. That's harder to do than one might think."

Like when you tried with me.

"I recall. Be careful you are not being overconfident."

Harry shook his head. "He's back in his normal student role, and one of the Silver Slytherin mentors - a Tower auror - is keeping an eye on him."

"It is a disturbing thing to hear how little you have learned from your own story, Mr. Potter. Do you not think that someone in a position of power should perhaps be wary of an adventurous and precocious young man with a prophesied role in great events? Does that not, perhaps, call anything to mind?"

"The thought had occurred to me," Harry said. He felt a moment of sadness… Voldemort should be speaking in the acid tones of a sarcastic Professor Quirrell for this moment of mocking pedagogy. He paused, then asked in a natural tone, "Willing to do another trade? I'd like to hear about the Resurrection Stone, if you're willing to discuss it."

It was tempting to add a diversionary turn of phrase, such as "wherever it may be" or "if I ever got ahold of it," or the like. But in the absence of body language and nonverbal cues, Harry had to be even more careful about his phrasing to avoid revealing to Voldemort that they'd already captured the Resurrection Stone, along with Bellatrix Black.

He had plans, and had uncovered some of the designs and powers of the Resurrection Stone - including some truly surprising things about the Peverell "brothers," but that didn't mean verification wouldn't be useful.

"No… I think not, Mr. Potter," replied the bland voice of Voldemort. "I know you have grand designs, and I do not object to many of them. But I will not help you in that, I think."

"Okay, Professor," said Harry, already deep in thought over his next possible question. "But let's talk about something else. Let's talk about some theories of magic. I have been doing some reading of both old and new ideas… tell me about how this theory sounds."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Powis Castle, Wales

May 16th, 1999

"So tell me honestly, Simon: how do you think we stand, right now? There are no big threats on the horizon, and no reason not to take every bit of necessary time to make sure they're okay," Hermione said. "We can let the world wait until they're feeling better."

"Esther is quiet. She doesn't say much... it's like before. Tonks is… I don't know," said Simon. His voice sounded flat and tired, and the hollowness of his eyes was more pronounced. These had been rough weeks for everyone.

Hermione turned to Nikitas Seyhan, who was sitting quietly at the table with them. The young man had been here at Powis for months, and seemed to regard it as his natural home… certainly he appeared to have no desire to ever return back to Cappadocia. His twelve years in Göreme had wiped out most of his memories of his old life anyway. He had learned some decent English, received a new face, and grown close to his caretakers here… the people like Jessie and Simon who had looked after him, in the time since his liberation. He'd Returned, and he looked likely to stay.

"Nikitas? What do you think?" she asked him, gently.

He looked surprised that she'd ask, and after a moment began to appear almost panicked.

"It's okay, dear," Hermione said with her best reassurance, smiling. She leaned forward to put a hand on his shoulder, patting him softly. "Just take a moment and think. Esther, Hyori, and Tonks all went through a lot on Walpurgisnacht. You know them. How do you think they are doing?"

"Hyori," Nikitas said, awkwardly, "only ever just one word."

"That's normal," said Simon.

Nikitas hesitated, then went on. "Esther does not talk. Before, she talked much more." He paused again. "Tonks…" He trailed off, frowning, and finally made a pained face and shrugged, discomfited.

"It's okay," Hermione repeated, warmly. She turned back to Simon. "We take as long as we need. Get in touch with St. Mungo's… let's get some outside help. This is different from dementation."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Khecheopalri Village, West Sikkim, India

May 16th, 1999

The mountains of Sikkim lie far to the north in India, in a region balkanized by the vagaries of history and war. They are cold and high and proud, counting the mighty peak of Kangchenjunga among their number. One of these mountains cradles the lakeside village of Khecheopalri, twenty miles away from the nearest sizable town. It is a small village, with perhaps two dozen buildings and eighty residents. Few Muggle tourists ever visit, except to see the holy lake - said to be a footprint left by Lord Shiva - and the last time a wizard came to stay was during the eighteenth century.

Even at this time of year, it is cold in Khecheopalri. When an older man left the small village temple, he traced his fingers on the surface of the bell, and found it unpleasantly cold. He pulled an old shawl closer around his shoulders, and walked off down the path away from the temple, slowly.

After some time, he reached his home. It appeared as modest as its neighbors - two rooms and a garden. A small pile of broken and discarded chhang gourds lie in one corner of the garden. The man entered the building, nodding a hello to one of his neighbors, Dorji, who was outside, trying to enjoy the warm sunshine, sheltered from the wind behind her low garden wall as she wrapped momos.

After some time, the man emerged. He went to the small wall that separated his garden from Dorji's, and addressed her politely in Sikkimese Tibetan.

"Dorji-la, I am going away on a small trip to Siliguri. I may be gone some time. I wonder if I could ask you to tend to my garden, in my absence?"

Dorji was already nodding and waving in agreement before he even finished speaking. "Yes, yes. Not a problem. We have been neighbors since I was young, and my garden and yours are one. But you go away so seldom! I hope there is no tragedy, umdze."

"No, no tragedy. Just a small matter of a property to which I must attend," said the man, smiling. "It is not a happy journey, and full of risk, but that is life."

"I hope that you have good results, umdze," Dorji said, smiling and placing another momo on the growing pile.

"Thank you. I hope so myself, as well," the man agreed, nodding solemnly.

"Let us play a game of shatranj when you return… it has been too long since you schooled me in my ignorance, umdze," she said, and returned her attention to her cooking.

"I would enjoy that," said the man. He returned inside of his home, to make preparations for leaving.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

"And were we not saying long ago that the soul when using the body as an instrument of perception, that is to say, when using the sense of sight or hearing or some other sense (for the meaning of perceiving through the body is perceiving through the senses)—were we not saying that the soul too is then dragged by the body into the region of the changeable, and wanders and is confused; the world spins round her, and she is like a drunkard, when she touches change?"

"Very true."

"But when returning into herself she reflects, then she passes into the other world, the region of purity, and eternity, and immortality, and unchangeableness, which are her kindred, and with them she ever lives, when she is by herself and is not let or hindered; then she ceases from her erring ways, and being in communion with the unchanging is unchanging. And this state of the soul is called wisdom?"

"That is well and truly said, Socrates," he replied.

Phaedo, Plato

Chapter 43: Pip Around the World

Portkey Office, Ministry of Magic, Whitehall, London
May 17th, 1999

"Hullo!" said Pip, smiling at the gent at the Official Business desk.

He looked up wearily from a thick ledger, squinting at Pip. "Hello." He stared at Pip with red-rimmed eyes, and waited. Pip smiled brightly back at him, expectantly. Finally, the man said, "Can I help you with something?"

"Auror Philip Pirrip, here to pick up some portkeys," said Pip, his smile dimming slightly at the reception. It brightened again as he leaned forward and said, meaningfully, "On business for the Tower."

The official stared at Pip for a moment, then looked back down at the ledger. He ran his finger down a column on the left, and then the one next to it. "Pirrip, Philip… yes. 875 Oxtail Red." He looked back up at Pip, and shoved back from his desk. His wheeled seat squeaked rhythmically as it bore him over to a bureau along the wall of the office. The man didn't even bother to get up, but just pushed himself along with his legs as he trailed an index finger along one row of small drawers, then down to another. All of them were progressively darker shades of red. When the official had found the one he wanted, he yanked it open. "Here we are, then." Another scoot of his chair brought the man squeaking back to his desk and Pip.

The official put a velvet sack on the desk. "Hangzhou, Bangkok, Cyprus, and return to the Ministry. All labeled. Don't mix them up." He took a quill from his desk and made some notes in his ledger, shoving the sack over to Pip.

"Thank you," Pip said, scooping up the sack. He opened it and checked inside, just for a quick count of the grimy old envelopes inside. There were four, sure enough. One of the envelopes was open - it looked to have an old biro inside.

"They're all there and all correct," said the man behind the desk, and Pip looked up to see him frowning in disapproval.

"Just checking," Pip said, uncomfortably. "After that thing the Weasley twins did, it just -"

"They're all there and all correct," said the official again, grindingly. He slammed the heavy ledger shut, and his inkwell rattled on the desk. They didn't like to be reminded of when the Weasleys had replaced all the Russian and Hungarian portkeys. Everyone who'd tried to go to Moscow had ended up in the third-floor loo, instead.

Well, there was no telling from looking at the bloody things, anyway, Pip supposed. He'd just have to hope he didn't end up somewhere nasty. Or if not, at least someplace dry.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Yu's Library, The Court of Rubies, Hangzhou

"Hullo!" said Pip, his face serious. "I'm here to pick up a parcel for Mr. Harry Potter-Evans-Verres." He did his absolute best to project an image of power and foreign might, tilting his chin upward and slightly to the side. It was a haughty look, he thought - the look of someone who had looked death in the eye and triumphed.

"Are you okay?" Sunny Chow asked from his side. He turned to see the Wizengamot's Special Envoy to the Court of Rubies staring up at him. She was shorter than average for someone of Asian descent, and she was looking at him frank curiosity in her hazel eyes.

Pip deflated slightly. Maybe his jawline wasn't strong enough to pull that off.

"No parcels here," said the librarian, his English heavily accented. He shook his head, and swept one palm around the room, as though to draw Pip's attention to the towering, haphazard stacks of books and piles of scrolls that occupied almost all of the long and wide room. "This is the library. You want the owlery. That way, sir." He pointed to one of the doors.

"No, Zhongying," said Chow, waving a hand dismissively. "This is Auror Pirrip. His Excellency He Jin has left a package here for the auror. It's going to a Mr. Harry Potter-Evans-Verres. His Excellency would have left this here himself."

"I will check," said the librarian. He turned and made his way to a corner of the room, stepping lightly among stacks of books that were easily twice his own height. They swayed unsteadily, simply from the touch of air left by his passage, but none of them fell.

Why a queer way to sort everything, thought Pip, watching a pyramid of scrolls. A stray scroll slipped from its place at the top of the heap and skidded halfway down the side of the pile, only to catch on the curling corner of a companion and hang there, precariously. And this place would be a nightmare to defend. Must be like this for protection against theft, and maybe camouflage. Hard to browse, but maybe that's not something they want people doing.

The librarian pushed aside a false panel in the wooden wall, and withdrew a metal case. He opened it, and Pip saw it was filled with glowing phials of memories. The librarian squinted at them, then nodded, slowly. He turned back to them. "Yes, there is something here for you. I apologize for my rudeness. If it would not be too much trouble, I must use precautions before I retrieve your package." He gestured at one of the few clear areas on the floor, and Pip saw that there was a faint outline of chalk there in the shape of a circle.

Pip glanced at the Special Envoy, but Chow had nodded easily, and was already stepping into the circle. He joined her. "What is this?" he muttered, uneasily. "Ward?"

"Not quite. Do you know the writings of a Xiang Yu?" Chow whispered back. The librarian rummaged in his robe, pulling his wand from some interior pocket. Pip shook his head in the negative.

"Well," Chow said, as the librarian pointed his wand at them, "let's just say you don't want to move."

"Peskipiksi rendehoushan," cast the librarian.

Almost without transition, Pip and Chow were encircled by an orange screen of some kind. It stretched in an unbroken column from the wooden floor to the wooden ceiling, and Pip could feel the heat of it on his face. He didn't start in surprise, but his wand was already in his hand, and he held the first stage of the wordless Drill Breaking Hex ready in his mind. But they didn't seem to be in any immediate danger, as long as they didn't move, and Chow was standing calmly next to him with her arms folded.

Pip could see through the orange. It was some manner of liquid, and small eddies and swirls moved lazily through it, but also thin enough that it was translucent. The librarian was visible through it, and Pip watched him as he stepped to one side of the room, and levitated a short stack of books to one side, uncovering a Pensieve. He added a memory to it, and then immersed his head.

Less than a minute later, the librarian rose from the basin, and turned to the chalk circle. He whispered the command word inaudibly, and the orange glare vanished as quickly as it had come.

"I apologize to you, Special Envoy and sir auror," the librarian said, inclining his head slightly. "The parcel was left here under some special circumstances, and we were not permitted to know about it."

"It is, I am told, a matter of some security and secrecy," said Chow. "The fault is ours, not yours."

The librarian inclined his head again, and turned to the wall where he'd retrieved the memory. He took hold of a seemingly random wooden panel and pulled on it, and the board telescoped out from the wall, revealing itself to be a large cabinet with numerous small cubby-holes apparent in its surface.

He pulled on the knobs of four of the drawers in sequence, and the last one slid open at his touch, allowing the librarian to slide his hand inside. The mouth of the cubby was too small for this, but it obligingly distended to permit him to reach inside.

I bet that if you do the sequence wrong, or choose the wrong little drawer, or something else like that, then you could lose your hand that way, Pip marveled. It was a good idea, but he'd bet it led to a lot of accidents. He'd have to tell the Ministry about it. Maybe they could imitate it, and a certain rude squeaky squinty git at the Portkey Office might be a little more polite in the future.

The librarian slowly and gently pulled out something from the hole - a book. No, part of a book. The ragged edges of torn binding showed that it was just a few dozen pages and a cover, ripped free from the whole book. The librarian turned and offered the packet to Chow, inclining his head again. She accepted it, bowing slightly in return, and turned to hand it to Pip.

He took it, and glanced at the cover. Not Mandarin, but an English book. Not new binding either, and it looked at least two or three centuries old. But it was also clearly the rebinding… a glance at the exposed back page showed that it was truly ancient, tinted yellow and marred with small imperfections in the parchment. The longskin goat had been bred in the fourteenth century, making the original book at least six hundred years old. It had seen some mishandling, too… affixed inside of the cover was a scrap of parchment that was clearly only the middle part of a page. None of the text was legible to him, which was probably just as well.

Pip looked at the cover again. The book was by Harry Lowe, according to the gilt letters.

The Transmygracioun, it was called.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

resisted them with its power. Our people took hold of the knowledge, and have donne great things. Likewise in the future, there will be invaders. But thei shall take the whole world. Fear shall come with them, and ruin. There lies the doom of which I have spoken to you. Þis shall not last. There shall be new maistery, and new maisters to take the place of the old. I have seen þis, and so I say to ye to come þis key. The fires of the soul are great and burn

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

The Wizarding Bank of Bangkok, Bangkok, Thailand

"Hullo!" said Pip, peering over the counter. "Anyone here?"

The bank building was dimly lit and poorly maintained. The floor was beautiful marble, but it was marked with innumerable scratches and scrapes. The long front desk was similar, made of a creamy soapstone marred with long gashes all along its surface. The place looked deserted, without even a guard, which was rather odd for a bank. It was somehow stranger, though, when Pip noticed that there also wasn't any furniture. No stools were behind the counter, no message boxes or unsummonable security boxes were resting on it, and there weren't even any chairs for customers.

"ขอโทษ… ขอโทษ!" called a voice from a back room, speaking in rapid Thai. A moment later, a chubby man with dark skin shuffled out into view. He was wearing a loose white robe and linen trousers, and he was barefoot. "สวัสดีครับ."

"Sorry, do you speak English?"

"คุณพูดไทยได้ไหม?" came the reply from the man, who looked puzzled.

"What?"

"อะไร?"

"Is there anyone here who speaks English?" Pip said, desperately. He'd just assumed that the bank would have someone who spoke English. Maybe that was silly, but English had been the wizarding language of the world for centuries. Almost everything the Confederation did was in English.

"Prasong!" called out the man, turning to shout over his shoulder. "Praaaaaasong! Prasong! คนอังกฤษ!"

"Yaaaaa!" called a response, sounding irritable. "ฉันกำลังมาาาาาาา!" Another man emerged from the back room. He looked identical to the first. For a moment Pip worried that he was turning into a Muggle and a horrible person, but realized after a moment that the two were twins.

"Hello, sir?" said the second twin. He had a strange way of speaking, ending each sentence as though it were a question. "Welcome to the Wizarding Bank of Bangkok? Can I help you?"

"Yes, hullo. I'm here to pick up a parcel? Auror Philip Pirrip, from Britain?" said Pip. He glanced around the room. "Is everything all right here?"

"Yes? Only English parcel here, I think?" said the man, nodding. "No problems?" He turned to his brother and said some things rapidly. They sounded like questions but were apparently instructions instead, since the other man vanished into the back again, nodding repeatedly.

Pip and the anglophone stood there in silence, awkwardly. The Thai man yawned hugely, rubbing at his face. Pip wondered if he'd just woken up. It was rather late here, after all.

"Where is everything?" Pip asked, speaking up to break the silence.

"Everything what?" asked the man.

"Well, this is a bank, right? Where are all the… banking things?" Pip finished, lamely.

The man shrugged. "We don't want things to be stolen? Money is in the vaults, so we can keep it from people… outside?" He flapped his hand at the door.

"But what's to stop someone from just… going back there and going into the vaults? Only you're here to guard the place," Pip pointed out. "In Gringott's, they have all sorts of guards… wizards and goblins both." He paused. "Are there loads of goblins back there or something?"

The man scratched his face, looking thoughtful at the question, then shook his head. "No, no… all the guards down on the sub-level? And Prethang and I are สควิบ… ah, Squibs? We just work?"

"This doesn't make any bloody sense," said Pip.

The Squib (could that be true?) shrugged. "One way into the bank? Naga live there, and they eat magic? If you are magic or have magic, they will eat you? So we go through the waterfall and down to the bank?" He shrugged again. "Guards down there, though, if you worry?"

Pip studied him. "That can't be true. There's not a kind of beast that only eats wizards. Professor Kettleburn wasn't good, but he wasn't so bad he'd have left that out."

The man just shrugged a third time, and said nothing. The pair stood in silence until his twin returned bearing another torn piece of book. It was the same book, Pip saw immediately. The last page was mostly gone, with only the first third still present. The rips looked like they would fit together.

The auror left without ever getting an answer, though he would make a full report. He never would find out the secrets of the Bangkok Bank… or a great many other things.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Alle of these things I have told you, but there is one thing I have not told you. Þis then hear, and then I shall be donne. At the end of his tyme, Merlin seiden then he hadde a great prophetie, but that he would not explain it. He seiden instead these words, and bade rememberance. "The Achaeans have brought many knowledge to owr island of Britain. Thei came to us as invaders, joyning with the little and the færie and laying waste to our places of power. Ac Britain is a strong land, and it

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Cypriot Hold, Cyprus

"Hullo!" said Pip. Some of the cheer had worn out of his voice, but he still tried to keep his best foot forward. It was like his mum always said: Act like a troll and folks will treat you like one.

The woman who turned towards Pip to fix him with a wary look was intimidatingly tall and extraordinarily beautiful. Thick waves of black hair were swept up into a loose and long ponytail that nearly reached her back, and her formal robes were a glimmering metallic fabric that clung to her body with the tailored precision of enchanted garments. Her eyebrows were sharply sculpted, slashing in skeptical curves over enormous brown eyes.

"Auror Pirrip?" she asked, her voice a throaty burr. "From the Tower?"

Pip thought he must be floating.

"Yes," he managed. "It is I."

She studied him for a moment longer, then nodded. "I am Lady Feri Sarah Ellesmere Önder, of the Noble House of Önder. I have a parcel for you, if you wish it."

Pip nodded, and tried to keep his smile from stretching to silly dimensions. "Thank you, Lady Önder. That would be appreciated."

"This way, then."

Pip fell into step next to the Cypriot as she led the way out of the Hold. It was a fragile-looking building of fluted glass columns and diamondine crenulations, and it looked all the more delicate for the damage that scarred its sides. Fire had taken some of the columns, and great melted rents had eaten into the walls behind. When the Tower had fought back against Independent aggression around the world, the Cappadocians had seized the opportunity to attack their ancient enemy once more. Even at this hour, three goblins were at work repairing a column. The wizard who owned them stood nearby - an immediate reminder that this was a barbaric country in some ways. It was scarcely believable that the bloody slavers here considered themselves British.

"Why has your master requested this book of me?" asked the Lady Önder as they walked, speaking quietly. "It is the greatest treasure of my House. I'd know the purpose of its journey."

"I don't know, madam," Pip admitted. "He wants to read it, I suppose. My, ah, 'master' is the Tower, and he seems to want to know everything."

Their path took them down the streets of Magical Cyprus, walking on smooth stones that had seen thousands of years of foot-traffic. There were few others on the streets - a single vendor selling aromatic snacks of roasted nut-and-fruit pastries; a pair of young women out for a romantic stroll, arm in arm; and a collared goblin carrying a caged owl.

"Your master thinks he already knows everything, I think," said the Cypriot. She stopped at the door of a grand home of green stone. It was very British in appearance - looked rather like pictures Pip had seen of Malfoy Manor, in fact - with the exception of the elegant minaret that rose from the roof peak. A crest was worked in gold into the stone above the door - three arms bendwise couped.

"What do you mean?" Pip asked.

The Lady Önder opened the door. "The Treaty, and now its successor, have brought much good to me and mine. But there is also a great deal of… direction in it. Matters that I had thought long settled are re-opened, and there is even some… well, some might call it ingratitude." She stepped aside, and gestured. "Please."

Pip nodded, and entered. "I am sorry to hear that you feel this way, madam. Cyprus and Britain have always been close."

The Cypriot smiled sharply. "Not always. But yes, for a long time we have followed the leadership of your country. At times, we have been the only ones to do so. In the minds of many, this should earn us some measure of respect from Britain. A friend does not like to see another friend take advantage."

"You don't like the interference," said Pip. It was cool and dark inside the home, but it was obvious that the House of Önder was enormously wealthy. There were low couches of white bicorn leather, an expensive-looking scrying mirror on one wall, and a vase with a towering arrangement of silver flowers. A wide staircase led up and out of sight.

"We do not," said the Lady Önder. Her voice was chilly. "Things have now been arranged so carefully that we have no alternative. That doesn't mean we need be pleased with that change, or the other changes that will be forced on us."

"I'm sorry that it is disturbing the relations between our countries," said Pip, summoning his best diplomatic turns of phrase. Yes, terribly sorry to be interfering in your bloody slavery, you crazy pile of kneazle-kak. Can't use house-elves like civilized people? What a bother for us to disturb your traditions. I'll try to get out of your hair as soon as possible so you can get back to sipping baby blood out of your goblin-skull goblets, or whatever it is you do here.

"Mithri!" called the Cypriot, raising her voice. "The Britisher is here. Bring me the book."

There was a quiet scraping sound from above. "Yes, Lady Önder," called back a tired voice.

The owner of the voice made his way to them. The steps sounded wrong - a thump and a scrape - and the reason became apparent as speaker came down the stairs, into the lights at the front entrance. It was a goblin, and he had only one leg. He used a crutch, hobbling slowly and carefully down the steps. The Being had very short ears for a goblin, but a long nose. The nose had a kink in the middle. It looked very tired, although at least they'd seen fit to give it decent clothing: a white tunic and necktie. The steel of a collar was just visible under the tie. There was a book under its free arm.

"Here you are, Auror Pirrip," said the Lady Önder, as her slave offered Pip the book. "I do not expect to see it again. I hope it brings your master ill."

"Thank you, Lady Önder," said Pip. "Thank you for everything."

"Everything?" asked the Cypriot, frowning, as Pip walked to the door.

"Yes, everything," Pip said, as he left. "Please believe me when I say that you have made me very proud tonight. Twice."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

as bright as the stars." At þis there was silence, and then protest, and then dismai, for none could understand these words. Thei were once more trublid. Mundre of the Brook took these words and set them down, and from him they passed to his son Mundre, and from him thei were taken by Togrod Teulu, and recovered from the little in the time of Yæl, who passed them to me. I have set them for you, that they may not be lost. So we are complete, and my tale is donne.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Safety Pole, Godric's Hollow

The same day

"Hello," said a kindly-looking older man. "I wonder if you could help me?"

The auror and the healer on duty at the Godric's Hollow Safety Pole were deep in a hand of Dragon Poker, but the healer was dutiful, and he dropped the cards without a thought. He ignored the sour look on the auror's face.

"Of course, sir. Are you feeling all right?" said the healer, drawing his wand.

"A little peaky," said the man. He accepted the offered hand of the healer, nodding gratefully. "It's been a worry."

"Ah, no need to worry any more," said the healer. "Everything will be all right."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Alle of these things I have told you, but there is one thing I have not told you. Þis then hear, and then I shall be donne. At the end of his tyme, Merlin seiden then he hadde a great prophetie, but that he would not explain it. He seiden instead these words, and bade rememberance.

"The Achaeans have brought many knowledge to owr island of Britain. Thei came to us as invaders, joyning with the little and the færie and laying waste to our places of power. Ac Britain is a strong land, and it resisted them with its power. Our people took hold of the knowledge, and have donne great things. Likewise in the future, there will be invaders. But thei shall take the whole world. Fear shall come with them, and ruin. There lies the doom of which I have spoken to you. Þis shall not last. There shall be new maistery, and new maisters to take the place of the old. I have seen þis, and so I say to ye to come þis key. The fires of the soul are great and burn as bright as the stars."

At þis there was silence, and then protest, and then dismai, for none could understand these words. Thei were once more trublid. Mundre of the Brook took these words and set them down, and from him they passed to his son Mundre, and from him thei were taken by Togrod Teulu, and recovered from the little in the time of Yæl, who passed them to me. I have set them for you, that they may not be lost. So we are complete, and my tale is donne.

Harry Lowe, The Transmygracioun, passus tertius decimus

Chapter 44: The Ineluctable Modality of the Visible

"What stories do you mean, and what fault do you find in them?"

"The fault one ought to find first and foremost, especially if the falsehood isn't well told."

"For example?"

"When a story gives a bad image of what the gods and heroes are like, the way a painter does whose picture is not at all like the things he's trying to paint."

"You're right to object to that. But what sort of story in particular do you have in mind?"

"First, telling the greatest falsehood about the most important things doesn't make a fine story - I mean Hesiod telling us about how Uranus behaved, how Cronus punished him for it, and how he was in turn punished by his own son. Even if that were true, it should be passed over in silence, not told to foolish young people. And if, for some reason, it has to be told, only a very few people - pledged to secrecy and after sacrificing not just a pig but something great and scarce - should hear it, so that their number is kept as small as possible."

"Yes. Such stories are hard to deal with."

-The Republic II.377e-378a, Plato

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 17th, 1999

The same day

"Well, that was a waste of two hours," drawled Draco, as he walked into the Pairing Partnership. He closed the door behind him, and the Lovegood Leaf rustled. "I suppose I never really considered just how tedious it would be to watch a gaggle of Muggles for any length of time." He shook his head, and swept one hand along his hair, smoothing it.

"Didn't enjoy the movie?" asked Harry, turning in his seat away from the computer screen. Auror Kraeme, nearby, kept a close eye on Draco. She was leaning with her back against a large metal cabinet, arms folded - but eyes sharp.

"You should call them something different, too. 'Movie'... it just emphasizes how primitive the entire thing is, compared to a real play." He affected his high-pitched Muggle Voice: " 'Wow, look, they're moving just like real people would, if only we had taste enough to go watch an actual troupe of performers!' "

"They used to be called 'talkies,' " Harry said, wryly. "So it could be worse. But ticket sales at the movie theatre go up every week, so I'm not sure that everyone agrees with you."

"It's the thing to do, like eating at Siegfried's. People are sheep, and right now you've set out some new paddocks. That doesn't mean there will be any long-term success. Grindelwald was a fanatic for painting, they say, but it's not as though Hungary is full of painterstoday. After Grindelwald was locked up in Nurmengard, most of the artists went back to sculpting. If you want people to become actually interested, not just intrigued by the novelty, then you need to make movies about things that they care about. Not Muggles with guns," Draco said. He pulled a chair over next to the EEG machine, where Harry was sitting in front of the attached computer.

"I am not going to start a production company," said Harry, shaking his head. But he froze in the middle of the gesture and frowned. "Well, actually, I guess there's no reason why we couldn't do that. They could begin with adaptations of some famous wizard plays, and cast some of the same actors, probably."

"Ah yes, one more industry dominated from first to last by Harry Potter," said Draco. "No, I don't think you'll be doing that. It will hardly help generate an appearance of real success if you look to be propping up your Muggle ventures like that. No, I think we need to decentralize a little."

Harry laughed. "Malfoy Productions?"

Draco glanced over at the auror by the wall, within earshot, wordlessly. Harry followed the glance, then looked back at Draco with a smile. "A Vow of secrecy, don't worry."

The Lord Malfoy nodded, and went on. "Well, I was thinking of a joint venture with some Americans, actually. It wouldn't be difficult to start up a similar movies theatre in Tidewater. There's an old Westphalian ally with deep pockets, Littlebrook Strongbound, who might like to get ahead of your bosom friend Hig on something. Too much gold and control slipping through his fingers… and I think he senses the leash slipping around the Council's neck."

"You'll need visible capital to start something like that," said Harry, "since Malfoys have typically been invested rather heavily in flying castles, which are not known for their liquidity. And the finance sector hasn't been your friend over the past few years." Traditional private usury was almost extinct in Britain, along with the corresponding interest rates. "Too many people are paying attention."

"Yes," said Draco. "A visible success to explain the new money, and I'll whisper in a few confidential ears that it's really Cappadocian gold - payment for steering things their way, here."

"I was thinking Amycus Carrow as a source, actually," said Harry. "If you'd taken control of some of his assets, it would be a tidier explanation."

"The Carrow sisters might not appreciate the news that I've taken control of some of their uncle's properties and loans, Harry," said Draco, raising an eyebrow. "They've already been through rather a lot."

It was subtle and quiet, but those words were question and concern and accusation, all at once. It wasn't like Harry to forget about innocent bystanders - and whatever their ideology, the Carrow sisters were certainly innocent of anything that might merit dragging them through any more ugliness.

"You're right, of course," said Harry, shaking his head. He rubbed his forehead, sighing. "I'm distracted - not at my optimum self today."

"Mm," Draco said, in noncommital acknowledgment. "Anyway, if the Cappadocian plan doesn't seem enough, add another layer for the clever folk: have Moody 'investigate' the possibility that I've co-opted one of the Tower arithmancers, and that the windfall is actually your money. You've already been working on building up their mystique for years, so rumors of a rogue arithmancer would help with that, as well."

"All right," Harry agreed. He sounded unsettled.

"Have you been sleeping enough, Harry?" asked Draco. "Or have you been spending half your time in the clinic tending to mermaids with mumps and Squibs with splinters, and half in here, scanning people's brains as they cast Goat Into Goblet?"

"Why would anyone need a spell to… no, never mind," said Harry, rolling his eyes. "Yes, I've been getting plenty of sleep. There's just been a lot to keep track of. Managing the Tower and Britain and - well, the world - just keeps getting more complicated, especially without Hermione around." Draco pursed his lips, and Harry rushed on. "It's been good to rely on you, of course… but uniting the Treaties hasn't actually simplified the situation."

"And you keep finding new projects," Draco said, agreeably. "Like ancient discoveries one of your Unspeakable or Tower minions brought back to you."

Harry looked surprised. "How did..." He followed Draco's gaze to a nearby table, where a box of Macadam's Easy-Apply Melters was still out, and made a face. "Maybe I am tired," he muttered.

"The only reason you'd need repair strips would be if you were trying to fix something you couldn't transfigure," said Draco, smiling. "And that's a short list. Something we can use?"

"A book about Merlin," said Harry. "It's given me some ideas, but nothing I can use - unless I decide I'd really enjoy the entropic heat death of the universe."

Draco didn't ask. "Then maybe give it a rest. Honestly, you should probably take a vacation. You have the government and the Confederation and Tower research and all of your little side projects, like the stupid movies and the sfaironauts and your theory of magic research. And you've been at this pace for… well, since we met. You can't keep it up forever; you're only a Ravenclaw."

"Maybe I just need some smarter Slytherins to help," said Harry. "Whatever happened to Vincent Crabbe?"

"Still trying to get something working in Nocturne Alley," Draco admitted. "He's never really forgiven me, and I rather think he'd like to be a power of his own. He backed a chandler's, but unfortunately I understand that investment's gone pear-shaped recently." It was an elegant retort and reminder of Draco's subtlety, but Draco didn't gloat, and allowed himself only the slightest smirk. "Anyway, just think of taking a few days off. Leave government to that gawky frump of a Weasley, the world to Bones, and everything else to Moody and me. Catch up on your reading."

"Eventually I'm going to take an entire year off… I'll go to Japan and spend my days having fun in the lab," said Harry. "But not yet. Things are still delicate. I'll be fine."

"I have a feeling this 'eventually' is scheduled sometime after everyone in the world has become free and immortal, there's a city on the Moon, and you've been able to take a quick little jaunt to Atlantis to pick up Dumbledore from outside of Time," said Draco. His voice was gentler than his words.

"We're one minute from midnight, Draco," said Harry, firmly. "Muggles have had the capability to destroy the world for generations, now, and it's only by the grace of Petrov it hasn't happened yet. I'm not going to introduce wizards to science and then take a vacation at the most delicate point. It's too dangerous. Look at Edgar Erasmus and how we've had to juggle people like him, to keep everyone safe." He shook his head. "Merlin tried to shut down the forward march of knowledge, since he thought that magical power was spreading too quickly and too easily. I don't think he was right about the solution, but that doesn't mean he was wrong about the problem. We have to keep tight control over things for right now. It's too dangerous for everyone, otherwise."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Elsewhere in the Tower

The same day

Healer Owen Wilifred frowned. There was something very strange going on, here.

He glanced down at the patient, who was lying unconscious, immobile, and safely stunned. And older man of indeterminate ethnicity - Asia or India or someplace. Clearly never rejuvenated, and no external symptoms. But when Owen moved his wand lower on the patient's abdomen, he kept seeing the same thing: absolutely perfect internal organs, without a single flaw or oddity.

The diagnosis convivium seemed to be working correctly; when Owen placed his wand on his own stomach, the spell suite produced a vivid mental image of his intestines gently shifting. There was a familiar series of benign nodules along the outside of his colon, and his duodenum looked just as oddly lumpy as usual. But when Owen returned the wand to the patient and focused the diagnosis convivium back on him, there was not a single cyst, scar, or other irregularity. And no matter where he looked, it was the same. The patient's body was as perfect as the illustrations of a medical textbook, and that was simply strange… especially since he was complaining of general aches and pains. They didn't appear to have any irregularities at all, much less a condition that would cause any suffering.

Owen considered the possibilities. It was conceivable that the patient just happened to be a bizarrely perfect specimen who had never had any sort of trauma, despite what appeared to be at least six decades of life. That was very unlikely, though. It was also possible that the man - Mr. Khan, by his intake parchment - had been seriously hurt and had received magical healing to most of his body. But that usually left traces; Skele-grow, for example, left bones with a distinctive (if harmless) spiral pattern of nonlamellar and lamellar.

The most likely explanation that occurred to Owen, though, was also the most alarming one: that the patient had been one of the first wizards to receive rejuvenation. If that were the case, it might explain the fact that his appearance was still middle-aged. In the earliest days of the Tower, Owen had heard that they'd sometimes omitted the cosmetic restoration. If the patient had been one of the first to be rejuvenated, it might also explain why they didn't have any treatment records for him. Many of those early records had been lost in some sort of fire, years ago.

It was also possible that Mr. Khan had been rejuvenated more recently, and had been granted special exemption from the cosmetic restoration. That was very rare, however, and it wouldn't explain the lack of a Tower record for the procedure.

At this point, Owen really couldn't go any further without waking up the patient and eliminating some of these possibilities. He was beginning to be worried about time, though. The clock said that he had only about fifty minutes before Harry's next pass through the clinic. The Tower enchantments required Harry's express touch before any healing transfiguration would become permanent, so if Owen didn't get this solved and the healing done quickly, he'd be stuck with Mr. Khan until the next scheduled pass - three more hours.

Did he need an auror when he woke up the patient? Probably not. Mr. Khan wasn't important or powerful enough to have any sort of file, and he didn't have his wand, like every patient. Plus, Owen wasn't a bigot or anything, but he hadn't been able to help noticing that Mr. Khan's wand was so battered-looking that it must be second-hand (or even third-hand).

Still, protocol was protocol. The security at the Tower was incredibly complex, considering the difficulties of admitting and treating powerful strangers from all over the world, but it wasn't infallible.

Owen stuck his head out of the screened-off examination cubicle, pushing aside the curtain. He called down the hall, "Wake-up here, need an auror!"

A bored-looking auror came striding on down past the rows of cubicles, nodding. "Anything I need to know?"

"He's a bit funny in his guts. I think he might have been an earlier rejuvenation - back before the Tower moved to this facility. I've heard about them… you were here then, right?" said Owen, handing over the sparse file that they'd started on Mr. Khan in the Receiving Room.

"No," said Auror Madagascar. "I was stationed somewhere else, then. But I heard the same thing." He flipped open the file, but it had virtually no information beyond a few uninteresting personal details like place of origin (the Vedic Kingdom, though he was admitted via the Godric's Hollow pole), number of siblings (seven, all deceased), and the like. Madagascar shrugged. "Wake him up."

Owen did so, after making sure a privacy spell was on and that Madagascar had raised the basic safety wards. That was just standard - some people didn't react well to waking up from the stunning effect of the Safety Stick or Safety Poles. A majority awoke as calmly though they were waking from a nap, but some people become disoriented and alarmed.

The patient opened his eyes, gently, and blinked a moment. He tilted his head and took in the healer and the auror, then glanced around. A flicker of some expression passed over his face - not the usual fear or uncertainty or pain, but instead a shadow of apprehension. But it was gone as quickly as it came.

"Am I all right?" Mr. Khan asked. He closed his eyes for a moment, and let out a long sigh.

Owen smiled. "You're fine, Mr. Khan. You're in the John Snow Center for Medicine. In the Tower. My name is Wilifred Owen. I'm a healer here. This is Harry Madagascar - he works here with me. We wanted to ask you a few questions, but if you need a moment to get oriented, take your time."

The patient sat up, nodding. "May I stand up? Is that all right?" he asked, mildly.

"No, sorry," said Owen. "It might make you dizzy. Just give it a minute." He stepped back next to Madagascar, but the auror waved him to the side. Clear line of fire, thought Owen, and restrained the temptation to roll his eyes.

Mr. Khan shifted where he lay on the cot, moving carefully. He was wearing very simple brown robes, worn through in spots with use.

"You told the healer you'd been feeling pains?" asked Owen.

"Yes," said Mr. Khan. He turned to look at Owen, and then at Madagascar, and then jerked his head downward, sharply, cringing. He reached to his chest with one hand, and grimaced. "Again."

Owen frowned, shaking his head. "I don't know what could be causing that... " He stepped forward again, lifting his wand. Behind him, he heard Madagascar move to one side - finding a good angle for a clear view. "Tell me, have you been here before, sir?" Owen set his wand on Mr. Khan's chest, and stared at the blank white wall of the cubicle as he focused on the view of the patient's organs afforded by the convivium. Everything looked pristine.

Mr. Khan murmured something, quietly. Owen lowered his head a little. "Pardon?" The patient reached up and gently touched Owen's elbow, and repeated himself in a whisper.

"I said, Egeustimentis."

And Owen went away for a while, and he and Mr. Khan were alone for a time in some narrow space. It seemed like hours, though it was only seconds.

While they were there, Mr. Khan made some changes to the way Owen thought about things. Owen distantly observed the process, and found it interesting. It was as though Mr. Khan were simultaneously very large and very small, peering down from a great height at Owen's mind - even as he moved within it. Owen's mind, Owen noted, was a ceaselessly sliding mass of a thousand thousand thin layers of slippery jelly, undulating and quivering as they slithered into and over each other. Simultaneously, it was an intricate tracery of vinegar-smelling lights that touched each other and flared bright and faded. And it was a stabbing prickery of needles stabbing in and out of dark shapes that quietly sighed. And Owen's mind was other things as well, as need be.

Mr. Khan moved things and explained to Owen that he needed Owen to be a slightly different sort of person. Not very different, but different enough to help Mr. Khan. After it had all been explained, it made sense. They spoke for a long while. All the while that they spoke, Mr. Khan was moving jelly/lights/needles/switches/teeth. And at the end of this time, Owen had been both persuaded and altered, and he wasn't sure where the persuasion had ended and alteration had begun, or if there was even a division between the two, or if there was even a difference.

Owen agreed it was probably best that Mr. Khan set up a way for him to forget about the whole thing. Mr. Khan set up a pressure in Owen's mind, waiting to be released by a command word - thoughts and impulses forced out of place and bent into tension, ready to spring out along a chosen path. He would leave only the one pressure, Mr. Khan explained, because he didn't want to hurt Owen. When Mr. Khan triggered the release of that pressure, Owen's mind would snap back into place along that chosen path… and Owen would forget that he'd ever treated Mr. Khan, helped Mr. Khan, and even that he'd ever known this Mr. Khan existed. By that time, everything would be all over.

Everything would be all right, Mr. Khan said. They'd sort everything out.

And then

"Wilifred, you all right?" asked Madagascar.

Owen turned around. "Sure. Just can't figure this out." He shrugged, and turned away from the patient. "Mr. Khan, just relax for a moment. Let me get another healer to consult. We have some excellent people on staff here at the Tower, and we'll do what it takes to sort everything out."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Begin by asking students to consider how a rumor might spread among a population. Suppose on Day 1 a single person tells someone else a rumor, and suppose that on every subsequent day, each person who knows the rumor tells exactly one other person the rumor. Have students ponder, discuss and answer questions like: "How many days until 50 people have heard the rumor? 100 people? The whole school? The whole country?"

In the situation with the rumor, the number of people who have heard the rumor doubles every day; this is because, each day, every person who knows the rumor tells it to a new person. In other words, there is a 100 percent transmission rate: 100 percent of those who know the rumor spread it to someone else. A transmission rate this high means that the number of people who know the rumor will grow very quickly. In fact, in this simplified exponential model, one person could spread the rumor to the entire population of the United States in less than a month!

"Exponential Outbreaks: The Mathematics of Epidemics," Patrick Honner

Chapter 49: Commentarii de Bello

CRAD: Now you understand that these are the deadly years for wizards. [Throws KARL's bloodstained necklace onto the ground in front of ERIN.] The metamorphosis of the world has begun… no more the plaything of the tall and beautiful!

[The remaining ATTENDANT takes notice, abandoning the corpse of his friend. He jumps up and down with joy, yelling and grimacing with savagery and waving his torch.]

ERIN: The Lady O'Bruinan will save me.

CRAD: [Strikes her across the face with a bloody hand. It leaves a mark of blood across her face. The blood is a symbol of violence.] Fool! I have destroyed Sontag, and should the aged Lady appear in my arena, here, I shall show her a taste of armageddon… as I did your mad lover!

[EXSES enters from stage right with a clamour of thunder, clad all in gold. In her left hand is a wand, and in her right is a spear.]

EXSES: I am come! I have seen the terrors you have wrought upon my people of Sontag, and I have brought my vengeance!

[CRAD and ATTENDANT cower back from EXSES. CRAD seizes ATTENDANT and pushes him at EXSES. She strikes him down with her spear, and there is another clamour of thunder.]

ERIN: My Lady! I never lost hope!

CRAD: No, no, no!

[CRAD wails and strips off his necklace of wizard teeth, flinging it to the ground. It lands next to KARL's necklace.]

EXSES: Yes! I will bring the goblins low for their crimes, a deserved punishment for their deeds! [She raises her spear, holding it high.] Thus do I condemn them: let them scrape in metal and toil in tin! Let them fear to raise their heads, lest those heads be struck from their shoulders! The blood of Sontag demands it - and let all know their just reward for such bloody deeds as have been done this day!

[CRAD collapses, wailing. ERIN inclines her head, and leans down to pick up KARL's necklace. She pauses, and then brings her delicate foot down upon CRAD's necklace, ruining it. ALL exit.]

[The stage darkens, and a spotlight focuses on CRAD's necklace. It is a symbol of hubris.]

- "The Last Days of Exses O'Bruinan," by S. Leigh, as staged in the 1979 London production.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 19th, 1999

The same day

"There," said Meldh, lifting his hand from Harry's wrist. "Think back, and see if you can remember anything."

Harry shut his eyes, standing silently. It was very quiet in the blank span of corridor where they stood, near the rear of the Tower - there were no distractions.

After a while, Harry opened his eyes again. "No, sir. I can't remember anything about where Voldemort might be. And I seem to remember all about the Tower departments, otherwise. There's no obvious gap that might provide a clue." He paused. "Thank you, sir, for leaving me with everything else."

"It seemed cruel to take all of that away from you," said Meldh, nodding.

"Thank you, sir," said Harry, smiling. His smile faded, though, as he said hesitantly, "Sir, before we go back to the others, I think we should talk about your succession to my place - at least in the broad strokes, so I can begin thinking about how to help. I know that you believe the Lethe Touch to be infallible, but there's no reason to risk it. It's basic information hygiene."

Meldh waved a hand, dismissively. "There is no concern. I will take your identity and you will become a new person. We will alter the trajectory you have chosen for the world, using the tools you have put at my command."

"No, sir," Harry said, shaking his head. "There are serious problems there. For one, the new terminal values you've given us are too…" He fumbled for words. "There's too much internal conflict, sir. It shows on our faces, and it will lead to strange behavior at some point. It will be like an Asimov story with the Three Laws… outside observers will be able to deduce from aberrant behavior that there are new underlying rules. Many people are very loyal to me, but no one is absolutely loyal, to the extent where my will and wishes are their most important goals."

"We have taken dozens of your allies here, but I have set up a pressure within them," Meldh said. "They are enchanted in the same fashion as yourself, but there is a capacity for release by recasting the Touch and adding -"

"No!" said Harry, abruptly, holding up his hand. "I don't need to know! Information hygiene." Sheepishly, he lowered his hand, smiling a bit. "Sorry, sir, but there's no need to tell me the command word… it can't possibly help. Yes, you can trust me absolutely, right now, but what if I were to get free somehow? The best weapon you'd have in that situation would be your control of almost all of my closest friends… I'm going to be substantially weaker if any attack on you risks killing Draco or Moody - or even if your death would just leave all of my friends as your servants, forever."

"Do not worry, Mr. Potter," said Meldh, kindly. "There is no risk that you will go free. No one has ever defeated the Lethe Touch by sheer willpower, and there is no spell known to you or any of your allies that could dispel the enchantment. We now possess the only real trust that can ever exist between two people."

"What about my Unbreakable Vow, sir?" asked Harry. "It's an obvious problem… what if you ask me to do something that might destroy the world?"

Meldh folded his hands in his sleeves. "You will not be able to comply, of course. But the results would be the same if I asked you to fetch me a Lethifold's smile- you could not do it, but neither would the Touch fail. I spent some time examining your mind, Mr. Potter, and I assure you that there is no power known to you that poses a threat to me."

Harry fell silent, and leaned back against the wall of the corridor. Meldh waited, patiently. After a time, Harry spoke up again, saying, "When I think about possible contingency plans for something like this, it seems obvious I would have prepared something and stored the memory in a Pensieve, or just erased it with such care as to leave no traces. Of course, if I thought of a contingency once, I should be able to think of it again, so it would also be necessary to erase the memories that led me to the plan in the first place."

"Then we're no better off for the wondering," said Meldh, chuckling mildly. "You cannot worry or defend against the unknown, since it can take any shape. The key to great strength is defending against every known, whether it appears a threat or not, and staying hidden from the unknown."

"I disagree, sir. It's possible to plan for the unknown - you can make a path for it or put in place some contingency that embraces a host of possibilities. And I am fairly sure that I must have at least tried to do so. The way magic works, it was never an outlandish idea that someone old and powerful might show up and take offense. I knew for certain that people like Nicholas Flamel were out there. Given the long history of the world and the fact that magic was once much more powerful, it was actually more likely than not that there would be some immortals out there." Harry shrugged. "I should have perhaps even foreseen you yourself, sir. The inventor of the Horcrux spell? It seems obvious, in retrospect. Maybe I did foresee it, actually."

Meldh looked amused. "You and Voldemort share the same opinion of your abilities. You will forgive me for saying that I do not, Mr. Potter. My victory was not a difficult one, and cost scarcely even a pawn's worth of trouble."

Harry shrugged. "That seems suspicious to me, sir." Then he opened his mouth, as though to go on speaking, but made no sound. He grimaced and shook his head, accidentally rapping it against the wall and wincing.

Meldh watched him, and replied to the unaskable question. "No, Mr. Potter," he said gently. "I do not think it is necessary to kill you now, out of fear of some possible trap you've laid. Rather, I will need your help.

"Once I take my place as the new Mr. Potter, you will be by my side in some altered shape, as an adjunct and adviser," he said. "I will release all others - they will continue to serve 'you,' and the Tower will move in a new direction to decisively end magic. Your Muggle knowledge will be turned to proper ends… without your foolishness." He chortled, amiably. "Some things can even be done immediately, to help stave off the end of the world and its people. There is at least one new ritual we may enact, based on your knowledge. To think what you would have let go to waste - for the sake of some distant bits of fire!"

Harry looked at the ground, his face uncomfortable. "Sir, I considered it to be immoral, especially when there are alternatives that don't increase entropy in the universe so much. And…" Harry fumbled over his words clumsily, as though many ideas were fighting for expression at the same time. "And many stars have the possibility of life, either now or in the future, and that risk is so apocalyptically bad that it overwhelms any benefit to an individual life here, and when we reach the second type on the Kardashev scale we'll then be confronted with a loss of useful energy on a scale of… of… well, I don't even know how to make a comparison! Obviously it would be like sacrificing our own Sun, but… well, it would be like a wiping out every scrap of phoenix flame that ever existed and could ever exist, all to save one person."

His voice wasn't rising, but it was filled with strange tension, as though he weren't arguing with Meldh, but were arguing with himself. He kept talking, though, fumbling through in a rush. "And we might not even need to do that! The Advancement Agency has made amazing strides in only a few years. With reconfiguring parts alone, they'll raise life expectancy. The prostate, the heart, the optic nerve, the retina, the spine, the knees, the teeth, the heart… there are all sorts of design fixes that will reduce the chances of morbidity. Making them a part of the standard rejuvenation and putting in greater security - even perhaps with the aid of the Touch, sir - will put us well ahead of the curve on a new Moore's Law of lifespan."

"No," said Meldh, flatly... that short and curt blade of a word. "We will not wait, not when the new ritual will be so simple to devise - with some little study of your Muggle knowledge about the stars. Not one more minute, as the saying goes."

Harry choked a little in his throat, then hung his head, and made no reply. He stared at the floor.

"To think I feared to come here, considering it an unwarranted risk," marveled Meldh, shaking his head and gesturing down the corridor. "Come. We must arrange for the death of the fallen bishop, Bellatrix Black, and take what actions are necessary to suborn the absentee goblins, and set them, too, on the correct path." He smiled at the thought. "Then I have some preparations to make before I step outside of this Tower to consult with my allies."

Harry began moving obediently, and they began walking back to the meeting room. Meldh glanced at him, and spoke, his voice kind. "The new immortals of the world, the ones that we choose to aid us in our cause, will have cause to praise my risk and your losses, Mr. Potter. There are endless stars in the sky… more than enough for every witch and wizard we might select."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

On the shores of the lake of teeth, where the black hills end, Tír inna n-Óc

May 19th, 1999

Later that day

Whispering teeth.

Fractal shadows.

Desolation.

"You have succeeded… well done," said the third figure - Nell. Her congratulations were light and pleasant, but none the more convincing for that.

"Thank you," said the first figure - Meldh. "We have swept the board."

The second figure said nothing, only watching them both.

"You have Touched the boy-king… will you leave him in charge?" asked Nell.

"No," said Meldh. "I will take his shape and his identity. He has built a formidable apparatus, and I think that few threats now exist that could stand against it."

"You do not think that you might be, perhaps overconfident? Is your control already so sure?" asked Nell.

Meldh paused and did not reply for a time. The second figure, silent still, turned a face of slithering shadow to regard him, watching intently.

"My pride prompts me to deny you, but mirgo que n'a qu'un trpu est bientôt prise… yes, perhaps you are correct," said Meldh, finally. "Mr. Potter himself said as much to me, not an hour ago. I had thought to use the goblins as an excuse to change policy, but even a goblin army may not be sufficient to rouse enough alarm and stem the suspicion of his allies."

"If you require further assistance, then you shall have it," said the second figure.

"We are gambling a great deal," agreed Nell. "You shall have every support we can offer."

"Then so be it," said Meldh. "I will not turn away one ounce of assistance. And for my part, I find that I will not have need of the Stone of the Long Song, so long as you would still be willing to lend its power on occasion, Madame."

"Of course," said Nell, and the shadows writhed in some distant imitation of a smile.

"No," said the second figure. "That shall not be sufficient. Now is not the time for conservative policies. We must take this opportunity to act. Our hand is in play - we will make it a fist. Now is the time to act. We will do as we have not done in many years. Sontag once thrived and threatened, rich on the concentrated lore of the Peverells, and made a perfect plum to be plucked. You fear preparations against you? Let us swamp them in violence."

"Is that not hasty?" asked Meldh.

Even Nell seemed startled by the proposition. "I will commit all to the enterprise, if necessary, but I think -"

"We will raise mighty forces. Armies. I will act with all puissance at my command," said the second figure, as though the others had not spoken. "Not only the goblins, strong with the restored knowledge of their ancient will-work. Also the visc and lejis of this place will take breath again, driven by the gaunt-horrors. I will break the cycle of the unsleeping, and bring forth your long-vanished terrasque and basilisks. Muggles in their hordes will take the eaters on themselves. They will march, we will sacrifice many… and take the opportunity to wipe away the magics of London, Boston, and Hangzhou."

"I am not sure that…" said Nell, hesitantly. "We have not acted on such a scale since…" She shook her head, darkness swirling. "Never. This is audacity truly worthy of Merlin. And unspeakably risky."

"Thus shall it be, Perenelle du Marais," said the second figure. He did not wait for a reply, but turned to Meldh, and stated, "Thus shall it be, Heraclius Hero. We will sweep the world with discord and blood, crush a thousand artifacts and burn a thousand scrolls, and raise such fear as has never been seen."

There was a desperately long pause, when none of them moved. They were not as such to act in haste, despite the brutal decisiveness they could bring to such conversations. All Three waited, patiently, for the others to come to terms with the new shape of the world to come.

Tentatively, Nell said, "In the face of such a threat, those remaining wizards will unite behind the Tower. Behind you." She looked back at Meldh.

"Behind us," corrected Meldh, mildly. "And I think we will have no resistance, then, in a push to redouble the Statute of Secrecy's strictures and limit the scope and growth of magic. The plan will need further thought to arrange all of the pieces, but there will be resources to spare, now that I have mastered the Tower."

"You disposed of Bellatrix Black and Voldemort," said the second figure - a question that was not really a question.

"I have made arrangements for the death of the Black woman, but there are... complications with Voldemort. I actually have much to say to you about Horcruxes at another time. I have sealed Voldemort away, however, and erased all memory of his hiding place. It will suffice, I think," said Meldh.

"Kill Potter, as well," said the second figure. "Whatever his lore, the risk is too great. And we need no more complications."

"As you wish, although the odd patterns of his brain have been fruitful," said Meldh, untroubled. "I will strip his mind of what else might be gleaned, and then end him." He inclined his head, gently. "I will send signal for our next meeting presently, after concluding such matters. We will plan for our war and arrange our pieces."

"Yes," said the second figure. "Consider, each of you, the utmost of your might. We will spare no energy or lore in the conflict to come. Victory must be certain for us to take such a risk."

All three departed, each their separate ways.

Whispering teeth.

Fractal shadows.

Desolation.

Tír inna n-Óc endured.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 19th, 1999

The afternoon of the same day

Upon his return to the Tower, Meldh appeared tired. He walked with heavy feet out of the annex next to the Receiving Room, where he'd performed the ritual. His fingers were still bloody, wet with the necessary components of a trip to the land of the Unseelie.

For a moment, the assured and calm wizard was gone. He looked the same… dusky skin, dark eyes, broad lips. But he looked weary and battered, and it was enough to bring a worried Moody to his side with gruff but concerned questions. Meldh waved away the Tower's spymaster, and stepped through the golden oval of the Tower entrance. Harry waited just inside, frowning and unhappy, accompanied by Diggory. Both young men looked immensely relieved to see their master alive, though their worried glances at each other showed their distress at his state.

"Sir, we're holding some people in Material Methods," said Diggory, speaking first. He and Harry walked along with Meldh down the corridor, slowly, towards the clinic. "Madame Bones, Percy Weasley, Councilor Reg Hig, and seven aurors reporting for their normal shifts. All stunned and waiting for you. And there is regular Tower business… people to heal."

"Good, good," said Meldh, slowly. "Harry must go and attend to matters. But I must rest. Keep the prisoners stunned and secured for now. Anything else?"

"Ackle and Curd have both sent away emissaries from Minister N'goma," said Harry, studying Meldh closely. "And Hermione Granger sent a message to let me know she'd be here this evening. All is well with your allies?"

"Fine," said Meldh. He sighed, heavily. "Ah, but… forgive my weariness, but there is such violence in the offing, Mr. Potter. I confess that I did not anticipate it, and the very thought makes me ache for my garden and my home and my temple. I fear I will not see them for a great while, and that is not a discomfort I have needed to endure for many years." He shook his head. Harry touched him on the arm, reassuringly, and the older wizard glanced down at the hand and smiled a small smile.

"Sir, I'm sorry, but we should prepare for Granger," said Diggory, breaking in on the moment. "She is resourceful and her Returned are insane."

"I am too tired, young man," said Meldh. "Mr. Potter, make plans accordingly." He sighed again. "I must rest. There will be war soon, and the world will shake because of it. A great and fearsome god calls for blood. That is not something I have seen for centuries. I must rest and think."

Harry took hold of Diggory's arm, restraining him, and they stopped in their tracks. Meldh continued on, moving slowly. He vanished from sight into the clinic.

"This is for the best, Cedric," said Harry. "I'm not sure that he would be able to appreciate the threat that Hermione could present, but we do. Let's make a plan."

Chapter 55: Antepenultimate

Receiving Room, Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry

Now

This was a defining moment. Gregor Nimue knew that. Everyone was leaning on him to break protocol, and he was standing fast.

It was a shining moment, and it was a long time coming.

Considering his experience and skill, he should have been Terminus of the Receiving Room a long time ago. He had twice the lore and three times the brains of any other Tower Auror, and it was practically a crime that he'd been sidelined for so long. He'd spent years chafing under the command of inferiors, stuck on chizpurfle duty or some other nonsense - all because he'd had the bad luck to be on the Azkaban rotation on the night that veela-giant crossbreed dropped out of the sky on a phoenix and knocked the place flat. An entire detail of good and experienced aurors were dropped down to sentinel duty the very next week, and Gregor had been taking orders from idiots ever since.

And what was even better, the very week he was finally back in a decent posting - Terminus, a job with some real heft - was one more in a series of crazy weeks. The blastbombings in Diagon and Tidewater, the start of the Treaty of Independence, an attack by some worthless students with a hundred doxies, the One-Day War, the attack by Bellatrix Black, and now some sort of takeover attempt at the same time that everywhere else in the world was going to pot. Too many people had been burnt out or hurt or both, and so good old Gregor's career was finally finally heading back to the top.

There were protocols for things like this, for powerful wizards who might manage to evade security and put people under their control, and Gregor followed them to the letter. As soon as McGonagall sent word about a message she'd received, he'd given the signal. They'd rolled the shield and locked down the Tower, and no power on the planet could make him open it until he was satisfied that the Tower hadn't been compromised. That was the rule. That was his role. The Terminus was the first and last guard against attack - from either side of the Tower's golden doorway.

Injured wizards, witches, and Squibs arrived and were sent to nearby chambers in Hogwarts, stabilized as well as could be done by a skeleton crew of the less-skilled aurors. Gregor kept his best stationed near him - and that necessity became even more apparent when entire squads of foreign Hit Wizards and auror teams arrived. Some of the most famous battle wizards and duelists in the world appeared on the summons of the Headmistress of Hogwarts and the Tower and some American muckitymuck. The Boston Brahmins didn't even arrive stunned; they spun into existence fully awake and aware, which meant that they'd used an illegal Tower portkey that didn't have the security enchantments. Gregor'd need to report that - earn another point in his favor.

As the story became clear, he'd let out messages and he'd let in a handful of runners and representatives, but still: no one left. A strange and powerful wizard had tried to take over and failed… fine, a good story, but would it be any different if a strange and powerful wizard had tried to take over and succeeded? Lockdown remained in place.

Even when he heard that the Ministry itself was under attack, and that the dregs of the aurors who'd been sitting idle in Hogsmeade or some other Knut-ante place had spotted a crowd of Muggles, Gregor knew better. He did his job. Americans, Russians, Koreans, and seemingly a thousand angry British including all the most powerful people he knew were all putting pressure on him, and he did his job.

It was a shining moment, and it was a long time coming.

"Lift the lockdown, Nimue!" shouted Auror Hedley Kwannon, "It's been nearly thirty minutes! Don't you know what's happening out there?"

"Don't you know what protocol is, Kwannon?" snapped back Gregor. He was off to the side of the door, out of its line of sight, but he knew she must be fuming. One more bit of consolation: knowing one of the Tower's pets was being treated like everyone else for a change. He'd already heard that another one of them, that flinty Kraeme woman, had been badly injured.

If he found out that Pirrip had fallen off his broom and broken his neck while mooning after the Diggory brat-in-charge, then Gregor's day would be complete.

"You don't have to let them out, but you're going to let us in," rumbled the biggest of the three Chinese wizards who'd been pestering Gregor for the last twenty minutes. He didn't approach too closely - not with fifty Tower Aurors on alert, wands ready for conflict (from either direction).

And if this whole thing were a ploy and it was you lot behind it, wouldn't that just what you'd bloody want? Gregor thought. Although all things considered, it's still most likely that Mad-Eye is the one behind the whole thing, somehow. He smiled a mocking smile right at the Chinese Hit Wizard, although all he said was a courteous, "No, sir. Sorry."

Two of the Tower Aurors exchanged an uneasy glance, but didn't lower their wands. Gregor noticed, and noted who it was. Unreliable.

"You have every confirmation code and you have Patronus verification from five of us," shouted Kwannon. "That is the protocol!"

"I still have discretion," called back Gregor, "and I haven't seen anything th-"

"No. That's enough now, Nimue," said a new voice, with a tone of command that was leather-tough. Madame Bones. His former leader in the DMLE, before she leapt up four or five rungs to Supreme Mugwump and Chief Warlock. "If the Tower has been compromised somehow, then it's past proof and past solution. You'll end the lockdown right now. Innocent people are dying."

Gregor considered. She's right. And I've made my name. If this was a Mad-Eye test, then I've made my reputation. And if not… well, this will probably still be good for me.

"Fine," he said. And before he'd even said a word more, tense aurors were lowering their wands with a sigh. The sharper ones were in immediate, rapid motion: heading to the bunched-up crowd sorting itself into a queue to get through the narrow Tower entrance, or going the opposite way to the rest of Hogwarts.

Gregor turned to one of the aurors in charge of scanning. "We'll need to sort out who is available for assistance outside…"

But his voice trailed off as he watched a ripple shift through the witches and wizards around the Tower entrance. They cleared a path.

Hermione Granger strode through the path, out of the Tower. Her step was brisk and her face was tight. She had her wand out - and her other hand looked oddly pinkish, as though it had been sunburnt.

This was a shining moment, Gregor knew. The same person who'd broken his career would now reward him for keeping to the rules at the moment when it had been the most difficult, and when there'd been every reason to give in.

He stepped forward to meet her. "Madame Granger, I hope you -"

The Goddess didn't even slow down. She walked forward like he wasn't there, and her shoulder swept Gregor aside like a curtain of iron as he tried to hastily get out of her way. He staggered backwards, met an obstacle behind one heel, and lost his balance. He landed on his rear, awkwardly.

No one took much notice - too many things going on - except for the few people near him (including the bass-voiced Chinese auror, who had stuck a foot out behind Gregor).

He watched the Goddess sweep through the room and out, and then she was gone, two witches right on her heels and dozens of aurors and others rushing in their wake, following her with grim faces. Almost before she'd vanished from the room, though, there came someone else - the only person, perhaps, who could draw even more attention than Hermione Granger.

"Cedric, take anyone not vital who can cast a Patronus," said Harry Potter, walking briskly up to the Tower entrance. He was wearing simple garments - trousers and a vest beneath plain robes. "Communications are now the most important thing you can do. We can bring reinforcements here quickly with Safety Sticks, but moving them after that is harder, so -"

"So we need to know exactly what threats are where, and now," finished the Chief Auror and Head of the DMLE, walking alongside and just behind the Tower.

Potter nodded, sharply, and then a look of uncertainty flashed over his face. His stride broke, and he halted. He was standing inside the golden oval of the Tower, looking out at the Receiving Room.

Gregor stood up and turned to the side, trying to follow the Tower's gaze. He glanced around the room. Nothing unusual now but a relatively plain stone room with the usual decorations - the tables of Dark Detectors, the shelves of chizpurfles, the few pieces of other furniture. It was crowded with combat-ready wizards, and injured people were arriving at a steady rate, but there were no apparent threats. There didn't seem to be any reason for the Tower to hesitate… was he nervous about any remaining danger? That didn't seem possible, considering how often Potter had been in serious peril. Just a couple of months ago, he'd nearly been blown up in Diagon, and just today there'd been an attempt to cast some sort of Imperius Curse on him. He is just a child, after all. A child who's taken charge of the world, but a child. With a stupid haircut, too.

Madame Bones stepped up from somewhere behind Potter. She said something too soft to hear, and then put a hand on his back and gave him a gentle but firm push forward. The Tower stepped forward and out of his eponymous facility, and took a deep breath. He closed his eyes. He looked pale.

Then the moment passed, and Potter was turning to yet another person walking with him - a blonde-haired witch - and telling her to get everything ready, and to remember everything he'd said.

Nimue found himself pushed to the side by several aurors, and then again by a scornful blonde wizard - was that Draco Malfoy?

"You're the one who was Terminus and kept us here? Well done, you fool," sneered Malfoy. He didn't stop, but walked on.

Things weren't supposed to go this way. This wasn't fair.

"Good going -" "- you complete bollocks," said a pair of red-haired Hit Wizards with bizarre cheer as they walked by.

"I followed protocol!" Gregor protested. "I just did what I was supposed to do!"

"You did the right thing, Nimue," Bones said, staring at him. Her voice was cool. "What an odd time to begin such behavior." Then she turned away from him, too, looking at another auror who'd emerged from the Tower behind her. "Madagascar, you're in charge here. Get everyone moving. Get everyone you can outside, to help Granger."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Harry stepped to one side of the Mirror, which sat as impossibly solid as ever, embedded in the masonry of Hogwarts as though it were a piece of interior decoration: a fancy accessory to the castle, rather than the most potent magical device known to still exist.

The Cup of Midnight might have been stronger, once. They hadn't been able to find much information about that ancient device, which came to them now only in scant shards, but Hopkirk's best guess was that the Cup had been the method by which the Interdict was enacted. Around the same time, the Cup was broken and Merlin lost his life and his time. Occam's Razor suggested that all three events were perhaps related, although contradictory legends told many different stories.

There was a time when Harry couldn't have imagined making a decision like that… a decision on behalf of humanity. On some level, of course, every little decision tasted of eternity. But to consciously choose a path for the future of mankind, to make a gamble in the name of human intelligence… well, that had been the fate of a precious few.

And now Harry was going to join them.

The scramble he'd inspired with his order to evacuate the Tower had caused something like a panic, especially when added to the chaos of the attacks and the tension of the lockdown. Healers and officials and researchers and diplomats and friends first tried to enter the Tower, only to find themselves turned back: Moody stood just inside, where the two main corridors split off, and roared orders. There were suddenly too few aurors, where only minutes ago there had been far too many, but those remaining worked to clear out the entire facility. The Records Room was emptied, desperate researchers were permitted a single trip to retrieve anything they needed from the departments, and every last straggler was forced out.

At least one researcher fought back, recklessly, after his request to return and retrieve his personal Pensieve was denied. He was stunned and removed. But while there was a great deal of complaining and even some tears, most accepted the warnings without such a drastic reaction.

Probably a lot of them don't really believe that anything is going to happen to the Tower - they expect to be able to come back after the alarm dies down. They don't know that it's going to… well, I don't even know what will happen to it. Harry stared at the Mirror. It stood immobile: a fixed point of supernal obdurance. If it were possible to truly conceptualize the supermassive black hole at the center of the galaxy, this is what he imagined it would be like: potent beyond reckoning and more solid than existence. Not that he'd ever had occasion to see a black hole. His mouth twisted in a wry smile.

Harry looked at the golden circle of the Mirror.

He had to do this.

He had to make himself do this.

Kwannon kept most people from bothering him with their urgent pleas for assistance or exceptions. She blocked their path physically - or with wards when necessary - to keep his corner of the Receiving Room empty, off to the side of the Tower entrance. He was startled, then, when he felt a hand tug on his sleeve. He turned to find Auror Pirrip, looking sweaty but grinning broadly. He glanced over Pip's shoulder at Kwannon, but she was smiling, too.

"Yes?" Harry asked.

"Mr. Potter! You're never going to believe… the goblins, sir!"

Harry felt a sick feeling in his gut. He knew what this was about, and celebrations were not in order.

Every round for countless rounds, wizards defected instead of cooperating. What did we expect would happen?

"Let me guess: they attacked, but we won." He sighed, and turned away, to stare at the Mirror again. "It's been building for weeks, now. Well, no, it's been building for years. And the frustrating thing is that it's impossible to even blame them, or feel happy about winning. It doesn't change anything, and it actually makes things worse in a lot of ways. I don't think moral culpability is heritable, but centuries of structural inequality and outright oppression can't be ignored for -"

"Sir!" interrupted Pip, putting a hand on Harry's arm again, his urgency overriding his patience and respect. "They're fighting with us - fighting for us! Everywhere! They've saved the Cypriot Hold and Beauxbatons. They've saved Godric's Hollow!"

That's… my god, that's better than we deserve. That's better than any of us deserve.

It was amazing. It was a touch of grace. It was a shining moment.

Harry felt his eyes fill with tears, and a smile spread helplessly across his face.

"Everything is going to hell, Mr. Potter," said Pip, smiling back, "but we're not alone."

"Sir!" said Kwannon, behind Pip, one arm raised to stop a panic-faced auror. "They need you! The Goddess is out there, but…"

Things must be bad and getting worse. And it was time. The Receiving Room was almost empty, except for healers. Almost everyone who could fight was gone, and everyone else was trying to secure themselves away with the students - down in the dungeons, he supposed.

Moody and a last team of aurors emerged, floating two stunned stragglers along in their wake. Moody gave Harry a heavy nod, his face sadder than Harry had seen it since Albus Dumbledore had been lost beyond time.

"Yes," said Harry to Kwannon. He turned back to the Mirror. And now he felt ready. "I can do this. But then we're going to the library, not outside. Let Hermione do her thing - I'll do mine."

He stepped in front of the entrance to the Tower - the pocket world of his creation. The world of his volition. He felt for his wand.

"Muffliato," he cast.

"Noitilov," he said. And the surface of the Mirror changed, and just like that, the John Snow Center for Medicine and the Tower School of Doubt was gone.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

What a waste, Hermione thought, grimly. She pulled her broom up and away from the entrance to the castle. What a heroic waste.

The defenders could have done any number of things differently, if they'd been willing to rethink their situation or defy convention. They'd fought like they'd always fought: with incredible bravery but limited creativity.

The castle fell away behind her as she flew upwards, set on the steep hill that edged upon the waters of the Black Lake. The staircase down the hill was gone, bitten away halfway down by the teeth of rubble that were strewn at the bottom. The Hogwarts grounds, normally a gentle rise of grass from the main gates from Hogsmeade all the way to the castle, were a torn mass of detritus and the dead, still intermingled with the scrambling mass of people who were pouring in from Hogsmeade in an endless stream. There were thousands, perhaps tens of thousands. Perhaps more. She'd heard that a million people could fit within Tiananmen Square in Beijing, and tried to estimate based on that. Considering all the chaos and the impassable areas… how many people was she looking at?

She picked a portion of ground and did a quick Fermi estimate, counting the living and dead on that portion and extrapolating to the whole field.

Ninety thousand.

There was a dull thump from far below, and a line of silver smoke arrowed through the air. Hermione watched as it arced gently downward, and hit the wrought-iron apex atop the Hufflepuff greenhouse. The missile exploded. It actually did little damage, except for a multitude of broken glass. But she could see rifles and numerous simpler weapons among the crowd, too.

Well, and she couldn't believe she was thinking this and very carefully reminded herself of the moral equivalencies and the slippery slope of the thought but even so she still couldn't help but think, they are just Muggles, after all.

Hermione dipped her broom sharply, dropping dangerously quickly to the ground. She pulled up just short of the gathering aurors. Every moment, more were arriving from outside. She took a moment to assess who was there and what their known capabilities were. A formidable force, even against an army like this. And if they fought smartly, they could win this.

The Returned were there. Simon was missing. In turn, Hermione met the eyes of Urg, Charlevoix, Esther, Nikitas, Tonks, Susie, and Hyori. She didn't say anything, and neither did they. There was nothing that needed to be said.

"Brahmins and Rakshasa," she said, firmly, jabbing her finger at the elite American and Russian auror squads. "You're in the air. I want to know about everything that happens. Stay high. You're not fighting, you're keeping yourself protected. If you seen an opportunity, you tell the Jīngluò or the Three Treasures." She indicated the Chinese and Korean squads. "They're going to be working in teams, protecting each other and attacking. You'll be transfiguring things I'll tell you - dangerous things. Things you're never supposed to transfigure. But you're going to do it, because it's the only way to stay alive… and the only way to save countless other lives."

Hermione waited a moment, anticipating arguments or demands about her authority. But there were none - just confident nods and cool determination. They knew of the Goddess. They knew the reputation of the Tower.

She turned to the British forces. "Shichinin and Omega, you've the most experience fighting Muggles. Defend this ground. Half of you will be on the battlements… this is a castle, use the cover. I have more ideas - things we can do to stop this. Draco Malfoy and Alastor Moody will join you when they arrive."

Hermione wheeled her broom around and pointed at the horde below. "Thousands of people have already died, including dozens of our own. But what finally worked was a physical barrier. Use that. Hold them off, stay on the defensive. The Muggle news is full of these disappearances - we don't know how many we're facing. So your job is just to hold back the tide and keep the school safe. If you have to, retreat inside. Stay alive."

She gestured at the Returned, and they began mounting brooms.

Neville Longbottom called out to her as they rose. "And you… you're going after the source?"

"Yes," she said. "Stay alive."

And then she was flying, the Returned by her side.

Chapter 57: Ultimate

Out of the night that covers me,

Black as the pit from pole to pole,

I thank whatever gods may be

For my unconquerable soul.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

The oldest stories of magical war are full of glory and drama, wrought on stage in bright colors, and entirely unlike the reality of war.

As the vile goblins or villainous Muggles or vicious warlords swarm the field, awash in blood and villainy, the valorous Lord of Emerald calls upon an ancient ritual and the eldritch might of his Staff of the Seven Words, and sweeps aside the enemy with a single, cathartic gesture. Or if it's a different sort of tale, the good-hearted baron finds himself at a loss at the climactic moment, and only the wits of his clever majordomo suffice to trick the gloating foe into a magical vow - allowing a quibble in that vow, in the end, to bring that same foe to his ruin. Or the entire action between heroes and villains takes place in the uncertain shadow of some ancient power in the distance, and in the extremity of danger, it is only the intervention of thunder from on high that resolves the dispute in favor of Goodness.

It is not that the authors of these stories were naive or ignorant of war. In a world where scholarship and warcraft were so closely linked, it was often the winner of a battle who wrote the story of the fight. Instead, a sort of wishful thinking prevailed in these narratives.

Real war is a horror.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

All of the defenders had fallen back within Hogwarts where possible, barricading the doors on the three sides of the castle not protected by the lake. They found battlements and windows and balconies, and rained down destruction on their enemies. Outside, a smaller few engaged in different sorts of combat, fighting with growing desperation.

Oddly enough, Hogwarts was not ideally suited for battle. The school was an ancient sanctuary of arcane lore, raised up when the world was wilder and magic was mightier, but it had seldom ever been directly challenged. Despite all probability and the disruptive nature of magic, there had not been a violent change of regimes in Britain since the time of Merlin, when the Wizard's Council was established - the riotous Thing that preceded Merlin's Wizengamot and the world's Confederation. Only two villains had ever dared to attack the walls of the castle-school, and they had met swift and sure ends.

An outside observer might even say, on balance, that magical history was suspiciously tidy.

Despite these limitations, however, the castle was a formidable fortification. And once the defenders were forced to fall back within its walls, they devoted everything they could spare to preserving their strength. It was all too apparent that, should the walls of the castle fail, it would be impossible to coordinate any sort of defense. There was no motte to which they could retreat, or even any internal system of defense beyond the unreliable will of the building itself. It was a single keep, and they could not allow it to fall.

They used every force and trick and power at their command, and the powers that be had called in every ounce of strength that could be spared from other fights.

In different corners and in secret places, there were portkeys held in reserve. Portkeys to Hogsmeade, portkeys to the Receiving Room or other places in Hogwarts, and portkeys to the Forbidden Forest. Most were illegal. All that could be found, were used. Too few came, for there were other wars and other battles. At the Ministry of Magic, a heroic handful had held their ground. At Godric's Hollow, a force of goblins had met a troop of monsters in a clash that could only be called audacious. Sadder still were the calls that simply went unanswered.

It was hard to say if there was victory to be had on any front. Across the globe, much of the enemy had withdrawn or had spent itself, but even successful defenses had been ruinous. And not every defense was successful. Tidewater was cold and lifeless. The Court of Rubies was bloody and dead.

But where there were warriors to answer and means to travel, they came to Scotland. They came to the defense of Hogwarts and the Tower, the center of a global war and the thoughts of all. From America and Russia and Korea and China they came. From the Free States and the Sawad and Cyprus and Cappadocia and Norden they came. From France and Germany and Hungary and Chile and New Zealand they came. From everywhere they could, they came.

And those in a position to know gradually came to understand that there could be only two outcomes here, as day reddened into dusk and nightmare hordes met castle wall:

Either Hogwarts and wizards would survive this night.

Or they would not.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hermione could hear Edgar Erasmus screaming. At some point, the pompous wizard, engaged in aerial battle high above, had been toppled from his broom by a gust of wind. When he fell, a goblin took the opportunity to dart forward and bury a spear into the man's belly. The spear had already claimed the life of a basilisk, and now an acid venom was wracking Erasmus' wound. He howled with agony, eyes fixed wide and face red, clutching at his stomach and writhing, legs slopping and flopping in a puddle of liquified stone. Most of the hill on the east side of the castle had been made into a ruin of shattered rock and enchanted soil. There were precious few Muggles left here, but the ones that were present could barely make their way forward through the devastated terrain… and most of the ones that managed were cut down by the careless and indiscriminate attacks of giant serpents and unliving creatures of rock, who did not differentiate between friend and foe.

Edgar Erasmus was in very much the wrong place, and his screams of agony spoke of that mistake. This was no place for humans. This was a primeval battle against horrors.

And as she heard him scream, Hermione Granger found herself thinking, No time for mercy, and - to her shame - not even knowing what she meant by the thought.

Shuddering, she brought the axe in her hand down a third time, and the head of the terrasque parted from its body, falling free. Its mouth fell open to let a cloud of stinking vapor escape, and the heavy carcass dropped to the ground with a crash that knocked nearby Muggles off their feet. It landed on Hermione's right foot. She barked a short cry of pain and instinctively yanked herself free, leaving behind at least one toe but keeping her footing. She turned to look for a new target, keeping her gaze low as she scanned around herself.

Off to her left, she saw another terrasque as it savaged someone - Muggle or wizard or goblin, Hermione didn't know. The creature was almost impersonal as it rent the body in its jaws into gorey pieces, holding most of it down with one of its six legs and methodically tearing away with its sightless lion's head of black stone.

She felt rather than saw the basilisk as it struck at her, and she lunged to the side, chopping down awkwardly with the axe. The goblin silver sank into the enormous serpent - a glancing blow. The blade sliced its way free and off to the side. Before she could move, one of the basilisk's coils or possibly just another basilisk collided with her back, swatting her with the strength of a freight train.

For a moment, Hermione lost track of things.

When she found herself again, she was on her rear, sitting with her back to something hard. She jerked her gaze back down to the ground. As if fighting giant monsters wasn't hard enough you can't even look at their eyes or else you die, she thought, dazedly. Erasmus was still screaming.

She heard the clank of metal boots - it was that trio of goblins who'd just joined the fight, Hermione realized. The ones who gave her the axe. She glanced at the sound, cautiously.

One of them was in full plate armor in a medieval sort of style, while the other two only wore breastplates and helmet. The armor was silver and gold and brass; some pieces were bevelled and decorated with engravings, while others had simple and clean lines. All three carried shields. For reasons that Hermione didn't fully grasp, all the goblins now had shields, even when it made it difficult to wield their chosen weapons.

She felt stupid, as if she should understand why, but that didn't help.

A green bolt came from a defender on the battlement above her and streaked out of view down below. Hermione was glad someone on their side could still cast the spell; she hoped they had hit a basilisk. Her own wand was in its holster. The axe had proven more effective.

She reached behind herself to feel the stone of the castle. Hermione had damaged it, cracking it with the impact of her body. If it had been mundane stone, she'd have gone straight through it, she thought; the stuff of Hogwarts was barely chipped. She found the edge of a stone and pulled herself up.

As the goblins charged past her, she looked at where they were going, scanning the torn and smoking ground carefully until she could see the giant curving form of the basilisk in her near-peripheral vision. Then she launched herself forward, following the three goblins as they charged. Two of them raised their swords, and one of them set a spear-butt in the crook of his elbow. All three of them raised their voices in guttural cries she couldn't understand.

A gleam of silver - her axe. Hermione snatched it up in her golden gauntlet as she ran. She heard the basilisk hiss, and saw a flash of movement as it struck. One of the goblins hurtled past her, broken.

The other two kept charging, roaring like heroes. She joined her voice to theirs, and followed them.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Draco couldn't move his right arm. Much of it had been torn away, removed with great gouges by one of the dog-like things that were racing around, tearing apart victims. He couldn't quite get a grasp on them - they weren't properly visible, but just seemed like smears of insane nonsense. Rough impressions: Wide mouth. Sucking discs of teeth. Pale eyes of blue cataracts. Knotty muscle.

What was left of his arm hung limply from his shoulder, as though it weren't even a part of him. At least the potion had stopped the bleeding. Kept him alive. That ugly little American had given it to him. Hig. The fellow was down the hall, with Gregory Goyle. At a different window. A different defense.

They'd managed to kill three or four of the things. The Killing Curse worked, and maybe other curses as well, Draco wasn't sure. They moved so quickly, leaping around faster than anything could move, faster than anything should be able to move, and their every touch brought bloody blight to their victims. Wards and shields could stop them, but when they struck even something as doughty as a Prismatic Sphere, it was as though they hit with the force of a dragon. Draco had thrown up a ward to deflect one of the human-shaped monsters from entering through the window he was defending, and the blow it had dealt his spell had brought him to his knees. He hadn't fallen, but only just. He could feel the magic positively drain out of him.

Draco lifted his wand, held it in Ochs. There were some Muggles below, but they were thin on the ground. And in light of the other creatures, they seemed quaint with their cricket bats and knives. None of them had guns or explosives, and so they weren't worth his attention.

The sun was setting, and all the light was red. It would be night, soon.

A flash of motion leapt past the window, and Draco heard a scream from somewhere.

He leaned against the curved side of the window. He wanted to fall to the ground. He wanted to weep. He wanted to sleep.

But he would not. Some things were stronger than sleep or weakness or death. He would fight.

Then he heard a hooting sound, and this time he was too slow with his shield. Before he knew what exactly had happened, he was on the floor before the window, and something was on him. He'd lost his wand, it was gone, he couldn't do anything.

It was one of the flying ones, and it was on his shoulder and one side of his chest

and

he felt

pain ripping

and

he heard

a wet sound

of flesh tearing

and the crackle

of bone

splintering

and the pain

was killing him

he screamed

he screamed

he screamed

he screamed

he went away for a moment

and remembered

"Draco," Harry said. "Thank you for coming. I… well, thank you."

"What do you want, Potter?" Draco said, staring at the other boy. Potter had his face all screwed up, brows furrowed, as he always looked when he was about to be unbearably earnest. Looking at him made Draco feel sick - a deep and bitter disgust that tasted of acid.

Potter closed his eyes. "I want to make you a promise. A promise about your father. I want to -"

"Harry Potter," said Draco, his voice a dangerous hiss. "Be very careful what you say next." He could feel the acid on his tongue, but even more, it was burning in his veins. The rage and hatred. The things that made him weep at night, as he forced his face into his pillow and sobbed with great wracking cries. The things that made the presence of his mother a cruel thing, because they were very nearly strangers and his father was freshly buried. The things that made him so eager to hurt someone, these days. "Be very careful," he repeated.

Potter hesitated, opening his eyes to look back at Draco. Green eyes, filled with compassion. Draco wanted to spit in them.

"Listen," said Potter. "I've been thinking about what I owe… about the shape of things, and the degree to which my own arrogance and blindness have hurt others. And you'll understand more about that, soon, I think, but…" He paused, looking at the ground. "Draco, I want to make you a promise. A promise to try my hardest to do something. And I don't want anything from you in exchange, not even your friendship. I want nothing from you. This isn't about you. It's about… terminal values." The other boy stopped again, seeming to think about how what he was saying might sound. "About the things that are the most important in the world to me."

Draco could kill him. They were alone, and no one knew Draco was here. He had a knife, and Potter wouldn't expect that.

"Draco," said Potter, "I am sorry your father is dead. Truly and absolutely. With all my heart." A flash of something came across the boy's face - regret, somehow. "But I have seen impossible things. Magic is an impossible thing - or rather, it is all possible things, which is pretty much the same thing. It's brought… Hermione is back, and magic has made the space between death and life, which was already not very wide, into something that seems so small. Magic is…" Potter closed his mouth, shaking his head. "Sorry, I'm not saying what I mean. I'm not saying this very well."

Potter folded his arms, and hugged himself. Draco stared at him.

"I… Draco, I don't know how to say this. If it will seem insulting or crazy or what. So I'm just going to say it and hope you know that I mean it," the other boy began again. He raised his eyes, and met Draco's gaze.

"I intend," said Harry Potter, "to spend the rest of my life working to stop anyone from dying again - everyone's father and mother and son and daughter. And I intend to bring back those that have died, through whatever ritual or spell that needs to be invented to cross that last remaining gap of time."

"Draco," Harry said, "I promise to try my hardest for the rest of my life to try to bring back your father."

And there was an instant, right then, when the Lord Malfoy very nearly murdered the Lord Potter for toying with his heart. But Draco stopped himself, and stared into Harry's eyes which did not leave his own.

And he saw something there. He saw steel, and something harder than steel. He saw a will that would brook no obstacle and tolerate no barrier. He saw the diamond-hard will that had brought back Hermione Granger and Draco didn't know how but he knew that had been Potter and he saw an honour that bound this boy to a path. He saw a promise that was stronger than sleep or weakness or death.

"Will you help?"

Draco's wand was in his hand. It was still in his hand.

He was there and he was alive. Something was attacking him. One of those things was attacking him. It was killing him. He didn't want to die. He wouldn't die. He couldn't die. Because...

Because he wanted to see his father again someday.

And some things were stronger than sleep or weakness. Or death.

"Avada Kedavra!" he cast. The thing on his shoulder vanished, dissolving in a blaze of green light that burned away the inchoate blur of murderous sensations.

He slumped back to the stone, gasping.

The world was hazy and dark. Draco blinked, rapidly.

"Sir!" A voice. "Sir, hold on, I'm here!"

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Pip jumped as the Bloodfoot Curse rippled across the rough slates of the roof towards him. He lost his balance as he landed, one foot sliding on a tile, but caught himself with one hand. Bellatrix Black laughed at him.

This was bloody deja vu, really.

The fight had been going on for what seemed like hours. They had been moving to the roof, to try to use massed volleys of the Killing Curse against some of the more insane-seeming monsters that had come calling at Hogwarts tonight, but what had begun as three tight, tactical formations had dissolved into chaos as some of the enemy took the fight to them. A flaming chariot had burst from somewhere sideways of reality, drawn by a horse of fire, and it had left madness in its wake:

Ten witches and wizards with bloody sigils of hands and swords on their robes.

That skinny American witch from the Council of Westphalia, looking spidery and sour.

And that bleeding bitchy bint Bellatrix bloody Black.

Pip felt how a Gryffindor in the library must feel: lost and upset. Bellatrix was missing an arm and an eye, and she was still a better duelist than he was.

To his left, Madame Bones was fighting the American. That should have been a brief contest, but somehow the Westphalian was managing to hold off the Chief Mugwump, fighting with unimaginably queer new spells and with a sad grimness.

To his right, Mad-Eye Moody and three other aurors were fighting the Grindelwaldians. Wait, didn't they have a proper name? Something Hungarian and unpronounceable? No matter. Despite being outnumbered two-to-one, the good guys were winning. Pip couldn't even follow some of the things Moody was doing. At one point, Pip could have sworn he'd actually seen one of Moody's stunners turn in mid-air before hitting its target.

That had left Pip and Kwannon to fight Bellatrix Black, which seemed insane since didn't they already know how that would end after last time? But there was nothing for it, and so they fought, and Bellatrix was laughing again.

Maybe one of the defenders in the air would be able to help. Pip knew that Mr. Diggory was up there, and one of the American auror squads, and the Shichinin. They had their own enemies to face, but this was Bellatrix Black.

Kwannon raised a shield to buy them some time, but Pip remembered the last fight - he raised his own, too. When a Breaking Drill eradicated Kwannon's barrier, the curse - following the first one almost immediately, impossibly fast - burst against Pip's redundant shield. And both of them were quick enough on the dodge to avoid the Killing Curse that blazed at them within an instant.

"Better!" shrieked Bellatrix with a laugh. "Dancing dollies!"

"Lagann! Stupefy!" cast Pip, at almost the same time that Kwannon shouted, "Stupefy! Lagann!"

Bellatrix twirled in place, cackling, and let her shield dissolve as she dodged. She had another raised almost as quickly as Pip could have blinked, and then she flicked her wand in a way that Pip didn't recognize. A stream of yellow liquid burst out at the gesture, spraying from nowhere.

Caught without any idea of what the curse would do, or what shield would be appropriate, Pip did as he had been trained: he dodged again. Kwannon, trained by the same person (the curse-casting blur just behind them, in fact) did the same.

And Bellatrix anticipated it. When Kwannon threw herself to the side, a Slow Blade of Unusually Specific Destruction was waiting for her. It exploded violently.

Kwannon was thrown bodily away, and off the roof, and she was gone.

And it was at this moment that Pip wished he were a different sort of person. Someone important. A noble, or a brilliant researcher, or a seer. Or even just someone truly special. Because he knew that truly special people wouldn't die. Not this way, not after so much. Not at the moment when it mattered the most, when failure would mean the death of Alastor Moody and Amelia Bones and so many others.

He'd seen the plays. Bloody hell, working in the Tower had been like living in a play. Utterly impossible things happened all the time when necessary. When the really special people were in danger, even if it was from things like the Killing Curse… well, somehow, it worked out.

Philip Pirrip was just his mother's son. He was a decent auror, and a hard worker. He could say that about himself. But in that moment, as he leapt to his feet and tried to think of what to do next, knowing that he'd already fought this battle and had lost as though he were a Hufflepuff toddler… well, he just wished he were someone else. Someone special.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

In the fell clutch of circumstance

I have not winced nor cried aloud.

Under the bludgeonings of chance

My head is bloody, but unbowed.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hermione saw her again. The witch in green. The one who'd been with the monsters, walking with them, controlling them.

Hermione dragged her axe free of the basilisk's head. It smoked with venom. So too did the golden gauntlet on Hermione's right hand. There was a greenish tinge to both metals, now. Hermione shook the axe, and gore splattered to the ground. Where the ichor fell, the ground began to bubble and steam.

The witch was standing in front of one of the walls of the castle, and she'd sunk her hand into the stone. A terrasque stood motionless beside her, obedient as a great stone dog, as the witch in the green dress dragged her hand downward. Like a knife sliding through butter, she cut a long rent through the stone of Hogwarts, kneeling as she brought her hand all the way to the ground. Then she pulled her hand free and straightened.

This must be one of them. One of the Three. One of the leaders. The enemy.

Hermione pulled her bubbler from her robes. The back of it had been crushed in, and the decorative clamshell case was falling apart, but it still worked. "Boys?" she said.

"We're here," came the voice of one of the Weasley twins.

" 'Boys,' " scoffed the Russian witch with them.

"Be ready and watch for the high sign," Hermione said.

"You got it," replied another twin, cheerily.

Hermione put away her bubbler, and steadied herself. Then she attacked.

She shouted no challenge and no warning. She simply threw her axe at the witch, as hard as she could. It flashed through the air, whistling as it flew.

The terrasque intervened, lurching into motion, and the axe bounced off of its side, the handle hitting the creature's rough red shell.

The witch turned to face Hermione. Her face was serious, but her eyes were bright. The terrasque shifted out of the way, lumbering aside.

"Hello," the witch said. There was a husky accent in her voice. "You are Hermione Granger. You are quite magical, and quite powerful." She raised her hand. "And I think your time is done."

Hermione already had the Elder Wand in hand, and she charged.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

A figure in plain grey robes walked the halls of Hogwarts, unseen. It moved with some uncertainty - as though it knew its destination, but not the exact path. But it found its way to the library before too long.

Harry Potter didn't see. He had a bubbler in hand, and was giving urgent instructions.

"- no, it's not enough to say the word. You have to… you have to find something within yourself. You have to produce a deliberate will within yourself, like you were casting wandless magic."

Harry Potter was standing at one of the library windows. A strange sort of Muggle device was set up there - a tube mounted on a tripod, pointing up at the stars. Two aurors stood on either side of it, maintaining shields across the window against any intrusion. The floor was covered in chalk markings, repeatedly rubbed away and redrawn.

This was not the Archon Heraclius Hero, perfectly reshaped into a facsimile. That was obvious. How strange. Harry Potter had won, somehow. It was beyond belief, but it had happened.

The threat personified stood there, unaware and vulnerable, and the figure studied him. Just a boy, really. The crux was still just a boy. So dangerous to everything and everyone, the age-old threat to life resolved by time's lens into this single person, and it was just a boy.

The figure permitted himself a smile.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Beyond this place of wrath and tears

Looms but the Horror of the shade,

And yet the menace of the years

Finds and shall find me unafraid.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

The Unseelie had gathered in a tight knot outside the western walls. They were pulling someone apart, and that person was screaming. Impressions of black eyes and wide, wet mouths moved delicately and deliberately, causing pain as if it were an art.

It was horrible, but it was a respite for the defenders.

No, not a respite, Draco thought. An opportunity.

Where was Moody? We need to take advantage of this, right now.

He shoved himself away from the wall that been supporting him, and brandished his wand. "Expecto Patronum."

A silver krait undulated on the stone before him, moving gently.

"Go to every wizard and witch on this side of the castle and on the battlements," Draco commanded it, and he bent his will to making that a thought of peace and happiness. "Tell them to find me near the entrance to Gryffindor Tower. We are going to strike."

Before the snake was gone, Draco had fumbled his bubbler out of his robes, and was contacting everyone he'd seen who was still answering.

Outside, someone was screaming.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

When Gregor Nimue and Harry Madagascar both slumped to the floor, as suddenly unconscious as though they'd been bludgeoned, Harry knew that the moment had come.

He turned around, and saw a middle-aged man in plain grey robes. A little out of shape, with a small paunch. Taller than average, but somewhat stooped. A face heavily seamed with care, and green eyes. Ancient, ancient green eyes.

"Are you him?" Harry asked.

The man smiled, softly. He had a kind face.

"Yes, Harry Potter," he said, in a voice that was mellow, and deeper than Harry expected.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Pip had lasted only a few minutes more, and he suspected that was only by Bellatrix Black's cruelty.

"Silly billy boy," sang the insane witch, "and now such fun!"

She had captured him casually, whipping the Incarcerating Curse at him amid a torrent of attacks.

He lay there, helpless.

He had to watch as she turned on Moody, who was backpedaling away, trying to find a way to create some space. Only one auror still stood by his side against five of the Hungarians, and curses and shields were appearing and disappearing and flowing and sparking out with such rapidity that it looked more like a magical dance than intelligible combat. But there was nowhere to retreat to, and no way to create room or escape. Now he would have to have to watch. Again.

Bellatrix Black shrieked her mad laughter and struck away Moody's shield. Then again as he produced another one, but despite the desperation of his motions he still had to fight Grindelwald's soldiers. They redoubled their attacks, and Moody reached the edge of the roof, and had no more room to retreat.

Bellatrix paused, sighing a deep and happy sigh, and giggled once more. She raised her wand.

"Bellatrix!"

The cry came from above.

"Bellatrix Black!"

It was otherworldly.

"Bellatrix Black!"

It was enraged.

"Bellatrix Black!"

It was magnificent.

"BELLATRIX BLACK!"

It was Neville Longbottom.

He came from the sky. He didn't land, exactly - rather, he plummeted to the roof in a swooping dive, so steep that it seemed as though he would simply crash straight through the slates, but Longbottom pulled up at the last minute dead even with the slates, alighting and walking without even an instant of transition. He stepped forward and the broom clattered to the roof and Longbottom was already attacking, once twice thrice, as though gravity and timing and all the laws of possibility were mere formalities that he'd chosen to discard. Tall and terrible, the Lord Longbottom moved like the wind.

He attacked Bellatrix, and it was a thing of beauty and glory - choreographed, as if it had been practiced every day for years. High feint drawing a shield, which put him into position for obfuscation, and which in turn flowed seamlessly into three glowing offensive bolts. It was a series like any auror would learn... but rather than two or three spells in sequence, Longbottom attacked without ceasing, a rhythmic and timed flow of variety and passion. He switched from low attacks to broad ones, raised wards and then shattered them with surprising new offensives, and stripped away Bellatrix's defenses with a hurricane of attacks.

In an existence that threatened to become overcrowded with the unbelievable, Pip still found room for astonishment.

Bellatrix laughed; high-pitched, insane. "Silly little do-" she began, but a flurry of attacks cut her off, and she was forced to defend herself. "Silly bi-" she began again, only to again be forced to bark out a shield of crystal and dodge away from danger.

"You -"

"Silly bi-"

No one could be standing after attacking endlessly, relentlessly, unstoppably, but Neville Longbottom never broke his stride and never broke his sequence. One spell followed another, one attack followed another, one shield followed another. No openings, no weaknesses, no opportunities, no respite.

Bellatrix Black's laugh broke. She lashed away attacks and raised wards and cast curses, but she was not fighting a wizard. She was fighting an elemental force.

And every taunt and every joke and every insanity was cut off by some new attack. Every word broken by offense. Every moment under siege.

"That's -"

Longbottom advanced without pausing, never breaking stride. He was discarding his humanity, and doing it despite eyes streaming with tears.

"No -"

"You -"

And finally, Bellatrix's mad smile cracked as she desperately ducked the hundredth attack, and she shrieked with a voice full of fear, "Stop!"

And like a wrathful god, Neville Longbottom, a thousand feet tall and burning with brimstone, roared in return, "That's what they said to you! Avada Kedavra!"

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hermione's duel with the witch in the green dress was a strange thing.

The Goddess charged, wand raised, already casting. The enemy sneered, raising her own hands, and lightning surged between them.

The Elder Wand took it from the air.

Hermione's attacks fell uselessly against the witch's shields, which barely glowed a gentle silver as they absorbed one curse after another. The witch's attacks found no purchase, for the Elder Wand moved of its own accord, assisting its true owner, obliterating magics as though they were a child's whisper.

Hermione closed the distance, and they fought. Spells fell on shields. Spells fell on wand-wards. The duel was a storm without wind.

Almost as an afterthought, the Goddess crushed the head of a terrasque with her golden gauntlet, which carved through the creature with the burning fury of basilisk venom. But she could gain no traction against the witch in the green dress, who evinced neither strain nor dismay.

"Foolish monkey," said the witch, her voice punctuated by the wordless thrusts of her hand which sent green light and burning flame and sharp crystal cascading into Hermione's wand-borne defenses. "Didn't you know there was only ever one outcome, here?"

"I did," said Hermione, panting. "And so now would be good, gentlemen."

She lashed out at the witch with every ounce of belief and faith and grief, and the enemy's wards glowed bright under duress. Hermione's other hand landed like a titan's hammer immediately afterwards, a crushing blow dealt with a troll's strength.

At the same instant, there were two sharp cracks, almost simultaneous. Twin gunshots, fired from above.

The first rifle shot shattered the witch's shield. The second passed through her stomach.

Perenelle du Marais screamed, and it was loud, and it was long.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Draco looked over his troops. Perhaps a hundred wizards and witches. Weary, ragged, wounded, crammed into the small room where the Gryffindor stairs met the main hallway. Three watching at the windows, where the horror-things were pulling apart their victim. He clutched his ruined arm with the other to stop it from swaying - he was swaying, bloody hell. No, this would not do.

Unbreakable honour.

The Lord Malfoy forced himself to straighten up. Black shapes danced in front of his eyes, and for a moment everything went dull and far away, but he held himself upright. He held himself like a Malfoy.

His face was out of control. Draco mastered it, arranging it how he pleased: a cold look of confidence. His body was a tool, his to wield.

His voice. Before he spoke, he felt the blood in his mouth and throat. No. He swallowed it back, swallowed down the bile and blood. Cleared his instrument.

"We're attacking. A massed attack. The enemy is gathered together. They're not afraid. They should be."

"We'll die," offered Reg Hig. Not opposition, but resignation.

"We might. But we are already dead. This way, we'll have a chance.."

No, this is… no, it's weak. The stuff of desperation and stupidity… last resorts persuaded no one. Damn you, Draco, focus on their weakness, not ours, he thought to himself. Where are you? You are the knife. Cut.

"Listen to me, all of you," Draco said, and he put steel in his voice. "I won't pretend to believe in everything that the Tower believes. I won't tell you any pretty stories about the way the world might be. Listen to me when I tell you that we need to act now to protect the way the world is, and everything that's in it. Listen to me when I say that magic exists and it is precious, and we need to protect it.

"I am not the sort of person they call 'good,' " he said, and now the steel came of itself, and he stood even taller, and he heard his father's voice in his own. "I am the sort of person who gets results. Against all odds. Against a united country and a united world, I have gotten results. Because there are things that are more important than you or me or even this bloody school. There are things more important than our blood or our very age. There is magic in this world, in every wand here and every soul, and they will crush it if we let them."

He raised his wand into the air, and it glowed with a fire he felt mirrored in his soul.

"So when I say to you that now is the time and when I ask if you will follow me, know that it is true and we will win. For there is something greater than goodness and greater than even these odds, and that is us!"

What arrent nonsense, thought the Lord Malfoy, as he spoke honeyed lies.

A hundred wands rose in response.

And from high above, there was a new sound. Many voices, raised in a single call.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

"Who are you?" asked Harry, lowering the bubbler. He left it open, Luna listening on the other end.

"Merlin," answered the man, simply. He watched Harry, arms folded.

Despite everything, Harry felt himself shiver at the name. He knew that it might well be a lie - certainly it was the lie he'd have chosen, in this man's place - but it could also be true. It was more plausible than any of the other possibilities, if the law of parsimony was any guide: Merlin applying a secret, guiding hand, working to prevent the doom that he'd foreseen… well, it broke no rules of time travel and required no additional elements.

Harry had anticipated other possibilities, of course. Albus Dumbledore, trapped beyond time - that could well have put him in some ancient era before the Mirror was made. Or Garrick Ollivander, whose familial presence in Britain had been suspiciously unchanging for most of wizarding history. Or Harry himself, returning from a future where they'd mastered all knowledge, acting to ensure the realization of that future. Or some random, unnamed individual, hidden perfectly from sight throughout all time and legend.

But ultimately, what plausible candidate made sense, other than the one who had famously acted from the start to try to limit magic and preserve the world?

"You're here to destroy me and save the future of the world," Harry said. He kept his voice rigidly formal. "And for that, sir, I respect you. It is even possible that -" his voice faltered as he remembered J.C. Kraeme's bloodied body, the death of Hermione and Granville, and the hundreds of thousands who had already died today, but he pressed on. "It is even possible that you have done the right thing."

Merlin nodded solemnly, his smile fading from his face. "Then you understand."

"I do," said Harry. For a moment, he felt the absurdity of the moment. This was a moment that might spell the difference between a world of magic and advancement, a world where death could be defeated and Dumbledore could be retrieved, and… and a different world. A darker timeline. And all of that was riding on this simple, clumsy conversation.

"But," Harry went on, as Merlin raised his hand, "your map is wrong."

Merlin didn't lower his hand, but only tilted his head. Just slightly. An invitation.

"You must have known of Albus Dumbledore - perhaps you even knew him, somehow," said Harry. "I sometimes wonder if he was the wisest man I've ever known, or the merely the bravest. He ransacked the Hall of Prophecy and used his knowledge of the future to guide its shape. He didn't believe prophecies could be truly averted, I think, and he might have been right. In retrospect this seems obvious, but people like Tom Riddle spent years trying to avoid one prophecy or another, and they always failed." Harry shrugged. "I've never heard of a prophecy that was simply wrong. And if my readings are correct, you agree with him."

"So you know this, then: I, Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, will tear apart the stars."

Merlin nodded his head, slowly. His eyes were amused and curious, but they held a fundamental flatness. Harry couldn't imagine what that might be - some jadedness from such a long life, a precommitment to ignore all persuasion, or something beyond his ken - but he had no time to worry about it. He pushed forward, and felt his thoughts begin to catch fire.

Once upon a time, a lonely little boy had gone to a strange school. He was a prophet of new ideas, and saw things in a new way - he was the needle's point of a black slash that cut from one entire civilization into another, bringing the force of thousands of years of accumulated knowledge to bear on a point forged by trauma into diamond strength. And yet not a single jot or tittle of that had mattered, in the end. So little of the boy's cleverness had actually been brought to bear. His beliefs were the hard uphill way, and even a prophet was not immune to easy answers.

It was not until the end that the boy had grasped the real meaning of his own beliefs, and had ascended. Rationality was winning.

Harry's mind blazed like an inferno. He raised his hand.

"First." He held up a finger. "Only two people are known to have ever mastered all the wizards and witches of the world. Both, I think, did it for a good cause. But consider that for all your power and your age, I have done what you did… and I have done it without force, and by granting life and power, and I have done it in only seven years. I am your equal in this respect, and if you underestimate me now, then think about the fate of everyone else who has done so. Think of your ally, Heraclius Hero.

"Second." He held up another finger. "Events are already in motion to ensure that magic and humanity survive. The Tower is gone, and the Mirror which was the door. It has found a new place." High above us, Harry thought. Six hundred kilometers high, so that its light-cone encompasses the whole planet. "Some friends of mine wait there - waiting to find out whether I live or die. I will not tell you their instructions. But know that we all lie within the mirror now.

"Third." He held up a third finger. "You have several times attempted to disrupt my designs. You arranged for the destruction of my first facility, killing my friend in the process. And this very day your ally tried to enslave me. And yet I am here, and he is gone."

Harry's mouth grew firm. He met Merlin's eyes for a long moment, and then moved those three fingers: thumb poised against forefinger and middle finger. Ready to snap.

"So think. Stop and think. You have a map in your head - a mental map of reality. As you move through the world, you can trace your path on it. You can tick off events as you come to them; that's how you know your map matches reality. When you're surprised, it's not because reality is wrong... it's because your map is wrong. When you realize that, you have two choices: you change your map, or you get lost."

Merlin stared at him, and all vagueness and flatness was gone. In its place was the raptor gaze of someone who was beyond death and weakness, who had weighed human life and discarded it when it interfered with his will.

"Consider whether you have been surprised by events. Consider whether this is unfamiliar ground. Consider your fallen allies. Consider your derailed plans," Harry said, and his voice was soft. "Stop and think, and consider: do you want to keep moving in this direction? Or might there be other surprises waiting for you?"

"I will give you the same chance that Lord Voldemort - that Tom Riddle - was given, before I took his life. I will give you the same chance that Meldh had, before I took his life. Stop now, and go in peace.

"Or I will end you."

Harry didn't waver, and he was not afraid.

And it wasn't because he knew of some ultimate sanction or greater plan.

And it wasn't because he knew that Hermione would save the day with some impossible feat.

And it wasn't because he had faith in something greater than himself.

Harry did not waver because this moment laid bare his heart, the white-hot line of humanity at his center, slashing through the black arc of Tom Riddle and cutting through every obstacle in his way. Harry did not waver because he had tested all things and held fast to that which was true, and he had set that truth in service of the good with every last ounce of strength and will and might.

And for Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres, that was the purpose of life.

"So?" said Harry.

From outside, a woman screamed, long and loud. The scream of a dying woman.

Within a moment, another cry joined with the first: the sound of a hundred phoenixes, their call like the birth of a new world.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

It matters not how strait the gate,

How charged with punishments the scroll,

I am the master of my fate,

I am the captain of my soul.

"Invictus," by W. E. Henley

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Merlin studied Harry closely.

And turned.

And left.

Chapter 58: Epilogue

ἔσχατος ἐχθρὸς καταργεῖται ὁ θάνατος·

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

The Tower

June 1st, 1999

Three weeks later

Hermione gave herself a moment to look around the room, moving from face to face. So few familiar faces: Percy Weasley, Amelia Bones, and Dolores Umbridge. Percy was smiling confidently on her left, while Amelia and Dolores were engaged in whispered conversations with their neighbors.

Many more of those present were relatively new, either to her or to the Tower. He Jin of the Court of Rubies. Per Aavik-Söderlundh-Ellingsen, on mission for the nobility of Europe. And others: a Westphalian appointed by Hig, who was now unchallenged in his dominance over the surviving rump of the Council; several wizards and witches from various strata of the Confederation, chosen as representatives-at-large; a goblin who was present in the same capacity, nominally representing Beings; a domovoi of Russia sent by the Thunderer on behalf of the Slavic tradition; and wizards from Nigeria, Dunedin, and Chile.

It was almost a parody of oligarchy, with stronger states and Things trying to cement their local power. The small nods towards democracy would have been pathetic if they hadn't actually represented progress.

Every little step is important, but there's still so much work to do, thought Hermione. Proportional regional representation for wizard; similar representation for Beings and some sort of system for Muggles; a federal system to incorporate adversarial interests; strong backing for select NGOs for science and healing... and so much more. She could almost see the future stretching out ahead of her, in all of its strangeness and complexity.

It might have been disheartening if Hermione hadn't been so eager to get started. There were so many lives to save, and she was in a position to help without a minute of delay. She smiled. Not one more minute.

All right, then. Time to do a little dance.

"Thank you, everyone, for coming," said Percy. "You should all have an itinerary, but I have extras if you need them. If you don't mind, we'll begin with introductions, and then we'll lay out our current status and our future plans."

"There is much we need to do," broke in Per, ignoring the orderly start of the meeting and the offered itinerary, his face haggard and serious with urgency. Percy looked mildly annoyed. "We must begin immediately to work on our defenses. The Muggles and the monsters and the other things… we must plan for their control."

He Jin cut in after the Norden diplomat, leaning forward and pointing out in calm and clipped words that the strange blurry monsters with fishlike eyes had been spotted in Ulan Bator a day ago, and there was no telling where they might go next.

The Westphalian agreed, nodding along with the mandarin and adding, "Our resources are a fraction of what they were, and it's taking everything we have simply to maintain the Statute of Secrecy. And that's not even mentioning the villains behind it all - the ones Reg called the 'Three.' "

"Yes," said Hermione, rising up from her seat slightly. The others quieted, and attention focused on her. "You are all absolutely right," she said, and she put force behind her words: cold steel. She pressed her lips tightly together, then gave a small nod, as though in confirmation of some inner resolution.

"Our current situation has become untenable," she continued. "If another attack arrived, we'd be wiped out. There is one member of the Three at large, assuming we have not fallen prey to misinformation in that regard - I can imagine a clever group adopting a misleading name - as well as a small army of Unseelie and many other threats. Even with the help of new allies," and she nodded to the Curdite who was there on behalf of the goblins and other Beings, "we have barely been able to hold things together. Thousands and thousands of people and goblins lost their lives on Götterdämmerung, and we are vulnerable as never before."

"Then now is the time to take hold of the Muggles, as our enemy did, and as we once did in old times," said the Russian domovoi. "We must command their numbers for our own." The New Zealand representative nodded her head, vigorously.

"Yes," agreed Hermione once more. Amelia and Dolores ended their hushed conversation, turning to look at her with shock and disbelief, and even Percy turned to stare at her. "I know that for many of you, this will be unimaginable, but I agree: it's the only way. The world has changed, and all of us have seen things happen that we never could have believed."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Elsewhere.

At the same time.

Limpel Tineagar's face had been frozen into an unpleasant expression of dismay and pain. Reg Hig was reminded of the stories of how the Eleusinian Mysteries had punished its enemies, petrifying them into living statues and then enchanting their limbs so that they could be adjusted into humiliating positions. It seemed petty to today's scholars of history, but its effectiveness couldn't be discounted - the Mysteries had maintained their hegemony over all of the Mediterranean for generations.

Not that they could do much, here, he thought, looking at Tineagar's maimed body, floating in the air in front of him, stunned stiff. One arm cut away at the shoulder, the other at the elbow. He'd heard that Amelia Bones had done this, in the last moments of a fight on Hogwarts' roof. He wondered if it had been punitive, necessary, or simply an accident of victory. Bones is not a cruel witch, but a new Eleusinian Mysteries has arisen. I can't ignore the implications of that, even if I am a part of it.

That last thought was some comfort, at least, he thought as he looked at the broken body of the betrayer, floating along at his wand's command. The great merchants and old families of Tidewater had been murdered, wiped out of life as thoroughly as if they'd never existed, but those Americans that were left would be an equal part of the new world. When the Council of Westphalia rose again - and that Thing would rise again, even if Hig had to spend the rest of his life rebuilding its ranks and its strength - the Americas would no longer be in the shadows, jockeying for leverage within the Confederation.

"Councilor Hig, sir," called a voice, and Hig looked up, returning from his reverie. It was the head of the DMLE, young Diggory, and four others. One was an auror that Hig recognized, but not the rest… they looked nervous and unsettled. Ranks were thin all over, and Hig supposed these must be new recruits or patrol-wizards pressed into more heady service than that to which they were used.

"Director Diggory, hello," said Hig.

"Hullo," said Diggory. The young man looked haggard, but somehow that made him look even taller and more handsome. His expression was solemn, perhaps due to their surroundings. The atrium of the British Ministry of Magic still bore scars and ragged wounds on every wall and surface. The basics had been put back in order, but it would be a long time before the cosmetic damage could be repaired - and even longer before the memories would fade. Hig thought of Tidewater again, and shuddered.

"Here is my delivery," said Hig, gesturing with his wand. Tineagar's body floated between them gently, as though wafted by the wind. "Good riddance. Have your people strip her mind, and if there's anything left when you're done, tell her that her home is gone."

Diggory didn't reply, watching Hig with a sad expression. He gestured to one of the witches with him, and she cast her own levitation spell on Tineagar, taking over from Hig.

"I'll be headed back later tonight," Hig said, "after taking some time to try to get together some people."

"Checking up on friends?" Diggory asked, as he stared down at the frozen face of Tineagar.

"No," Hig said, shaking his head. "There are some ex-pats of the Americas here in Britain. From all over… Chile, Brazil, the States, Canada, et cetera. I'm going to touch base with a few of them and see if they'd be amenable to coming home."

"Make sense. I'm sorry about what happened."

"It could have been worse," Hig said. "Salem escaped without a scratch on a single student, thanks to the goblins and centaurs, and Houston and Buenos Aires only lost a handful. And we'll rebuild. Everyone, everywhere, needs to rebuild." He gestured broadly around the atrium, as though to illustrate his point.

"We'll be here to help."

"Thank you," Hig said, and sighed. He shook his head. "Sorry, it's too easy to be gloomy, these days. All is well with you?"

"As well as can be expected," Diggory said, nodding. "I lost some friends and a cousin, but everyone lost someone. It's been too busy to really think about it."

"Make sure you make time for yourself - to keep a clear head," Hig offered. "In fact, maybe you want to have dinner tonight? Take your mind off things?"

"Actually," said Diggory, a bit sheepishly. "I have an engagement tonight."

"I heard rumors about a long-sought romance. I suppose sometimes persistence pays off, eh?" said Hig, smiling gently. A signal to the young man - levity is okay, even now with what happened in Tidewater, I won't be offended.

Diggory shrugged. "What can I say?" he asked. "We've all been through so much, and sometimes a person comes out the other side a bit… well, bolder, I guess. It'll be new and probably fun, and worth giving it a chance, and anyway..."

And Diggory glanced with a smile over at the group that had accompanied him, where Pip was standing guard. "...he did save my life."

Pip noticed their attention. He smiled hugely and gave them a little wave. Then he returned his attention to his work, straightening himself up and returning his attention to Tineagar…. though she was hardly in a position to escape, even if she were somehow to wake, and though it didn't seem as though any amount of dutifulness could erase the smile that was plastered on his face.

"Well then," said Hig, and now his smile was rather more genuine. "I hope you have a good evening. I'm sure I'll see you soon, Master Diggory. Let's hope for the best of luck - in all our new beginnings."

When Reg Hig left the Ministry of Magic, he found himself oddly optimistic. Despite all of his common sense and despite everything he knew of history… he let himself believe that things might get brighter. Things might get better.

Isn't it pretty to think so.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

"Muggles are an existential threat," Hermione said, firmly, looking around at everyone at the meeting table. It was a new piece of furniture, without the scuffs and broken edge from Hermione's demonstrations of anger three months ago. New like everything else in this new Tower. "Götterdämmerung showed that to everyone, even skeptics. Harry had some strong beliefs on this, as you know, but I think we need a new plan. The Statute of Secrecy made us vulnerable, since it encouraged us to separate ourselves and gather together into little enclaves. There was a time when wizard and witch lived among Muggles, usually ruling them, and it would have been impossible to try any sort of magical genocide. We need that protection again - the protection of Muggles."

"Madame Granger," said Amelia, and her voice was harsh. "I am surprised to hear this from you. You used to moderate Mr. Potter's approach, but now you sound more extreme than he ever did. What is your idea - that we attempt to seize control? It's not even practical, even if it wasn't a gross departure from our ideals. We are so few… do you imagine we could dominate the Muggles when they have as many cities as we have people?"

"We have been intervening strategically for years," said Hermione, coolly, standing up. "On a small scale, even a handful of wizards can effect incredibly quick change at a minimum of risk."

"I hardly think a few Hit Wizard squads are good evidence," objected Dolores. "And you know what they're like."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Elsewhere.

At the same time.

"This seems like the perfect moment for sniping," said Neville, in a hopeful whisper. He scrunched himself forward enough to see over the rim of a huge spool of copper wire that was currently hiding him from sight, then ducked back down. "Yes, sniping it is. For sure."

"If we did that, then -" said Fred, cocking his head to the side.

"- wouldn't he be dead?" said George, cocking his head to the other side.

"No, I just need to snipe the gun out of his hand," said Neville. "That can be healed."

"Then there would be the blastbomb only to explode, I think," said Bogdanova, peering around the corner for a moment. She pulled her head back and turned to Neville with a mocking smile. "Which means all of our problems here would be gone very shortly... yes, you have convinced me."

"I can snipe his other hand, too," offered Neville. "Then he can't blow up the bomb."

"This might be one of those situations that can't be solved with sniper rifles," mused George, contemplatively.

"Although now that we say that out loud, it just sounds silly," contemplated Fred, musingly.

"We can use the Extinguishing Charm on the bomb. That will stop any detonation," said Neville. "Then the sniping."

"Snipe the hostages, as a distraction?" suggested Bogdanova. Her appearance may have changed with rejuvenation, but her attitude certainly hadn't been affected.

"Enchanted bullets, that's the ticket," said Fred.

"Zip around to both hands, whammo, knock him back and to the left," agreed George.

Neville turned to squint at George suspiciously, but the Weasley twin only smiled serenely. Neville sighed, and crossed his arms with a scowl. "Fine, fine… the same as always, then."

"Don't worry, Nev," said George, consolingly. "You'll get your chance, someday."

"There will be another time the world is about to end, and then you'll just nip in and snipe the arch-villain just in time to save everyone," said Fred, nodding.

"Happens all the time," said George.

"Definitely not a unique opportunity for awesomeness," said Fred.

The twins were grinning, now. They reached across to each other, and each tapped the other on the head. With the sound of a cracking egg, they vanished into Disillusionment.

Bogdanova waited a second, then leaned around and tugged on Neville's earlobe, affectionately. "They're not wrong, you know," she said, her tone softening. "Who knows what may happen? Think about other things of that day."

"I know," Neville said, sighing again as Bogdanova lifted her wand and tapped herself on the head, vanishing from sight with a wet crackling noise. "And I'm grateful, of course. But still… the sniping…" he said plaintively.

"Oh, come on," the invisible Russian witch said, and her voice was fond. "Let us go. There's a girl in the pond that needs rescuing."

Neville grinned, and Disillusioned himself.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

"This is good," said the domovoi, who obviously approved of the plan. Several others joined him in that attitude. Per, Percy, and Dolores looked doubtful. Amelia looked hostile. The others seemed to have reserved judgment.

He Jin cleared his throat, delicately, and asked Hermione what she was proposing.

The fast reverse.

"We have already seen the success of making our rivals into our allies," said Hermione, gesturing at the Curdish envoy. "So we need to do the same with the Muggles. We need to turn a threat into an asset… potentially the biggest asset we could ever have. We need to eliminate the Statute of Secrecy and present ourselves to the world as a magical people. It's a risk, and we'll need to be careful, but remaining isolated has proven even riskier."

Nearly everyone seemed confused by what she was proposing, except for Amelia. Her expression softened, and displeasure was supplanted by surprise. "You're not proposing mastery at all. You're proposing the modus meli."

"Open and free, and as equal as we can manage," confirmed Hermione. "Not hiding from them, not ruling them, but living with them."

Per spoke up, cautiously. "If you will excuse me, that seems to be an idea with a very interesting goal, but one with too many problems. It is impossible."

"There are so many problems that it's staggering," Hermione allowed. "Every Muggle government will see magic as a weapon, so there will be a risk of global warfare - in addition to the constant threat of kidnapping or blackmail. There are also different aspects of magic that are incredibly dangerous to the untrained, but any Obliviator can tell you how hard it is to completely eliminate information from a Muggle population… which is why nearly every aspect of our magical world can be found approximated in folklore and legends, even today. And of course, there's every possibility we'd face a return to the days of witch-hunts and inquisitions… especially after recent events."

"But you believe you have a solution," Amelia said, quietly, speaking over the murmurs of the others.

"It is possible that the Mirror of Noilitov can be used to alter the terms under which our world operates," said Hermione. "It is also possible that the Goblet of Fire can be used to bind people without their conscious knowledge, if it will recognize a proxy in terms of political representatives. It is also possible that some of the new spells we will acquire from our two captive members of the Three - or even one of the ones we already possess - could be used once we have mastered them to manipulate even a global population. But we may not even need to resort to any of these, if we devote ourselves as one to this goal and find different solutions. There are many others, including mundane ones like wand control. There were only one hundred and twelve wandmakers worldwide a month ago, and there must be many fewer, now. We kept the entire world in an imperfect ignorance for centuries - surely if we really try, we can manage a transition without too much damage."

Percy was staring at her, eyes wide. He'd realized what she was saying - her true message - before anyone else. But he didn't seem angry. He seemed awed.

"It might be hard," Hermione added. "But sometimes the hardest things - the things that seem the most impossible - are the things that most need to be done. The first step to finding a solution is rejecting the idea of impossibility. Then you just take the first, hard, scary step."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Elsewhere.

At the same time.

Nikitas Seyhan knocked gingerly on the door to the cottage at Külek Boğazı. There was no answer. Nikitas frowned and turned around, glancing behind himself to where Tonks, Jessie, and Urg were watching. Tonks smiled and nodded, miming a knock. Nikitas turned back around and knocked a second time, more loudly. He knew he should be nervous, but really only felt a distant discomfort.

"Hello?" said a voice in the local Greek. The door cracked open, slowly.

"Is this the Seyhan house?" said Nikitas, in the same tongue. He felt like he was in a dream.

The door swung open, and a big bluff man stood there. He was bearded and florid, and his eyes were wide.

"Nikitas? You've come back to us?"

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Dolores said something first, in a syrupy voice that was unusually quiet. "Ms. Granger… the Mirror, and the Goblet, and the new spell… aren't these all things you could have already done? Couldn't you have… Did you?"

He Jin was out of his seat, glaring at Hermione as though his eyes were capable of murder under their own power. The Westphalian had gone pale. Per was looking rapidly around him, not having yet understood but too afraid to ask.

Hermione stood and stepped away from the table, and walked to the room's window. Dramatic pose at the window, put my silhouette against the sky. Like so. She looked out and down, at the clouds rolling beneath the Tower as the building lightly floated along, borne up by the salvaged Aa-Khem of the Shafiq. The scarab statues had been recovered from the wreckage of The Declaration of Intent. The new Tower, still only a fragment of its future self, was buoyed up in the sky: unassailable, invisible, and puissant.

The people in this room represented enough power and influence to sway the Confederation. They'd fought a global war together, and now faced new challenges and a new world. They'd been forged out of a disparate and violent assemblage of fractious Things, and could now be united.

Fear could do it. She could threaten most of them. They might seek her death and plot against her, but they'd obey. She knew that Draco would do it that way, if he were in her position. A cold and intimidating speech, leveraging all his power and influence, and enlisting the weak as his enforcers.

Persuasion could do it. She could convince most of them. They wouldn't be wholly won over, and may later change their minds, but they'd agree. She knew that Harry would do it that way, if he were in her position. A bold and inspirational speech, changing as many minds as possible, and backed up with a redundant plans to handle anyone who was recalcitrant.

But she wasn't Draco and she wasn't Harry. They'd each stepped away from these things, perhaps permanently. She was Hermione Granger, daughter of dentists, goddess. She was standing at the crux of things, and she knew the right thing to do.

Fear was limited. Draco had been afraid all of his life, in one sense, but he'd still found the courage to face the worst and overcome it. A single lever was all it took to overturn fear.

Persuasion was limited. Harry had spent years railing against insanity and irrationality, hurling evidence and reason against dull walls and burning with frustrating when they failed. He sometimes couldn't see the way the world was, out of eagerness to see it the way it should be.

Hermione knew that wasn't how you led people. It wasn't how you changed minds. She had led the Returned, and she knew why. She had led soldiers, and she knew why they'd followed her on the battlefield. She had led the people, and she knew why they wanted to touch her hand and worshipped her.

Hermione had died twice, and she knew what she'd followed back to this world. She knew what people would follow.

They followed the light.

Far below, all around the Tower, she could see bright spots of crimson glory. She heard a phoenix call, as though it saw her, and heard another answer.

Hermione turned around, and smiled, and began to speak.

She brought her own special gift. She brought hope.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.

Yesterday.

"It just seems unlike you, is all," Hermione said to Harry, watching him curiously. She opened a satchel and looked inside, but the extended space within was still empty.

"I think my part in this is over," Harry said, shrugging. He was silent for a moment as he finishing bolting down the Vanishing Cabinet inside of the spherical silver ship, then he stood back and surveyed his work. He nodded approvingly, and turned back to Hermione. "And I'll be within reach, from time to time. I might need help."

Hermione frowned. "You'll need a lot of books, and you might get lonely, but as far as we can tell, there's no limit to that Cabinet. You don't even really need to 'go' at all, since you could just as easily live here and check in on your ship once a month. So this is really you taking a sabbatical from everything. And that's fine, but I think I'm the one who's going to be asking you for help. Be ready to pop on through, the first time I encounter an insuperable problem."

"Well, see, here's the thing," Harry said, leaning down with a silver wire rack so that he could affix it to the interior of the ship. "You remember all of my work with Luna, looking into the nature of magic? Magical theory has come quite a ways since we started to systematically eliminate possibilities. And we found some pretty amazing things when we looked at the brains of people casting spells. We never did have enough of a chance to discuss it, I think," he mused. "Anyway, I pretty much have just one strong hypothesis now. And it fits with what we know about Merlin, and explains a lot.

"Spoken magic and wandless magic look almost the same when you see how they're expressed. BETs and POSTs and all the rest in specific patterns, even though the interference each spell generates might be completely different. The same effect, the same patterns. It's not a far inferential leap to conclude that the pattern is a command, like you might give to a computer. If you're magical in nature, then something in the universe knows to pay attention to that command.

"Now, it's possible that it's just the nature of the universe that specific electrochemical patterns in our neurology trigger complicated phenomena. I've read weirder theories. But that opens up a big question: why are we the only ones?

"It's the Fermi Paradox on an even bigger scale. There are so many planets where life could evolve, out there in the universe. And the existence of magic means that a lot of the normal answers probably don't work. Distance and difficulty don't seem like they could possibly matter once any magical civilization is advanced enough, and some of those lifeforms that probability suggests must exist would end up being magical, just like humans.

"Now, there's a lot of possible explanations. Maybe magic makes it even more difficult for life to evolve than we thought, somehow. Or maybe there are magical barriers we don't know about, blocking us off.

"But then I think about Merlin, and what he was afraid of, and how he… well, he backed down, when it came down to it."

Hermione's jaw had dropped open and she'd forgotten to breathe since Harry had said the words "Fermi Paradox." He continued on.

"I didn't present him with very much new information, when it came right down to it. He must have already known Meldh had been defeated, and they'd been watching me so they already knew the other things I said. And I told him that prophecies always come true, but I learned that from a book that quoted Merlin. So why did he go?

"Maybe he's just biding his time. Maybe he's seeking a way to neutralize our advantages. Maybe he was just suddenly persuaded.

"But someone that powerful with that much lore and prophecy…" Harry shook his head. "I'm not sure about that. Because I'm thinking of what Merlin's goal might really have been, and about a thing called the Great Filter, and…" He paused, then continued. "No, I think that -"

"Wait," interrupted Hermione. "Just wait. Because I think you're about to tell me that you think the British wizard Merlin is an alien from another planet, sent here to watch us or guard us or something. And that maybe aliens invented magic? And that is…" She frowned. "Just… no. Put a pin in that. I can't handle that right now."

Harry grinned. "I imagine a computer somewhere, advanced beyond our furthest dreams, that fulfills commands to users it recognizes. And we just happen to have matched that pattern in the wierdest way. But all right. Another time, then. Or until it becomes more urgent."

Hermione was silent for a long period, while Harry continued packing away supplies. Lots of redundancies and failsafes, since this was a journey into the unknown. He'd be pushing against new limits and uncertainties about all sorts of materials and spells.

After a while, the witch spoke again. "How do you know that this will work? And where to go?"

"Prophecy," Harry said, shrugging. "Which is the only way I can even do this, since I know I will succeed someday. Eventually. I just need to head to the Scorpion and the Archer… Scorpius and Sagittarius. Something is locked beyond return along that path. Just by coincidence, that's also where astronomers think a black hole is situated, at the center of our galaxy. So that's where I'll go, and we'll see if that's where Dumbledore is now. If it's where Atlantis is now. If it's where all the things locked beyond return are trapped outside of time. It's inconvenient and crazy, but sometimes so is the world."

"How far is it?" asked Hermione.

"26,000 light years or so," answered Harry, grinning. "Although I expect to find faster ways to travel than the speed of light."

"I feel as though we're saying goodbye," Hermione said, and her voice trembled a little. "Which is stupid, because you'll probably be back for lunch next week, once you start to need someone to talk to. But you really are leaving."

"I'm leaving," Harry said.

"And you're leaving me in charge."

"You're in charge," Harry agreed. "Oh, I have three things to give you! Might as well give them over now."

He reached into his pocket and pulled out a milky-white stone. "The Spirit Stone. The last of the Deathly Hallows. Yours now in truth, along with the others." She accepted it, wordlessly. It was also reportedly a Horcrux of Voldemort. A research project: how to break those ties.

He tugged on the fingerless glove on his right hand, pulling it free. A pained expression passed over his face, but he didn't hesitate. He offered it to her, and again Hermione took it.

She glanced at his other hand, at the decoy glove he always wore, but he smiled a wry smile. "No, I'm going to hang on to this one. I discovered something useful about it, recently. No, the third thing is a ritual. It's a sacrificial ritual… a dangerous one, but an important one. The most important one, really."

"You… wait, what?"

"It was one of the only things I could think to do, at the end. I couldn't fight, not really. And I only knew one thing that had impressed anyone in the Three. A ritual that he saw in my mind, one I'd never actually done. I had it in my mind, all the principles - I'm really not sure how to explain it, it just works out somehow, when you're inventing a spell - and Meldh had told me I was being stupid not to use it." Harry pulled a folded parchment from his pocket, carefully, and handed it over to her. "I still think he's wrong, and I'm still not sure if it's the right thing. But I did use it once. To fulfill a promise. I picked a star that seemed least likely to have any negative consequences… a Bok globule that would only have existed as a star for a few thousand years, as best I could figure."

Hermione took the parchment. She didn't know what to say… didn't know how to react to a succession of surprises that seemed too great to be borne. All she could think was a single sentence, a miraculous sentence that embraced the multitude of stars scattered throughout her mind's eye, each one now with a name: We can save everyone.

She smiled gently. Her eyes were wet.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Malfoy Manor

The small family accepted no visitors, and seldom left the house.

It was a strange, new way to live: as though ambition were sated, as though ambition had reached its natural end. Surely, it was temporary - for the gnawing of desire never rests for long - but for a time, the family wanted for nothing. They were together, and they were content.

Sometimes they played music, or had long conversations, or spent entire afternoons in cooking elaborate meals. But often, they simply sat with each other in silence. It was a happy and full silence where nothing needed to be said, because everything important was known.

From time to time, Draco would close his eyes and hold them that way for a long time, before opening them again. As though testing what he was seeing.

But nothing changed, and every time he would open them again, Draco would see his father anew, holding his mother's hand.

He smiled gently. His eyes were wet.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Somewhere beyond Earth and everything else we know. Somewhere in the darkness of space.

Soon.

Harry took a deep breath, and then let it out, slowly. It sounded very loud inside of his ship.

He held the glove from his left hand, and examined it with a smile. He touched the curved fragment of the Cup of Midnight that was bound there. A decoy he'd worn for years, to balance the Stone of Permanence. Impervious to harm and enchantment and damage, and always close to him.

He pushed hard on the underside of the smooth piece of pottery, twisted it to the side, and then pushed down on it. There was a small click, and the piece of broken earthenware slid upwards, revealing the round aperture to an extended space sheltered beneath.

Harry set the glove on the floor of the ship. He reached over to pick up a book from a small shelf where he'd placed it earlier, and then stepped into the glove. It drew him in, delicately.

Finding his way past all of the traps and security precautions had taken him weeks. Removing a substantial part of a mass of tungsten had taken almost as long, since he'd needed to be extremely careful. In this, after all, he was entirely alone.

But he'd done it.

He sat on a small stool, and smiled. "Hello, Professor. I brought a book, and I thought I'd read to you today."

"That would be acceptable, Mr. Potter," said Voldemort.

"It's called The Feynman Lectures on Physics, and it's one of my favorites."

"Is it long?"

"Yes."

"Then begin at your leisure, Mr. Potter."

Harry didn't begin right away. He just looked at the box for a moment.

He smiled gently. His eyes were wet.